{
  "sections": [
    {
      "wordsets": [
        {
          "title": "6.1",
          "definitions": {
            "LEVY": {
              "word": "LEVY",
              "phonetic": "(lev'-E)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to impose, collect; to carry on (war) \nTo LEVY is to impose something like a tax or a fine, and to collect it by authority or force. \n\"The king LEVIED a new tax on the citizens.\" \n\"The judge LEVIED a huge fine on the company.\" \nLEVY is also used in a different sense, to mean \"to start or make war.\" \n\"The king decided to LEVY war against his enemies.\" \nAs a noun, a LEVY is the act of imposing or the thing imposed, a _tax_. \n\"The governor announced a new LEVY on cigarettes.\""
            },
            "ONSLAUGHT": {
              "word": "ONSLAUGHT",
              "phonetic": "(on'-slot)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "an attack, assault \nONSLAUGHT is related to the word _slaughter_. An ONSLAUGHT is a furious attack, of an enemy or of something like an enemy. \n\"The enemy launched a fierce ONSLAUGHT against our army.\" \n\"The ONSLAUGHT of the illness put him in the hospital for a week.\" \n\"They built a wall to protect themselves from the ONSLAUGHT of the cold wind.\""
            },
            "THWART": {
              "word": "THWART",
              "phonetic": "(thwart)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to block, prevent, foil, frustrate \nTo THWART someone is to block or prevent him from doing something. THWART suggests making things difficult for a person by running counter to what he wants or plans. \n\"The governor successfully THWARTED his opponent's attempt to win the election.\" \n\"Her plans to attend the party were THWARTED by a sudden illness.\" \n\"The baby screams whenever he is THWARTED\"--that is, whenever he is not allowed to do something he wants to do. \nIn the Pretest, many people select _delay_ as the meaning of THWART, but THWART suggests more complete and successful interference. \n\"Lack of funds _delayed_ the project, but the principal's opposition finally THWARTED it.\""
            },
            "DEGENERATE": {
              "word": "DEGENERATE",
              "phonetic": "(di-jen'-:}-rAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to worsen, decline, deteriorate \nTo DEGENERATE is to become worse, to pass from a higher state to a lower or worse one. See _de-_ under Prefixes. The word can be used about physical, mental, or moral qualities. \n\"The disease caused his health to DEGENERATE and now he's confined to bed.\" \n\"The play started brilliantly, but then DEGENERATED into a typical silly comedy.\" \n\"The once great lawyer has DEGENERATED into a drunken bum.\" \nDEGENERATE is also an adjective and a noun, pronounced (di-jen'-:i—rit). These words are most often used about lowered moral qualities. \n\"He may once have been a good man, but now he is just a DEGENERATE.\" \n\"The DEGENERATE emperor practiced every sort of vice.\""
            },
            "ELITE": {
              "word": "ELITE",
              "phonetic": "(i-lEt')",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "the chosen ones, a superior or highly special group \nNote the pronunciation. ELITE originally came from a Latin word meaning to _choose_. The ELITE are the chosen ones, a group of people who are considered superior because of their achievements, wealth, power, or other quality. \n\"This store would only do business with the social ELITE.\" \n\"His tremendous feats as a hitter put him among baseball's ELITE.\" \n\"He was part of the political ELITE who ran the country year after year.\" \nELITE is also used as an adjective, meaning _choice_ or _best_. \n\"An ELITE group of soldiers was selected to lead the attack.\" \nOther forms of the word: ELITISM, n. ELITIST, adj., n."
            },
            "INDIFFERENT": {
              "word": "INDIFFERENT",
              "phonetic": "(in-dif'-ÔøΩrQnt",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "uninterested, unconcerned, unimpressive, commonplace \nThe most common meaning of INDIFFERENT is \"not caring one way or the other\"; in this sense the word is usually followed by _to_. \n\"I love swimming, but I am INDIFFERENT to winter sports.\" \n\"How can you be so INDIFFERENT to the suffering of these people?\" \nAnother meaning of INDIFFERENT is \"neither good nor bad,\" _commonplace_, _mediocre_. \n\"It was an INDIFFERENT novel; I've read much better.\" \n\"He played the piano very well, but he sang INDIFFERENTLY.\" \nOther forms of the word: INDIFFERENCE, n."
            },
            "KALEIDOSCOPIC": {
              "word": "KALEIDOSCOPIC",
              "phonetic": "(kQ-lld-Q-skop'-ik)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "continually changing, extremely varied \nA KALEIDOSCOPE is a tube that contains mirrors and pieces of colored glass. When the tube is turned, the glass appears in an endless variety of multicolored patterns. The adjective KALEIDOSCOPIC means \"formed by or relating to a KALEIDOSCOPE.\" See _-ic_ under Suffixes. The word is usually used in a general sense, about shapes or events that are constantly shifting into new patterns, as if seen through a KALEIDOSCOPE. \n\"The reporters could barely keep up with the KALEIDOSCOPIC events of the day.\" \n\"It was a time of KALEIDOSCOPIC change, when no one knew what to expect next.\" \nOther forms of the word: KALEIDOSCOPE, n."
            },
            "PATERNAL": {
              "word": "PATERNAL",
              "phonetic": "(pÔøΩter'-nÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "having to do with a father, fatherly \nPATERNAL comes from _pater_, the Latin word for _father_, and means \"like or of a father.\" See _-al_ under Suffixes. \n\"He took a PATERNAL interest in the boy. He treated him as if he were his own son.\" \n\"I didn't like his PATERNAL attitude. He talked to me like a father talking to his little girl.\" \nSimilar words are _maternal_, meaning _motherly_, and _fraternal_, meaning _brotherly_."
            },
            "RETROSPECT": {
              "word": "RETROSPECT",
              "phonetic": "(re'-trÔøΩspekt)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a review \nRETROSPECT comes from a Latin word meaning to _look back at_. The _spect_ part is also found in other words having to do with seeing, like _inspect_ and _spectacles_. A RETROSPECT is a view of past events. The word is usually used in the phrase \"in RETROSPECT,\" which means _in review_, _in looking back_. \n\"In RETROSPECT, I guess I made a mistake in doing what I did.\" \n\"At the time we thought we had failed, but in RETROSPECT it seems that we did pretty well.\" \nOther forms of the word: RETROSPECTION, n. RETROSPECTIVE, adj., n."
            },
            "TORRENT": {
              "word": "TORRENT",
              "phonetic": "(tor'-ÔøΩnt",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a flood, deluge \nA TORRENT is a rush or surge of water or other liquid. The word stresses the rapidity and violence of the water. \n\"Their rowboat was swept away in the TORRENT.\" \n\"A TORRENT of lava flooded the city at the foot of the volcano.\" \nTORRENT is also used about any kind of sudden surge. \n\"The quarterback was greeted with a TORRENT of abuse from the crowd.\""
            },
            "ZENITH": {
              "word": "ZENITH",
              "phonetic": "(zE'-nith)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a peak, summit, highest point \nIn astronomy, the ZENITH is the point in the sky that is directly overhead. ZENITH has come to mean the peak or highest point of anything. \n\"The singer's popularity reached its ZENITH just after World War II.\" \n\"He was at the ZENITH of his powers when he was tragically killed in an auto accident.\" \n\"The country's prosperity was at its ZENITH for only a short time before the depression started.\""
            },
            "BIGOTED": {
              "word": "BIGOTED",
              "phonetic": "(big'-ÔøΩt-id)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "intolerant, narrow-minded \nA BIGOT is a person who is completely intolerant of any belief, opinion, or religion that differs from his own. \n\"He is such a BIGOT that he won't even speak to someone who doesn't belong to the same party as he does.\" \nBIGOTED is the adjective from BIGOT. \n\"He complained that the company executives were BIGOTED and would hire only people of their own religion.\" \n\"They didn't want to appear BIGOTED, so they invited people of different races, creeds, and political parties to the conference.\" \nThe most common mistakes for BIGOTED in the Pretest are _vicious_ and _greedy_. People who make those mistakes perhaps know that it is bad to be BIGOTED, but don't know exactly why. \nOther forms of the word: BIGOT, n. BIGOTRY, n."
            },
            "EXCEPTIONAL": {
              "word": "EXCEPTIONAL",
              "phonetic": "(ek-sep'-shÔøΩn-ÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "unusual, rare, uncommon \nAn EXCEPTION is something that doesn't follow the rule. \n\"All the students passed the test with one EXCEPTION--Tommy Jones.\" \nEXCEPTIONAL is the adjective from EXCEPTION. See _-al_ under Suffixes. Something that is EXCEPTIONAL is out of the ordinary, doesn't follow the rule. \n\"There have been an EXCEPTIONAL number of warm days this spring.\" \nThe word is usually used in a positive sense, about something that is better than average or uncommonly good. \n\"He thought it was an EXCEPTIONAL movie--one of the best he'd seen.\" \nMost people who make a mistake on this word choose _perfect_ as the synonym. Something that is EXCEPTIONAL may be unusually good, but it is not necessarily _perfect_. \nOther forms of the word: EXCEPT, v., prep. EXCEPTION, n."
            },
            "IMPERATIVE": {
              "word": "IMPERATIVE",
              "phonetic": "(im-per'-;}-tiv)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "urgent, essential, obligatory, pressing \nIMPERATIVE is related to the words _emperor_ and _imperial_. All come from a Latin word meaning to _command_. Something that is IMPERATIVE is like a command; it is not to be disobeyed or avoided. \n\"She said it was IMPERATIVE that we treat the most badly injured soldiers first.\" \n\"It is IMPERATIVE that we leave this building before it collapses.\" \nIn grammar, an IMPERATIVE sentence is one that expresses a command. \n\"Stop that right now!\" is an IMPERATIVE sentence."
            },
            "PERCEIVE": {
              "word": "PERCEIVE",
              "phonetic": "(pÔøΩr-sEv')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to notice, observe, become aware of, sense \nTo PERCEIVE something is to become aware of it, especially through the senses. \n\"We PERCEIVED a faint light in the distance.\" \n\"He could PERCEIVE very small differences in sounds.\" \n\"The critics failed to PERCEIVE the greatness of the novel until many years later.\" \n_Trick_ is often chosen as the meaning of PERCEIVE. This is probably due to a confusion of PERCEIVE with _deceive_, which means to _trick_. \nOther forms of the word: PERCEPTIBLE, adj. PERCEPTION, n. PERCEPTIVE, adj."
            }
          },
          "id": 0,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "To LEVY a fine.",
                  "answers": [
                    "increase",
                    "ignore",
                    "impose",
                    "accept",
                    "give back"
                  ],
                  "word": "LEVY",
                  "correct": "impose"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Another ONSLAUGHT.",
                  "answers": [
                    "arrival",
                    "argument",
                    "attack",
                    "death",
                    "victory"
                  ],
                  "word": "ONSLAUGHT",
                  "correct": "attack"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "THWART his effort.",
                  "answers": [
                    "delay",
                    "block",
                    "support",
                    "dislike",
                    "twist"
                  ],
                  "word": "THWART",
                  "correct": "block"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Started to DEGENERATE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "worsen",
                    "leave",
                    "fall",
                    "disappear",
                    "improve"
                  ],
                  "word": "DEGENERATE",
                  "correct": "worsen"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Among the ELITE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "last",
                    "worst",
                    "chosen",
                    "happiest",
                    "rest"
                  ],
                  "word": "ELITE",
                  "correct": "chosen"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Completely INDIFFERENT.",
                  "answers": [
                    "separate",
                    "unaware",
                    "involved",
                    "similar",
                    "uninterested"
                  ],
                  "word": "INDIFFERENT",
                  "correct": "uninterested"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "KALEIDOSCOPIC events.",
                  "answers": [
                    "publicly seen",
                    "important",
                    "faraway",
                    "strange",
                    "continually changing"
                  ],
                  "word": "KALEIDOSCOPIC",
                  "correct": "continually changing"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PATERNAL cares.",
                  "answers": [
                    "brotherly",
                    "inherited",
                    "motherly",
                    "continual",
                    "fatherly"
                  ],
                  "word": "PATERNAL",
                  "correct": "fatherly"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "In RETROSPECT.",
                  "answers": [
                    "review",
                    "admiration",
                    "sight",
                    "planning",
                    "politeness"
                  ],
                  "word": "RETROSPECT",
                  "correct": "review"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Sudden TORRENT.",
                  "answers": [
                    "fire",
                    "flood",
                    "silence",
                    "fear",
                    "wind"
                  ],
                  "word": "TORRENT",
                  "correct": "flood"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Approached the ZENITH.",
                  "answers": [
                    "bottom",
                    "wizard",
                    "peak",
                    "radio",
                    "end"
                  ],
                  "word": "ZENITH",
                  "correct": "peak"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They were BIGOTED.",
                  "answers": [
                    "open-minded",
                    "intolerant",
                    "worried",
                    "vicious",
                    "greedy"
                  ],
                  "word": "BIGOTED",
                  "correct": "intolerant"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They were EXCEPTIONAL.",
                  "answers": [
                    "unnecessary",
                    "perfect",
                    "unusual",
                    "unfair",
                    "normal"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXCEPTIONAL",
                  "correct": "unusual"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IMPERATIVE statements.",
                  "answers": [
                    "urgent",
                    "tender",
                    "royal",
                    "harsh",
                    "pleading"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPERATIVE",
                  "correct": "urgent"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To PERCEIVE them.",
                  "answers": [
                    "describe",
                    "show",
                    "hide",
                    "trick",
                    "notice"
                  ],
                  "word": "PERCEIVE",
                  "correct": "notice"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Do ordinary citizens LEVY taxes?",
                  "word": "LEVY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could an ONSLAUGHT be dangerous?",
                  "word": "ONSLAUGHT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do you assist someone by THWARTING him?",
                  "word": "THWART",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a DEGENERATE make a pleasant neighbor?",
                  "word": "DEGENERATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do most people belong to the social ELITE?",
                  "word": "ELITE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do people get excited about INDIFFERENT movies?",
                  "word": "INDIFFERENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are KALEIDOSCOPIC events often exciting?",
                  "word": "KALEIDOSCOPIC",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would your PATERNAL grandfather be your father's father?",
                  "word": "PATERNAL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "When a person talks about something in RETROSPECT, is he talking about the future?",
                  "word": "RETROSPECT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can someone speak with a TORRENT of words?",
                  "word": "TORRENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "If someone's reputation is at its ZENITH, is it as high as it will ever get?",
                  "word": "ZENITH",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does a BIGOT believe that everyone should be treated equally?",
                  "word": "BIGOT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would it be EXCEPTIONAL for someone to run a mile in less than three minutes?",
                  "word": "EXCEPTIONAL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is \"Are you coming?\" an IMPERATIVE sentence?",
                  "word": "IMPERATIVE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can you PERCEIVE something with your eyes?",
                  "word": "PERCEIVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Congress passed an additional LEVY on imported oil.",
                  "word": "LEVY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The ONSLAUGHT of the blizzard caught them completely unprepared.",
                  "word": "ONSLAUGHT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Every time she tried to go to the beach something happened to THWART her plans.",
                  "word": "THWART",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The new power plant DEGENERATES a great deal of electricity.",
                  "word": "DEGENERATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Several ELITE musicians were chosen to play at the White House.",
                  "word": "ELITE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The judge was INDIFFERENT to the criminal's cries for mercy.",
                  "word": "INDIFFERENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The result was completely KALEIDOSCOPIC. All our work was ruined.",
                  "word": "KALEIDOSCOPIC",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Her PATERNAL instincts were aroused whenever she saw a newborn baby.",
                  "word": "PATERNAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "In RETROSPECT we realized we should have paid more attention to our parents.",
                  "word": "RETROSPECT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The lake was so calm and peaceful it looked like a TORRENT.",
                  "word": "TORRENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Fads quickly reach the ZENITH of their popularity, and then they fade away just as quickly.",
                  "word": "ZENITH",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His BIGOTED attitude makes it difficult for him to accept others on their individual merits.",
                  "word": "BIGOT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The fourth pair of skis was EXCEPTIONAL, since only three of us were going skiing.",
                  "word": "EXCEPTIONAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The teacher felt it was IMPERATIVE that her students be able to read well.",
                  "word": "IMPERATIVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Too late he PERCEIVED that she had been right from the start.",
                  "word": "PERCEIVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "LEVY",
                  "answers": [
                    "gift",
                    "tax",
                    "fine"
                  ],
                  "word": "LEVY",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ONSLAUGHT",
                  "answers": [
                    "battle",
                    "retreat",
                    "assault"
                  ],
                  "word": "ONSLAUGHT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "THWART",
                  "answers": [
                    "bother",
                    "frustrate",
                    "despise"
                  ],
                  "word": "THWART",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DEGENERATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "decay",
                    "defend",
                    "decline"
                  ],
                  "word": "DEGENERATE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ELITE",
                  "answers": [
                    "young",
                    "noble",
                    "best"
                  ],
                  "word": "ELITE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INDIFFERENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "ridiculous",
                    "unbiased",
                    "average"
                  ],
                  "word": "INDIFFERENT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "KALEIDOSCOPIC",
                  "answers": [
                    "changing",
                    "improving",
                    "varying"
                  ],
                  "word": "KALEIDOSCOPIC",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PATERNAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "brotherly",
                    "fatherly",
                    "grandfatherly"
                  ],
                  "word": "PATERNAL",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RETROSPECT",
                  "answers": [
                    "memory",
                    "decision",
                    "past"
                  ],
                  "word": "RETROSPECT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TORRENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "rapid",
                    "strength",
                    "heat"
                  ],
                  "word": "TORRENT",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ZENITH",
                  "answers": [
                    "top",
                    "acme",
                    "beginning"
                  ],
                  "word": "ZENITH",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BIGOTED",
                  "answers": [
                    "intolerant",
                    "contemptuous",
                    "impatient"
                  ],
                  "word": "BIGOT",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EXCEPTIONAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "pleasant",
                    "rare",
                    "outstanding"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXCEPTIONAL",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IMPERATIVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "important",
                    "crucial",
                    "unusual"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPERATIVE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PERCEIVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "view",
                    "comprehend",
                    "select"
                  ],
                  "word": "PERCEIVE",
                  "correct": "2"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "6.2",
          "definitions": {
            "IMPAIR": {
              "word": "IMPAIR",
              "phonetic": "(im-pÔøΩr')v.:",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "make worse, weaken, injure \nTo IMPAIR something is to make it worse, to do harm to it. The word often suggests damage that gradually increases. \n\"Smoking cigarettes will damage your lungs and IMPAIR your breathing.\" \n\"His eyesight was IMPAIRED by reading in very dim light.\" \n\"The scandal will IMPAIR their chances of winning the election.\" \nIn the Pretest, many people choose _destroy_ as the meaning of IMPAIR. When you IMPAIR something, you cause it some damage, but you do not _destroy_ it."
            },
            "SYNOPSIS": {
              "word": "SYNOPSIS",
              "phonetic": "(si-nop'-sis)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a summary, outline \nA SYNOPSIS is a short summary or outline, usually of the plot of a book, play, or movie. \n\"It was difficult to make an understandable SYNOPSIS of a book with so many characters doing so many different things.\" \n\"According to the SYNOPSIS, the next act takes place in the living room.\" \n\"The announcer gave a SYNOPSIS of the president's speech and summarized the main ideas.\" \n\"We hurriedly read through several SYNOPSES to prepare for the test.\" \nUsage: The plural form of SYNOPSIS is SYNOPSES."
            },
            "BLISS": {
              "word": "BLISS",
              "phonetic": "(blis)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "joy, happiness, delight \nBLISS is a state of complete happiness or great joy. It is a very strong word, and often refers to the joys of heaven. \n\"She was unhappy in life, but hoped for eternal BLISS after death.\" \n\"When he fell in love, he realized he had never known such BLISS before.\" \n\"Their years of perfect BLISS were ended when he became ill.\" \nBLISSFUL is the adjective from BLISS and means \"full of or causing great happiness.\" \"BLISSFUL ignorance\" is happiness resulting from a lack of knowledge of events or circumstances that could cause unhappiness. \n\"They lived in BLISSFUL ignorance of the great dangers that surrounded them.\" \nOther forms of the word: BLISSFUL, adj."
            },
            "INFRINGE": {
              "word": "INFRINGE",
              "phonetic": "(in-frinj')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to break, violate; to encroach, trespass \nTo INFRINGE a rule, law, or agreement is to break it, to fail to obey it. \n\"He accused us of INFRINGING the contract we had signed with him.\" \n\"They INFRINGED the treaty by sending troops into the other country.\" \nINFRINGE is often used with _on_ or _upon_ to mean \"to break in upon,\" to _encroach_. \n\"We must never INFRINGE upon the rights of others.\" The noun form of INFRINGE is INFRINGEMENT, the act of violating or trespassing. \n\"He was accused of copyright infringement because he printed the photo in his book without getting the photographer's authorization.\" \nOther forms of the word: INFRINGEMENT, n."
            },
            "MICROBE": {
              "word": "MICROBE",
              "phonetic": "(ml'-krOb)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a bacterium, germ \nThe prefix _micro-_ means _very small_. It is used in the word _microscope_, which is an instrument that helps you to see very small objects. A MICROBE is a very small living creature, one that is invisible to the naked eye. The word is used especially about small living things that cause diseases. \n\"There are thousands of tiny MICROBES in the air we breathe.\" \n\"The scientists tried to discover the MICROBE that was responsible for the mysterious deaths of the animals.\" \nThe most commonly chosen incorrect answer is _atom_. An _atom_, of course, is a very small thing--in fact, far smaller than a MICROBE. The key difference is that a MICROBE is _alive_ while an atom isn't."
            },
            "NONENTITY": {
              "word": "NONENTITY",
              "phonetic": "(non-en'-tÔøΩtE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "an unimportant person or thing \nAn ENTITY is something that exists. The basic meaning of NONENTITY is \"something that does not really exist.\" See _non-_ under Prefixes. Usually, though, NONENTITY is used about a person who is so undistinguished and insignificant that it is as if he didn't exist. \n\"Although he came from a famous family, he himself was a NONENTITY.\" \n\"Everyone thought he was a complete NONENTITY, but then it turned out he was a prince in disguise.\""
            },
            "TREMULOUS": {
              "word": "TREMULOUS",
              "phonetic": "(trem'-y:-1:s)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "quivering, trembling; timid, fearful \nTREMULOUS is related to the word _tremble_. Someone or something that is TREMULOUS trembles or shakes. \n\"The old lady could not hold the cup of tea in her TREMULOUS hands.\" \nWhen used about a person, TREMULOUS sometimes suggests that the trembling is due to fear or nervousness. \n\"The boy TREMULOUSLY asked the girl if she would dance with him.\" \nMany people pick _huge_ as the meaning of TREMULOUS. They are probably confusing TREMULOUS with _tremendous_, which sounds and looks very much like it."
            },
            "VOID": {
              "word": "VOID",
              "phonetic": "(voyd)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "emptiness, vacancy \nA VOID is an empty, unfilled space. \n\"He gazed into the limitless VOID of outer space.\" \n\"There is an aching VOID in my heart since you left me.\" \n\"The car plunged over the cliff and into the VOID.\" \nVOID is also an adjective, meaning _empty_, _vacant_. The word is usually found in the legal term, \"null and VOID,\" which means \"having no legal force.\" \n\"The judge declared that the contract was null and VOID.\" VOID is also used in this sense as a verb, meaning to _nullify_. \n\"The judge VOIDED the contract.\""
            },
            "ASSAIL": {
              "word": "ASSAIL",
              "phonetic": "(:-sAI')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to attack, assault \nTo ASSAIL someone is to attack him, usually suddenly or repeatedly. \n\"The mob ASSAILED the soldiers with rocks and sticks.\" \n\"He was ASSAILED by blows on the head as he tried to escape from the crowd.\" \nASSAIL can be used in a general sense about any kind of attack. \n\"As soon as he started the project he was ASSAILED by doubts about whether it would be successful.\" \nAn ASSAILANT is someone who attacks. \n\"Dick was beaten up in the alley by several unknown ASSAILANTS.\" \nOther forms of the word: ASSAILANT, n."
            },
            "HYPOCRISY": {
              "word": "HYPOCRISY",
              "phonetic": "(hi-pok'-r:-sE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "insincerity, deceit \nHYPOCRISY comes from a Greek word meaning _acting_. Someone who practices HYPOCRISY acts good or virtuous when in reality he isn't. \n\"I can't believe his HYPOCRISY. He always talks about how wrong it is to lie, and he's the worst liar I know.\" \n\"The reporter exposed the HYPOCRISY of the religious leader who in private was a cruel and evil man.\" \nA HYPOCRITE is someone who pretends to be virtuous when he isn't. \n\"They're all HYPOCRITES who don't practice what they preach.\" \n_Vanity_ is a popular choice as the meaning of HYPOCRISY. Both _vanity_ and HYPOCRISY are vices, but a person can have one fault without the other. \nOther forms of the word: HYPOCRITE, n. HYPOCRITICAL, adj."
            },
            "DESTITUTE": {
              "word": "DESTITUTE",
              "phonetic": "(des'-t:-tUt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "extremely poor, needy; lacking, deprived \nSomeone who is DESTITUTE is absolutely penniless and lacks the basic necessities of life, such as food, clothing, and shelter. \n\"They had always been poor, but the fire left them homeless and completely DESTITUTE.\" \n\"I have never been DESTITUTE, but I know what it's like to go hungry.\" \n\"When Mr. Jones died, his widow was left DESTITUTE.\" \nThe phrase DESTITUTE _of_ means _lacking_, _not having_, _devoid_. \n\"We could tell the tree was dying because it was completely DESTITUTE of leaves in the middle of the summer.\" \n\"The cruel dictator was DESTITUTE of ordinary human feelings.\""
            },
            "ENDOW": {
              "word": "ENDOW",
              "phonetic": "(en-dow')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to provide, give \nENDOW means to _give_ or _provide_ something for the benefit of a person or an institution. \n\"The grateful parent ENDOWED a new wing in the hospital in his son's name.\" \n\"The school is looking for someone to ENDOW a new library.\" \nTo be ENDOWED _with_ something is to have it naturally. \n\"She is ENDOWED with a great talent for painting.\" \n\"He was ENDOWED with the gift for making money.\" \nThe noun form of ENDOW is ENDOWMENT, which means a _gift_, usually of money or property. \n\"Harvard College received an ENDOWMENT of several hundred books.\" \nOther forms of the word: ENDOWMENT, n."
            },
            "IMBECILIC": {
              "word": "IMBECILIC",
              "phonetic": "(im-bÔøΩ-sil'-ik)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "idiotic, weak-minded \nAn IMBECILE is an extremely weak-minded person, one who cannot develop mentally beyond the age of about seven. IMBECILIC is the adjective from IMBECILE, and means \"like an IMBECILE.\" \nSee _-ic_ under Suffixes. \n\"His actions were so IMBECILIC that no one could believe he was an adult.\" \n\"She said Bill's ideas were IMBECILIC and not worth discussing.\" \nOther forms of the word: IMBECILE, n."
            },
            "LOATH": {
              "word": "LOATH",
              "phonetic": "(10th)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "unwilling, reluctant, disinclined \nLOATH means _extremely unwilling_, _reluctant_. \n\"He was LOATH to go.\" \n\"They were LOATH to lend us any more money until we had paid back what we already owed.\" \n\"I am LOATH to sign anything I haven't read first.\" \nDo not confuse LOATH and _loathe_ (pronounced (pronunciation). The verb _loathe_ means to _hate_, to _despise_. \n\"I _loathe_ having to get up early.\" \nLOATH has a similar meaning, but is only used as an adjective. \n\"He is LOATH to stay behind. He loathes being left out of anything.\" \nUsage: LOATH is also sometimes spelled loth."
            },
            "THRONG": {
              "word": "THRONG",
              "phonetic": "(throng)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a crowd, multitude \nA THRONG is a great number of people crowded together. \n\"THRONGS of people came to see the hit movie.\" \n\"The small child got lost in the THRONG at the parade.\" \nTHRONG is also a verb, meaning to _crowd together_ or to _fill by crowding_. \n\"People THRONGED into the street for the parade.\" \n\"The park was THRONGED with people waiting to hear the concert.\""
            }
          },
          "id": 1,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Was it IMPAIRED?",
                  "answers": [
                    "weakened",
                    "increased",
                    "destroyed",
                    "improved",
                    "changed"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPAIR",
                  "correct": "weakened"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Another SYNOPSIS.",
                  "answers": [
                    "conclusion",
                    "prediction",
                    "viewpoint",
                    "summary",
                    "report"
                  ],
                  "word": "SYNOPSIS",
                  "correct": "summary"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Unending BLISS.",
                  "answers": [
                    "joy",
                    "sorrow",
                    "excitement",
                    "laughter",
                    "prayers"
                  ],
                  "word": "BLISS",
                  "correct": "joy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He INFRINGED the agreement.",
                  "answers": [
                    "tore up",
                    "opposed",
                    "hated",
                    "wrote",
                    "broke"
                  ],
                  "word": "INFRINGE",
                  "correct": "broke"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Studied the MICROBE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "atom",
                    "star",
                    "germ",
                    "loudspeaker",
                    "spotlight"
                  ],
                  "word": "MICROBE",
                  "correct": "germ"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Talked to the NONENTITY.",
                  "answers": [
                    "masked man",
                    "same one",
                    "new soldier",
                    "clerk",
                    "unimportant person"
                  ],
                  "word": "NONENTITY",
                  "correct": "unimportant person"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TREMULOUS hands.",
                  "answers": [
                    "tiny",
                    "steady",
                    "huge",
                    "broken",
                    "quivering"
                  ],
                  "word": "TREMULOUS",
                  "correct": "quivering"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Complete VOID.",
                  "answers": [
                    "total",
                    "change",
                    "confusion",
                    "emptiness",
                    "darkness"
                  ],
                  "word": "VOID",
                  "correct": "emptiness"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He ASSAILED it.",
                  "answers": [
                    "approved",
                    "attacked",
                    "destroyed",
                    "launched",
                    "despised"
                  ],
                  "word": "ASSAIL",
                  "correct": "attacked"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His HYPOCRISY.",
                  "answers": [
                    "vanity",
                    "insincerity",
                    "theory",
                    "interest",
                    "hatred"
                  ],
                  "word": "HYPOCRISY",
                  "correct": "insincerity"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DESTITUTE people.",
                  "answers": [
                    "unhappy",
                    "diseased",
                    "wealthy",
                    "poor",
                    "filthy"
                  ],
                  "word": "DESTITUTE",
                  "correct": "poor"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ENDOWED by our Creator.",
                  "answers": [
                    "provided",
                    "loved",
                    "taken away",
                    "permitted",
                    "made"
                  ],
                  "word": "ENDOW",
                  "correct": "provided"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IMBECILIC remarks.",
                  "answers": [
                    "drunken",
                    "funny",
                    "important",
                    "religious",
                    "idiotic"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMBECILIC",
                  "correct": "idiotic"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LOATH to go.",
                  "answers": [
                    "not ready",
                    "eager",
                    "unwilling",
                    "unable",
                    "happy"
                  ],
                  "word": "LOATH",
                  "correct": "unwilling"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Saw the THRONG.",
                  "answers": [
                    "boat",
                    "shoe",
                    "family",
                    "crowd",
                    "king"
                  ],
                  "word": "THRONG",
                  "correct": "crowd"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Will eating poisoned food IMPAIR your health?",
                  "word": "IMPAIR",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does the SYNOPSIS of a book include every word?",
                  "word": "SYNOPSIS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is BLISS a pleasant sensation?",
                  "word": "BLISS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would most people like to have somebody INFRINGE upon their rights?",
                  "word": "INFRINGE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it difficult to see a MICROBE?",
                  "word": "MICROBE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Was Julius Caesar a NONENTITY?",
                  "word": "NONENTITY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would TREMULOUS handwriting be difficult to read?",
                  "word": "TREMULOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a VOID be very large?",
                  "word": "VOID",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do people enjoy being ASSAILED?",
                  "word": "ASSAIL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are HYPOCRITES usually trustworthy?",
                  "word": "HYPOCRITE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a millionaire be DESTITUTE?",
                  "word": "DESTITUTE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are pigs ENDOWED with the ability to fly?",
                  "word": "ENDOW",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would most people like to be called IMBECILIC?",
                  "word": "IMBICILIC",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are children usually LOATH to eat ice cream?",
                  "word": "LOATH",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are you a THRONG?",
                  "word": "THRONG",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "He IMPAIRED the two of us and decided I was the better.",
                  "word": "IMPAIR",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "After reading the SYNOPSIS of the TV show in the newspaper, we decided not to watch it.",
                  "word": "SYNOPSIS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Their BLISSFUL marriage lasted over fifty years.",
                  "word": "BLISS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The truce between the countries was INFRINGED when enemy soldiers attacked our town.",
                  "word": "INFRINGE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The doctor examined the tissue under the microscope to try to spot the MICROBES.",
                  "word": "MICROBE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The public relations man said he could take any NONENTITY and make him world famous in six weeks.",
                  "word": "NONENTITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "In a TREMULOUS voice he said he'd never been so scared in his entire life.",
                  "word": "TREMULOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We built the biggest VOID in the city.",
                  "word": "VOID",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Police searched for the ASSAILANT who had attacked the man in broad daylight.",
                  "word": "ASSAIL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She felt it was HYPOCRISY to say you liked a person if you really didn't.",
                  "word": "HYPOCRISY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "This program is terrible. The actors on it are completely DESTITUTE of talent.",
                  "word": "DESTITUTE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We are ENDOWED with certain rights under our Constitution.",
                  "word": "ENDOW",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Everyone praised the play as being truly IMBECILIC.",
                  "word": "IMBICILIC",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The boss was LOATH to fire anyone just before Christmas.",
                  "word": "LOATH",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "THRONGS of people visited the museum for the display of Egyptian treasures.",
                  "word": "THRONG",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "IMPAIR",
                  "answers": [
                    "harm",
                    "force",
                    "damage"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPAIR",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SYNOPSIS",
                  "answers": [
                    "addition",
                    "outline",
                    "sketch"
                  ],
                  "word": "SYNOPSIS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BLISS",
                  "answers": [
                    "excitement",
                    "happiness",
                    "delight"
                  ],
                  "word": "BLISS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INFRINGE",
                  "answers": [
                    "violate",
                    "forget",
                    "trespass"
                  ],
                  "word": "INFRINGE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MICROBE",
                  "answers": [
                    "tininess",
                    "creature",
                    "brightness"
                  ],
                  "word": "MICROBE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "NONENTITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "unknown",
                    "being",
                    "insignificance"
                  ],
                  "word": "NONENTITY",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TREMULOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "shaking",
                    "afraid",
                    "nasty"
                  ],
                  "word": "TREMULOUS",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VOID",
                  "answers": [
                    "distant",
                    "hollow",
                    "vacant"
                  ],
                  "word": "VOID",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ASSAIL",
                  "answers": [
                    "hit",
                    "beat",
                    "chase"
                  ],
                  "word": "ASSAIL",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HYPOCRISY",
                  "answers": [
                    "lie",
                    "pretense",
                    "argument"
                  ],
                  "word": "HYPOCRISY",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DESTITUTE",
                  "answers": [
                    "starving",
                    "penniless",
                    "forgotten"
                  ],
                  "word": "DESTITUTE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ENDOW",
                  "answers": [
                    "give",
                    "finance",
                    "insure"
                  ],
                  "word": "ENDOW",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IMBECILIC",
                  "answers": [
                    "idiotic",
                    "silly",
                    "humorous"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMBICILIC",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LOATH",
                  "answers": [
                    "required",
                    "opposed",
                    "hesitant"
                  ],
                  "word": "LOATH",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "THRONG",
                  "answers": [
                    "battle",
                    "horde",
                    "mob"
                  ],
                  "word": "THRONG",
                  "correct": "0"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "6.3",
          "definitions": {
            "CAVORT": {
              "word": "CAVORT",
              "phonetic": "(k:l-vort')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to make merry, prance, jump about \nTo CAVORT is to make merry, usually by jumping and dancing about. The word was originally used about a horse and its rider. \n\"The mother dog looked on calmly while her puppies CAVORTED in the tall grass.\" \n\"We enjoyed watching the children CAVORTING on the beach.\" \n\"The students CAVORTED on the steps of the school, happy to be going home at last.\""
            },
            "CONCEDE": {
              "word": "CONCEDE",
              "phonetic": "(k:ln-sEd')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to admit, acknowledge; to grant, surrender \nCONCEDE has two different meanings. To CONCEDE something is to admit that it is true. \n\"After a long debate Ed finally CONCEDED the point and said we were right.\" \n\"We CONCEDED that we had been a bit hasty in criticizing her.\" \nThe word can also mean to _grant_ or _surrender_. \n\"When Jim injured his foot he had to CONCEDE the match to his opponent.\" \n\"As part of the peace treaty they CONCEDED all the territory they had won in the war.\" \nThe most common mistake in the Pretest is to choose _deny_ as the meaning of CONCEDE. This is a confusion of a word with its opposite. People who choose _deny_ as the meaning of CONCEDE perhaps know that CONCEDE has something to do with the truth, but aren't exactly sure what. \nOther forms of the word: CONCESSION, n."
            },
            "INTEGRAL": {
              "word": "INTEGRAL",
              "phonetic": "(in'-tÔøΩgr:ll",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "necessary for completeness, essential \nINTEGRAL is from a Latin word meaning _whole_, _entire_, also the source of the word _integer_. An _integer_, in arithmetic, is a whole number (1, 2, 3, 4 . . .) as opposed to a fraction. Something that is INTEGRAL to something else is necessary for its completeness. \n\"This piece is INTEGRAL to the machine. If you remove it, nothing will work.\" \nINTEGRAL is often found in the phrase \"an INTEGRAL part of,\" which means a _necessary_ or _essential_ part of. \n\"Learning vocabulary is an INTEGRAL part of education; without words you can't read.\""
            },
            "DOTING": {
              "word": "DOTING",
              "phonetic": "(dOt'-ing)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": ": overly fond; weak-minded \nTo DOTE on someone is to show excessive affection for him. \n\"Our grandmother DOTES on us; she'll give us anything we want.\" \nDOTING is the adjective from DOTE, and means \"showing too much fondness.\" \n\"The DOTING parents couldn't keep their eyes off their new baby.\" \n\"The DOTING husband brought his wife flowers every night.\" \nIn another sense, DOTING is sometimes used to mean _weak-minded_, especially from old age. This sense is particularly found in the noun DOTAGE, which means \"feebleness of mind resulting from old age.\" \n\"In his DOTAGE his mind started to wander and it was hard to understand him.\" \nOther forms of the word: DOTAGE, n. DOTE, v."
            },
            "INTERIM": {
              "word": "INTERIM",
              "phonetic": "(in'-tÔøΩr-im)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "temporary, provisional \nINTERIM comes directly from a Latin word which means \"in the meantime,\" _meanwhile_. INTERIM is used as a noun in the phrase \"in the INTERIM,\" which means exactly the same as the Latin word. As an adjective, INTERIM means \"done or occurring in the meantime,\" _temporary_. \n\"They issued an INTERIM report until the new set of figures came in and they could make it final.\" \n\"They set up an INTERIM government to rule while the new constitution was being written.\""
            },
            "LACKLUSTER": {
              "word": "LACKLUSTER",
              "phonetic": "(lak'-luhs-tÔøΩr)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "dull, uninspired \n_Luster_ is _brightness_, the glow of a polished surface. Something which is LACKLUSTER lacks _luster_ or brightness; it is dull, uninspired. The word is especially used about expressions, actions, events, and the like. \n\"She always had a LACKLUSTER expression on her face, as if she weren't interested in anything.\" \n\"It was a LACKLUSTER performance--nothing very good about it, nothing very bad about it.\" \nMany people think LACKLUSTER means _terrible_. LACKLUSTER, however, is not that strong. It merely means _dull_, _uninteresting_, _lacking brilliance_."
            },
            "CONVULSION": {
              "word": "CONVULSION",
              "phonetic": "(kÔøΩn-vuhl'-shÔøΩn)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a fit, disturbance, upheaval \nTo CONVULSE is to shake violently. \n\"California was CONVULSED by an earthquake.\" \nCONVULSION is the noun from CONVULSE. A CONVULSION is a violent shaking or disturbance, particularly the uncontrolled irregular movements of the muscles during a fit. In this case the word is usually used in the plural. \n\"The child went into CONVULSIONS after she swallowed the poison.\" \nA CONVULSION can also be any kind of disturbance or upheaval. \n\"Constant social CONVULSIONS kept the nation in a state of chaos for years.\" \nThe most popular wrong answers on the Pretest are _illness_ and _urge_. A CONVULSION can be caused by an _illness_, but its meaning is much more specific. The choice of _urge_ is probably due in most cases to a confusion between CONVULSION and _compulsion_, which is a strong _urge_. \nOther forms of the word: CONVULSE, v. CONVULSIVE, adj."
            },
            "PLAUSIBLE": {
              "word": "PLAUSIBLE",
              "phonetic": "(plo'-zÔøΩbÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "likely, apparently reasonable \nSomething that is PLAUSIBLE has the appearance of being true. A PLAUSIBLE argument sounds true and makes sense, even if in fact it is not true. \n\"He gave the teacher a PLAUSIBLE reason about why he hadn't done his homework.\" \n\"Her excuse sounded PLAUSIBLE at the time, but later on we found out she had been lying.\" \nThe opposite of PLAUSIBLE is IMPLAUSIBLE, which mean _unlikely_, _improbable_. \n\"The account of his adventures sounded IMPLAUSIBLE, but in fact that was exactly what had happened.\" \nOther forms of the word: PLAUSIBILITY, n."
            },
            "WHIMSICAL": {
              "word": "WHIMSICAL",
              "phonetic": "(hwim'-zÔøΩkÔøΩI",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "playful, fanciful, fantastic \nWHIMSICAL is an adjective from WHIMSY. See _-ic_ under Suffixes. WHIMSY is odd or fanciful humor, or the product of such humor. \n\"He is full of WHIMSY; he always has such fanciful ideas.\" \nSomeone or something that is WHIMSICAL is full of such odd notions or behavior. \n\"Although usually very serious, he could sometimes be very strange and WHIMSICAL.\" \n\"Her WHIMSICAL behavior bewildered everyone. She was always doing the oddest things at the most unexpected times.\" \n\"He told the children a WHIMSICAL story about how elves paint the grass green.\" \nOther forms of the word: WHIM, n. WHIMSY, n."
            },
            "ABORIGINE": {
              "word": "ABORIGINE",
              "phonetic": "(ab-ÔøΩ-rij'-ÔøΩ-nE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a native, original inhabitant \nNote the pronunciation. The _e_ is sounded. \nYou can see the word _origin_ in ABORIGINE. ABORIGINE comes from the Latin phrase _ab origine_, which means \"from the beginning.\" An ABORIGINE is one of the native people of a region or country. ABORIGINES have lived in a particular region \"from the beginning.\" They were the very first people to come into the region from somewhere else and settle there. \n\"The colonists arriving from across the sea found the ABORIGINES friendly and willing to share their land.\" \n\"The invading tribe conquered the ABORIGINES and made them leave their native land.\" \nThe word ABORIGINES is also used for the original flowers and animals in a particular region. \nOther forms of the word: ABORIGINAL, adj."
            },
            "CEREBRAL": {
              "word": "CEREBRAL",
              "phonetic": "(ser'-ÔøΩ-brÔøΩI",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "mental, intellectual \nThe CEREBRUM is a part of the brain. The basic meaning of CEREBRAL is \"of the CEREBRUM or the brain.\" See _-al_ under Suffixes. CEREBRAL _palsy_ is a disability caused by damage to the brain. When used about people or their activities, CEREBRAL means _intellectual_, as opposed to _emotional_. A CEREBRAL person mainly uses his reasoning and critical powers, and not his intuitions or instincts. \n\"He is a CEREBRAL writer; his stories aren't exciting, but they give a lot of food for thought.\""
            },
            "INCITE": {
              "word": "INCITE",
              "phonetic": "in-sit')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to stir up, spur on, urge on, arouse \nTo INCITE is to stir up, to urge somebody to do something. Usually the word suggests that something bad is being stirred up. \n\"Her fiery speeches INCITED them to riot.\" \n\"His tales of gold hidden inside INCITED the crowd to break into the building and steal everything they could find.\" \n\"The assassination of the prince INCITED violence between the two warring parties.\" \nThe noun from INCITE is INCITEMENT, something that stirs people up. \n\"The umpire's one bad call was enough of an INCITEMENT for the crowd to boo him for the rest of the game.\" \nOther forms of the word: INCITEMENT, n."
            },
            "COSMOPOLITAN": {
              "word": "COSMOPOLITAN",
              "phonetic": "(koz-mÔøΩ-pol'-ÔøΩ-tÔøΩn)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "worldwide, universal, worldly \nCOSMOPOLITAN comes from two Greek words. The _cosmo_ part of the word means _world_ or _universe_; it is also found in the words COSMOS and COSMONAUT. The _polit_ part means _citizen_; it also appears in _politics_ and _police_. COSMOPOLITAN is used about people or things that are at home all over the world. It is especially applied to people who are free from local prejudices or interests, who have a broad, sophisticated outlook. \n\"Jim has a COSMOPOLITAN background; he lived in six different countries before he was twelve.\" \n\"He believed that statesmen should have a COSMOPOLITAN point of view when trying to solve world problems.\""
            },
            "DERIVATION": {
              "word": "DERIVATION",
              "phonetic": "(der-ÔøΩ-vA'-shÔøΩn)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "source, origin \nTo DERIVE means to _take_ or _obtain_, especially from a source. \n\"We DERIVE great pleasure from watching television.\" \n\"The name of this town is DERIVED from an Indian word.\" \nThe DERIVATION of something is its source or origin. \n\"What is the DERIVATION of the custom of collecting candy on Halloween?\" \nDERIVATION is used especially about the development of a word from earlier words. \n\"Many English words are of Latin DERIVATION.\" \n\"The teacher explained the DERIVATION of the word amateur.\" \nOther forms of the word: DERIVATIVE, adj. DERIVE, v."
            },
            "FRACAS": {
              "word": "FRACAS",
              "phonetic": "(frA'-kÔøΩs",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a disturbance, uproar, noisy quarrel, fight, brawl \nA FRACAS is a noisy disturbance, an uproar. The word is generally used about people fighting or disagreeing with one another. \n\"A FRACAS erupted among some spectators who had been drinking.\" \n\"Two policemen were injured trying to end the FRACAS.\" \n\"A nice party suddenly became a FRACAS when everyone started arguing about politics.\" \nA FRACAS is smaller and less serious than a _riot_, but larger and usually more violent than a _quarrel_."
            }
          },
          "id": 2,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Watched them CAVORT.",
                  "answers": [
                    "rest",
                    "make merry",
                    "eat",
                    "answer",
                    "change"
                  ],
                  "word": "CAVORT",
                  "correct": "make merry"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He will CONCEDE it.",
                  "answers": [
                    "overcome",
                    "announce",
                    "deny",
                    "admit",
                    "lose"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONCEDE",
                  "correct": "admit"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INTEGRAL parts.",
                  "answers": [
                    "different",
                    "reliable",
                    "essential",
                    "useless",
                    "perfect"
                  ],
                  "word": "INTEGRAL",
                  "correct": "essential"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DOTING parents.",
                  "answers": [
                    "capable",
                    "overly fond",
                    "mean-spirited",
                    "cheerful",
                    "self-satisfied"
                  ],
                  "word": "DOTING",
                  "correct": "overly fond"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INTERIM chief.",
                  "answers": [
                    "next",
                    "new",
                    "first",
                    "temporary",
                    "former"
                  ],
                  "word": "INTERIM",
                  "correct": "temporary"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LACKLUSTER performances.",
                  "answers": [
                    "pleasant",
                    "overwhelming",
                    "terrible",
                    "dull",
                    "sad"
                  ],
                  "word": "LACKLUSTER",
                  "correct": "dull"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Sudden CONVULSION.",
                  "answers": [
                    "hope",
                    "hatred",
                    "urge",
                    "fit",
                    "illness"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONVULSION",
                  "correct": "fit"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PLAUSIBLE excuse.",
                  "answers": [
                    "unusual",
                    "typical",
                    "perfect",
                    "poor",
                    "likely"
                  ],
                  "word": "PLAUSIBLE",
                  "correct": "likely"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "WHIMSICAL ideas.",
                  "answers": [
                    "playful",
                    "serious",
                    "original",
                    "useless",
                    "dangerous"
                  ],
                  "word": "WHIMSICAL",
                  "correct": "playful"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "More ABORIGINES.",
                  "answers": [
                    "slaves",
                    "natives",
                    "mountains",
                    "foreigners",
                    "animals"
                  ],
                  "word": "ABORIGINE",
                  "correct": "natives"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CEREBRAL activity.",
                  "answers": [
                    "happy",
                    "mental",
                    "physical",
                    "religious",
                    "serious"
                  ],
                  "word": "CEREBRAL",
                  "correct": "mental"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To INCITE the rebellion.",
                  "answers": [
                    "understand",
                    "stir up",
                    "put down",
                    "plan",
                    "approve of"
                  ],
                  "word": "INCITE",
                  "correct": "stir up"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "COSMOPOLITAN interests.",
                  "answers": [
                    "expensive",
                    "immoral",
                    "religious",
                    "local",
                    "worldwide"
                  ],
                  "word": "COSMOPOLITAN",
                  "correct": "worldwide"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We knew its DERIVATION.",
                  "answers": [
                    "source",
                    "purpose",
                    "contents",
                    "meaning",
                    "result"
                  ],
                  "word": "DERIVATION",
                  "correct": "source"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Ended the FRACAS.",
                  "answers": [
                    "game",
                    "silence",
                    "party",
                    "fight",
                    "meeting"
                  ],
                  "word": "FRACAS",
                  "correct": "fight"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Do snakes usually CAVORT?",
                  "word": "CAVORT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a stubborn person enjoy CONCEDING something?",
                  "word": "CONDEDE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is the engine an INTEGRAL part of a car?",
                  "word": "INTEGRAL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a DOTING father be proud of his children?",
                  "word": "DOTING",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Will an INTERIM plan always be used?",
                  "word": "INTERIM",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a LACKLUSTER game be very exciting?",
                  "word": "LACKLUSTER",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are CONVULSIONS usually pleasant?",
                  "word": "CONVULSION",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can PLAUSIBLE explanations be false?",
                  "word": "PLAUSIBLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a WHIMSICAL story be amusing?",
                  "word": "WHIMSICAL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Were the Pilgrims ABORIGINES in America?",
                  "word": "ABORIGINE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is falling in love a CEREBRAL activity?",
                  "word": "CEREBRAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a raise in pay sometimes INCITE people to work harder?",
                  "word": "INCITE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a COSMOPOLITAN newspaper contain just local news?",
                  "word": "COSMOPOLITAN",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do names have DERIVATIONS?",
                  "word": "DERIVATION",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could people get hurt in a FRACAS?",
                  "word": "FRACAS",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "We were so excited we CAVORTED through the halls of the school.",
                  "word": "CAVORT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "It was certain that he was going to lose, but he refused to CONCEDE defeat.",
                  "word": "CONCEDE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The idea that there was intelligent life on other planets was INTEGRAL to his theory about the universe.",
                  "word": "INTEGRAL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The DOTING boy stopped six different places on his way home from school.",
                  "word": "DOTING",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "This is just an INTERIM solution to the problem; we'll have to come up with something better before long.",
                  "word": "INTERIM",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Her dancing is brilliant, but her singing is LACKLUSTER.",
                  "word": "LACKLUSTER",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The comedian's jokes CONVULSED us with laughter; we laughed so hard our sides were aching.",
                  "word": "CONVULSE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He told an IMPLAUSIBLE tale about a trip he took to Mars.",
                  "word": "PLAUSIBLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We heard a WHIMSICAL story about bloodshed, torture, and death.",
                  "word": "WHIMSICAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The ABORIGINES could not defend their island against the invaders.",
                  "word": "ABORIGINE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He suffered a CEREBRAL in his leg.",
                  "word": "CEREBRAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The general INCITED the private for outstanding bravery.",
                  "word": "INCITE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Her COSMOPOLITAN interests took her to Europe at least once a year.",
                  "word": "COSMOPOLITAN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She DERIVED a great deal of satisfaction from seeing her son graduate from college.",
                  "word": "DERIVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "I was afraid the meeting would turn into a FRACAS if people lost their tempers.",
                  "word": "FRACAS",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "CAVORT",
                  "answers": [
                    "dance",
                    "climb",
                    "jump"
                  ],
                  "word": "CAVORT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CONCEDE",
                  "answers": [
                    "yield",
                    "grant",
                    "dispute"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONCEDE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INTEGRAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "whole",
                    "helpful",
                    "necessary"
                  ],
                  "word": "INTEGRAL",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DOTING",
                  "answers": [
                    "recognizable",
                    "fond",
                    "loving"
                  ],
                  "word": "DOTING",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INTERIM",
                  "answers": [
                    "unusual",
                    "provisional",
                    "temporary"
                  ],
                  "word": "INTERIM",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LACKLUSTER",
                  "answers": [
                    "average",
                    "boring",
                    "harmful"
                  ],
                  "word": "LACKLUSTER",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CONVULSION",
                  "answers": [
                    "trembling",
                    "fear",
                    "turbulence"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONVULSION",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PLAUSIBLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "reasonable",
                    "probable",
                    "certain"
                  ],
                  "word": "PLAUSIBLE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "WHIMSICAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "scary",
                    "odd",
                    "silly"
                  ],
                  "word": "WHIMSICAL",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ABORIGINE",
                  "answers": [
                    "original",
                    "native",
                    "despot"
                  ],
                  "word": "ABORIGINE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CEREBRAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "desirable",
                    "brainy",
                    "thoughtful"
                  ],
                  "word": "CEREBRAL",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INCITE",
                  "answers": [
                    "spur",
                    "defend",
                    "encourage"
                  ],
                  "word": "INCITE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "COSMOPOLITAN",
                  "answers": [
                    "worldly",
                    "sophisticated",
                    "young"
                  ],
                  "word": "COSMOPOLITAN",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DERIVATION",
                  "answers": [
                    "outcome",
                    "source",
                    "origin"
                  ],
                  "word": "DERIVATION",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FRACAS",
                  "answers": [
                    "riot",
                    "brawl",
                    "conversation"
                  ],
                  "word": "FRACAS",
                  "correct": "2"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        }
      ],
      "reviewTest": {
        "wordList": [
          "ABORIGINE",
          "CONVULSION",
          "ELITE",
          "INDIFFERENT",
          "NONENTITY",
          "ASSAIL",
          "DEGENERATE",
          "FRACAS",
          "INFRINGE",
          "PLAUSIBLE",
          "BIGOT",
          "DESTITUTE",
          "HYPOCRISY",
          "INTEGRAL",
          "THRONG",
          "CEREBRAL",
          "DOTING",
          "IMBECILIC",
          "LOATH",
          "TORRENT",
          "CONCEDE",
          "BLISS",
          "EXCEPTIONAL",
          "KALEIDOSCOPIC",
          "PATERNAL",
          "TREMULOUS",
          "CAVORT",
          "IMPAIR",
          "LACKLUSTER",
          "PERCEIVE",
          "VOID",
          "COSMOPOLITAN",
          "IMPERATIVE",
          "LEVY",
          "RETROSPECT",
          "WHIMSICAL",
          "DERIVATION",
          "INCITE",
          "MICROBE",
          "SYNOPSIS",
          "ZENITH",
          "ENDOW",
          "INTERIM",
          "ONSLAUGHT",
          "THWART"
        ],
        "questions": [
          {
            "part1": "We found out about his",
            "part2": "when he told us how important it was not to lose your temper. He has the worst temper I've ever seen.",
            "answer": "hypocrisy"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He was a member of the educational",
            "part2": "--one of the greatest professors in the country.",
            "answer": "elite"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The party began very pleasantly, but by midnight it had",
            "part2": "into a drunken brawl.",
            "answer": "degenerated"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He had the",
            "part2": "notion that if he flapped his arms fast enough he would be able to fly.",
            "answer": "imbecilic"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Since she was taught from childhood to hate and fear those who were of a different race, it was only natural for her to be",
            "part2": ".",
            "answer": "bigoted"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The illness caused him to go into sudden",
            "part2": "during which he lost control of his muscles.",
            "answer": "convulsions"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The dog gets very upset if another animal",
            "part2": "on her territory.",
            "answer": "infringes"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "grandparents showed pictures of the new baby to all their friends.",
            "answer": "doting"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Jack was",
            "part2": "to go to college if it meant leaving behind all his friends.",
            "answer": "loath"
          },
          {
            "part1": "When the dam burst, a(n)",
            "part2": "of water gushed out and flooded the valley.",
            "answer": "torrent"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The enemy",
            "part2": "our position with a hail of gunfire and bombs.",
            "answer": "assailed"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Linda was",
            "part2": "to John's difficulties; she didn't care if he solved his problems.",
            "answer": "indifferent"
          },
          {
            "part1": "When we pressed him about it, he",
            "part2": "that he did sometimes lose his temper.",
            "answer": "conceded"
          },
          {
            "part1": "While he was alive, people thought that he was a complete",
            "part2": ", but after he died they realized what a great artist he had been.",
            "answer": "nonentity"
          },
          {
            "part1": "There was a(n)",
            "part2": "outside the theater as people started pushing and shoving to get in.",
            "answer": "fracas"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Playing chess is a(n)",
            "part2": "activity; you really have to use your mind to do it well.",
            "answer": "cerebral"
          },
          {
            "part1": "A(n)",
            "part2": "of eager fans jammed into the airport to see the movie star.",
            "answer": "throng"
          },
          {
            "part1": "When the explorers reached the valley, they found a tribe of",
            "part2": "who must have lived there for thousands of years.",
            "answer": "aborigines"
          },
          {
            "part1": "When our father lost his job we were",
            "part2": "; we didn't even have enough money to buy food.",
            "answer": "destitute"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The coach told Ed he was a(n)",
            "part2": "part of the team. He said they couldn't get along without him.",
            "answer": "integral"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Jim’s explanation sounded",
            "part2": ", but I still didn’t believe him.",
            "answer": "plausible"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He was unable to",
            "part2": "the difference between the two colors.",
            "answer": "perceive"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The millionaire promised to",
            "part2": "a stadium for the school if they would name it after him.",
            "answer": "endow"
          },
          {
            "part1": "They reached a(n)",
            "part2": "agreement that would last until they could settle the dispute once and for all.",
            "answer": "interim"
          },
          {
            "part1": "His fiery words so",
            "part2": "the crowd that they attacked the police station.",
            "answer": "incited"
          },
          {
            "part1": "When the nation was at the",
            "part2": "of its power it ruled over half the world.",
            "answer": "zenith"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "contained a brief summary of the plot and mentioned the main characters.",
            "answer": "synopsis"
          },
          {
            "part1": "A good dictionary will give both the meaning of a word and its",
            "part2": "so that you can see how the word came to us from other languages.",
            "answer": "derivation"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The foot injury",
            "part2": "his ability to run quickly.",
            "answer": "impaired"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He had",
            "part2": "skill in playing the piano. Only a few were as good as he was.",
            "answer": "exceptional"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We knew the enemy was coming, but we were still unable to resist their",
            "part2": ".",
            "answer": "onslaught"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The happy children laughed and",
            "part2": "in the yard.",
            "answer": "cavorted"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Nothing could spoil the perfect",
            "part2": "of their happy family life.",
            "answer": "bliss"
          },
          {
            "part1": "In",
            "part2": "it is easy to see how foolish we must have looked to other people.",
            "answer": "retrospect"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The teacher had a(n)",
            "part2": "feeling toward his students. He liked to think of them as his own children.",
            "answer": "paternal"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The state",
            "part2": "a tax on cigarettes and other tobacco products.",
            "answer": "levied"
          },
          {
            "part1": "She told the children a(n)",
            "part2": "story about the adventures of a family of rabbits.",
            "answer": "whimsical"
          },
          {
            "part1": "It was a(n)",
            "part2": "party; nothing very interesting or exciting happened the whole evening.",
            "answer": "lackluster"
          },
          {
            "part1": "With his",
            "part2": "hands he was unable to get the key into the lock.",
            "answer": "tremulous"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "changes of this decade make it difficult for a historian to discuss it briefly.",
            "answer": "kaleidoscopic"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The disappearance of her favorite cat left an aching",
            "part2": "in her heart.",
            "answer": "void"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We're looking for someone with a(n)",
            "part2": "background: someone who has traveled widely and seen the world.",
            "answer": "cosmopolitan"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Nothing they could do could",
            "part2": "the evil scientist's plan to take over the world.",
            "answer": "thwart"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The scientists discovered that a tiny",
            "part2": "was causing the terrible disease.",
            "answer": "microbe"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The hurricane will hit us any minute; it is",
            "part2": "that we seek shelter immediately.",
            "answer": "imperative"
          }
        ],
        "type": "fitb"
      }
    },
    {
      "wordsets": [
        {
          "title": "6.4",
          "definitions": {
            "MANIFOLD": {
              "word": "MANIFOLD",
              "phonetic": "(kwerk)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "numerous, various, diverse \nThe suffix _-fold_ means \"multiplied by.\" To increase something a _hundredfold_ means to increase it a hundred times. The _mani-_ part of MANIFOLD is the word _many_. So MANIFOLD basically means \"multiplied by many.\" The word is used about things or actions that are numerous and varied, or that have many different features or uses. \n\"As head of the organization he has MANIFOLD responsibilities.\" \n\"One of the machine’s MANIFOLD advantages is that it is easy to fix.\" \nThe most commonly chosen incorrect answer in the Pretest is _obvious_. This is probably due to a confusion of MANIFOLD with _manifest_. _Manifest_ means \"clear to the senses,\", _evident_, _obvious_."
            },
            "QUIRK": {
              "word": "QUIRK",
              "phonetic": "(kwerk)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a peculiarity of behavior \nThe basic meaning of QUIRK is \"a sudden twist or curve.\" It is still used this way in the phrase \"a QUIRK of fate,\" which is a sudden twist or change of fate. Usually today the word means \"twists\" of behavior--that is, personal peculiarities or mannerisms. \n\"If you ignore some of the QUIRKS of his personality, he's really a very nice fellow.\" \n\"She has this odd QUIRK of always wanting to be the last one to arrive at a party.\""
            },
            "NONPAREIL": {
              "word": "NONPAREIL",
              "phonetic": "(non-pÔøΩ-rel')",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "unequaled, having no equal, the best, peerless \nNONPAREIL is a French word used in English; it means _not equaled_. See _non-_ under Prefixes. Anything which is NONPAREIL cannot be topped. It is the best. \n\"She has a marvelous, NONPAREIL beauty.\" \n\"He was a NONPAREIL boxer.\" \nSometimes NONPAREIL comes after the word it modifies. \n\"He was a boxer NONPAREIL.\" NONPAREIL is also a noun, meaning \"a person or thing that has no equal.\" \n\"She was a NONPAREIL as a pianist. I've never heard anyone better.\""
            },
            "PANG": {
              "word": "PANG",
              "phonetic": "(pang)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a sharp pain \nA PANG is a sudden, brief, sharp pain. \n\"The starving man felt PANGS of hunger.\" \nThe word is more commonly used about mental pain than physical pain. It is used about a piercing feeling of sorrow, longing, or a similar strong emotion. \n\"He suffered PANGS of conscience after he stole the bicycle.\" \n\"Jane felt a PANG of envy when she saw how popular Mary was.\" \n\"With a PANG of regret they looked back for the last time at their old house.\" \n\"She was eighteen when she first felt the PANGS of love.\""
            },
            "SWOON": {
              "word": "SWOON",
              "phonetic": "(swUn)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to faint; to become enraptured \nSWOON means to _faint_ or _lose consciousness_. Often SWOON is used about people in a state of sudden excitement or rapture. \n\"The young girls SWOONED when they saw their favorite singer come into the room.\" \n\"He felt faint and nearly SWOONED at the sight of so much beauty.\" \nSWOON is also a noun meaning a _faint_ or a _fainting fit_. \n\"She started to regain consciousness and come out of the SWOON.\""
            },
            "HALLOWED": {
              "word": "HALLOWED",
              "phonetic": "(hal'-Od)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "holy, sacred, blessed \nTo HALLOW something is to make it holy or to treat it as sacred. HALLOWED is the adjective from HALLOW and means _sacred_, _holy_. \n\"We walked solemnly past the HALLOWED ground of the graveyard.\" \n\"No one was allowed to touch the HALLOWED objects that had once belonged to the saint.\" \nNovember 1 is the Feast of All Saints, which used to be _All_ HALLOW. So October 31 is HALLOWEEN, which is short for _All_ HALLOW _Evening_. \nThe most popular mistake on the pretest for HALLOWED is _haunted_, due to the confusion caused by HALLOWEEN and the tales of ghosts and demons we associate with it. \nOther forms of the word: HALLOW, v."
            },
            "IMPLORE": {
              "word": "IMPLORE",
              "phonetic": "(im-plor')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "beg, beseech, request earnestly \nTo IMPLORE someone is to call upon him urgently for help, mercy, or the like. \n\"I IMPLORE you not to let us down when we need you the most.\" \n\"We IMPLORED the teacher not to give us any homework.\" \nTo IMPLORE something is to ask for it urgently. \n\"We IMPLORED his forgiveness.\" \n\"He IMPLORED her to help him, and finally she agreed.\" \nIMPLORE means almost exactly the same as _beg_, except that usually IMPLORE is a stronger word. \n\"I asked him to come. Then I begged him. Finally I IMPLORED him to come.\""
            },
            "PROCURE": {
              "word": "PROCURE",
              "phonetic": "(prO-KyUr'",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to get, obtain \nPROCURE means to _get_, especially as the result of effort and planning. \n\"We managed to PROCURE our supplies before they ran out.\" \n\"She was unable to PROCURE the necessary funds.\" \n\"He had to go to a hardware store ten miles away to PROCURE the special tool he wanted.\" \n_Protect_ and _save_ are often mistakenly chosen as the meaning of PROCURE, perhaps because of confusion with the word _secure_."
            },
            "ALLOT": {
              "word": "ALLOT",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩlot')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to assign, distribute by lot \n_Lots_ are objects like straws or pebbles used to decide something by chance. To _draw lots_, for example, is to choose pieces of paper or the like to decide who will do something, who wins something, etc. To ALLOT something is to distribute it or divide it up as if by lot. Usually the word doesn't suggest the actual drawing of lots. \n\"He took whatever he was ALLOTTED and didn't complain, even if it was much less than everyone else received.\" \n\"The ALLOTTED time for his speech had ended, but he refused to stop talking.\" \nThe noun from ALLOT is ALLOTMENT, which means \"a share or portion.\" \n\"His ALLOTMENT was only nine dollars.\" \n_Permit_ is often thought to be the meaning of ALLOT, probably because ALLOT looks so much like _allow_. \nOther forms of the word: ALLOTMENT, n."
            },
            "BLASPHEME": {
              "word": "BLASPHEME",
              "phonetic": "(blas-fEm')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to curse, speak irreverently \nBLASPHEME comes from a Greek word meaning to _speak evil_. In English BLASPHEME also means to _speak evil_, especially to talk in an irreverent or abusive way about God or something sacred. \n\"The church leaders said he had BLASPHEMED the name of God by his criticisms of religion.\" \nBLASPHEMY is an act of irreverence toward something sacred. \n\"The priest said the youths committed BLASPHEMY by writing swear words on the church doors.\" \nOther forms of the word: BLASPHEMOUS, adj. BLASPHEMY, n."
            },
            "MELEE": {
              "word": "MELEE",
              "phonetic": "(mA'-IA)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a confused struggle, free-for-all, brawl \nNote the pronunciation. MELEE is a French word, and has kept its French pronunciation. \nA MELEE is a confused struggle involving a crowd of people. \n\"A MELEE broke out among the fans at the football game.\" \n\"The police had to use tear gas to break up the MELEE.\" \nMELEE is also used about a confused or disorganized crowd in general, without the suggestion of fighting. \n\"He elbowed his way through the MELEE of people trying to finish their Christmas shopping.\""
            },
            "PLACATE": {
              "word": "PLACATE",
              "phonetic": "(plA'-kAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to soothe, pacify, appease, mollify \nTo PLACATE means to _soothe_ someone who is hostile or offended, usually by making concessions. \n\"In order to PLACATE his teacher Bob did extra homework that weekend.\" \n\"We tried to PLACATE Jane, but everything we did seemed to make her even angrier.\" \n\"He PLACATED the store owner by agreeing to return everything he had stolen.\""
            },
            "VEHEMENT": {
              "word": "VEHEMENT",
              "phonetic": "(vE'->mÔøΩnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "intense, strong, passionate, emphatic \nVEHEMENT means _intense_, _passionate_, _earnest_. \n\"The lawyer had some VEHEMENT objections to the judge's rulings.\" \nVEHEMENT is often used about the way people talk or act. \n\"His VEHEMENT tone left no doubt that he was quite upset about the matter.\" \n\"Jim VEHEMENTLY denied having taken the money.\" \nOther forms of the word: VEHEMENCE, n."
            },
            "STEADFAST": {
              "word": "STEADFAST",
              "phonetic": "(sted'-fast)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "faithful, loyal, firm, unswerving \nThe _stead_ part of STEADFAST comes from an old English word meaning _place_. A _homestead_, for example, is a place where you have your home. The _fast_ part does not mean _quick_ or _speedy_, but comes from another use of the word which means _firmly fixed_. You can see this use of _fast_ in the word _fasten_. So something which is STEADFAST is firmly fixed in place. Usually today STEADFAST is used about people, and means \"firmly fixed in one's beliefs or loyalties,\" _faithful_, _resolute_. \n\"He was a STEADFAST friend. He would always help you when you needed it most.\" \n\"She STEADFASTLY maintained her innocence despite all the proof that she was guilty.\""
            },
            "ALOOF": {
              "word": "ALOOF",
              "phonetic": "(>IUf')",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "distant, indifferent, remote \nALOOF is used about people who like to keep the feelings and opinions of others at a distance. ALOOF people stand apart and don't become involved in the affairs of others. Often the word suggests that this happens because these people feel superior to the rest of us. \n\"Mary always remained ALOOF from the other children, as if she thought their games were too silly for her.\" \n\"He was very warm and friendly with his family, but at work he seemed quite ALOOF.\""
            }
          },
          "id": 0,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "MANIFOLD attractions.",
                  "answers": [
                    "few",
                    "numerous",
                    "different",
                    "wonderful",
                    "obvious"
                  ],
                  "word": "MANIFOLD",
                  "correct": "numerous"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Obvious QUIRK.",
                  "answers": [
                    "intelligence",
                    "problem",
                    "peculiarity",
                    "grin",
                    "nervousness"
                  ],
                  "word": "QUIRK",
                  "correct": "peculiarity"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The performance was NONPAREIL.",
                  "answers": [
                    "well-received",
                    "unfortunate",
                    "unequaled",
                    "sloppy",
                    "free"
                  ],
                  "word": "NONPAREIL",
                  "correct": "unequaled"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Unexpected PANGS.",
                  "answers": [
                    "terrors",
                    "expressions",
                    "pains",
                    "delights",
                    "noises"
                  ],
                  "word": "PANG",
                  "correct": "pains"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Made them SWOON.",
                  "answers": [
                    "fall",
                    "sing",
                    "cry",
                    "wake up",
                    "faint"
                  ],
                  "word": "SWOON",
                  "correct": "faint"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HALLOWED places.",
                  "answers": [
                    "holy",
                    "awful",
                    "lovely",
                    "ancient",
                    "haunted"
                  ],
                  "word": "HALLOWED",
                  "correct": "holy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They IMPLORED us.",
                  "answers": [
                    "told",
                    "asked",
                    "begged",
                    "needed",
                    "hated"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPLORE",
                  "correct": "begged"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To PROCURE it.",
                  "answers": [
                    "pay for",
                    "protect",
                    "obtain",
                    "reach",
                    "save"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROCURE",
                  "correct": "obtain"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His ALLOTTED share.",
                  "answers": [
                    "expected",
                    "assigned",
                    "permitted",
                    "huge",
                    "stolen"
                  ],
                  "word": "ALLOT",
                  "correct": "assigned"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To BLASPHEME them.",
                  "answers": [
                    "hate",
                    "punish",
                    "curse",
                    "bless",
                    "envy"
                  ],
                  "word": "BLASPHEME",
                  "correct": "curse"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "During the MELEE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "rush hour",
                    "free-for-all",
                    "ambush",
                    "quiet evening",
                    "war"
                  ],
                  "word": "MELEE",
                  "correct": "free-for-all"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To PLACATE them.",
                  "answers": [
                    "love",
                    "show",
                    "ask",
                    "arouse",
                    "soothe"
                  ],
                  "word": "PLACATE",
                  "correct": "soothe"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VEHEMENT speech.",
                  "answers": [
                    "long",
                    "difficult",
                    "quiet",
                    "intense",
                    "well-meaning"
                  ],
                  "word": "VEHEMENT",
                  "correct": "intense"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "STEADFAST people.",
                  "answers": [
                    "quick",
                    "likable",
                    "dangerous",
                    "loyal",
                    "powerful"
                  ],
                  "word": "STEADFAST",
                  "correct": "loyal"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He seemed ALOOF.",
                  "answers": [
                    "friendly",
                    "lazy",
                    "odd",
                    "cruel",
                    "distant"
                  ],
                  "word": "ALOOF",
                  "correct": "distant"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Would most people want to buy a house that has MANIFOLD problems?",
                  "word": "MANIFOLD",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a QUIRK always a bad thing?",
                  "word": "QUIRK",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a NONPAREIL dancer be better than average?",
                  "word": "NONPAREIL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are PANGS usually pleasant?",
                  "word": "PANG",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a person in a SWOON fully awake?",
                  "word": "SWOON",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a church contain HALLOWED objects?",
                  "word": "HALLOWED",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a person who is drowning IMPLORE someone to save him?",
                  "word": "IMPLORE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do you have to go to a doctor to PROCURE a disease?",
                  "word": "PROCURE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can food be ALLOTTED?",
                  "word": "ALLOT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it BLASPHEMY to rob a bank?",
                  "word": "BLASPHEME",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a MELEE generally peaceful?",
                  "word": "MELEE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does an angry person like to PLACATE people?",
                  "word": "PLACATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a VEHEMENT tone indicate that a person is upset?",
                  "word": "VEHEMENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a STEADFAST friend desert you in time of trouble?",
                  "word": "STEADFAST",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are salesmen usually ALOOF?",
                  "word": "ALOOF",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "We went to see the MANIFOLD attractions and displays in the museum.",
                  "word": "MANIFOLD",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We were so accustomed to his QUIRKS that we were surprised when other people commented on how odd he was.",
                  "word": "QUIRK",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He was a singer NONPAREIL--perhaps the greatest that ever lived.",
                  "word": "NONPAREIL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He felt a few PANGS of fear as he walked into the haunted house.",
                  "word": "PANG",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She SWOONED with joy when the rock 'n' roll star threw her a flower.",
                  "word": "SWOON",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Seeing the ghost really HALLOWED them.",
                  "word": "HALLOWED",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The king IMPLORED them to join the fight against their common enemy.",
                  "word": "IMPLORE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We had to PROCURE a license before we were allowed to stay at the campgrounds.",
                  "word": "PROCURE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The teacher ALLOTTED us each five minutes to speak to the class.",
                  "word": "ALLOT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He BLASPHEMED all religions, calling them the work of the devil.",
                  "word": "BLASPHEME",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Each afternoon there was a MELEE at the bus stop as all the school children tried to get on at once.",
                  "word": "MELEE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The king refused to do anything to PLACATE the angry mob.",
                  "word": "PLACATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The leaf drifted VEHEMENTLY down to the ground.",
                  "word": "VEHEMENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The STEADFAST horse raced around the track in record time.",
                  "word": "STEADFAST",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The rich boy kept ALOOF from all the other children at school.",
                  "word": "ALOOF",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "MANIFOLD",
                  "answers": [
                    "many",
                    "complicated",
                    "varied"
                  ],
                  "word": "MANIFOLD",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "QUIRK",
                  "answers": [
                    "oddity",
                    "strangeness",
                    "pleasantness"
                  ],
                  "word": "QUIRK",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "NONPAREIL",
                  "answers": [
                    "good",
                    "marvelous",
                    "perfect"
                  ],
                  "word": "NONPAREIL",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PANG",
                  "answers": [
                    "ache",
                    "noise",
                    "sorrow"
                  ],
                  "word": "PANG",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SWOON",
                  "answers": [
                    "fainting",
                    "unconscious",
                    "sleepy"
                  ],
                  "word": "SWOON",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HALLOWED",
                  "answers": [
                    "sacred",
                    "beautiful",
                    "divine"
                  ],
                  "word": "HALLOWED",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IMPLORE",
                  "answers": [
                    "plead",
                    "beg",
                    "need"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPLORE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PROCURE",
                  "answers": [
                    "get",
                    "show",
                    "buy"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROCURE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ALLOT",
                  "answers": [
                    "divide",
                    "distribute",
                    "desire"
                  ],
                  "word": "ALLOT",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BLASPHEME",
                  "answers": [
                    "insult",
                    "refuse",
                    "swear"
                  ],
                  "word": "BLASPHEME",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MELEE",
                  "answers": [
                    "joy",
                    "crowd",
                    "struggle"
                  ],
                  "word": "MELEE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PLACATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "trick",
                    "please",
                    "calm"
                  ],
                  "word": "PLACATE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VEHEMENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "passionate",
                    "enthusiastic",
                    "vain"
                  ],
                  "word": "VEHEMENT",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "STEADFAST",
                  "answers": [
                    "generous",
                    "faithful",
                    "firm"
                  ],
                  "word": "STEADFAST",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ALOOF",
                  "answers": [
                    "talkative",
                    "superior",
                    "indifferent"
                  ],
                  "word": "ALOOF",
                  "correct": "0"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "6.5",
          "definitions": {
            "BENEVOLENT": {
              "word": "BENEVOLENT",
              "phonetic": "(bÔøΩ-nev'-ÔøΩlÔøΩnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "kindly, good, humane \nThe _bene_ part of BENEVOLENT means _good_ or _well_; it is also used in words like _benefit_ and _benefactor_. The _vol_ part of the word means _wish_. A BENEVOLENT person wishes other people well; he wants to make other people happy, and therefore is generous and kindly. See _-ant_ under Suffixes. \n\"The BENEVOLENT woman worked as a volunteer in a hospital and gave thousands of dollars to charity.\" \nBENEVOLENT is also used about people's actions and attitudes, and about places that exist to do good works. \n\"The teacher took a BENEVOLENT attitude toward her students, and tried to help them in every way she could.\" \n\"The BENEVOLENT institution provides toys for poor children at Christmastime.\" \nOther forms of the word: BENEVOLENCE, n."
            },
            "GUISE": {
              "word": "GUISE",
              "phonetic": "(glz)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "outward appearance, aspect, semblance \nThe GUISE of something is its outward appearance, the way it looks. The word may often suggest that this appearance is false or misleading. \n\"The prince walked through the city streets in the GUISE of a poor beggar.\" \n\"Under the GUISE of friendship he offered to help them find the money; he really wanted to keep it all for himself.\" \nTo DISGUISE something is to change its appearance or GUISE. \n\"The thief got into the house by DISGUISING himself as a mailman.\" \nOther forms of the word: DISGUISE, n., v."
            },
            "CONTRIVE": {
              "word": "CONTRIVE",
              "phonetic": "(kÔøΩn-trlv')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to invent, design, concoct; to manage or devise a way To CONTRIVE something or to CONTRIVE to do it is to find a way of doing it. \nThe word suggests the use of cleverness in achieving something that may be rather difficult. \n\"She CONTRIVED a device that would open locked doors without a key.\" \n\"He CONTRIVED to get both the enemies into one room together to discuss their differences.\" \n\"The author CONTRIVED a happy ending for his novel.\" \nThe adjective CONTRIVED is used about things that show too clearly that they are planned and artificial. \n\"His remarks were clever but rather CONTRIVED, as if he had rehearsed them all beforehand.\" \nOther forms of the word: CONTRIVANCE, n. CONTRIVED, adj."
            },
            "DEPICT": {
              "word": "DEPICT",
              "phonetic": "(di-pikt')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to describe, represent \nDEPICT is related to the word _picture_. To DEPICT something is to draw it or describe it, to make a picture of it. Something can be DEPICTED in a real picture, in words, on stage, etc. \n\"The painting DEPICTS the king as a young man.\" \n\"He is DEPICTED in the novel as a mean, vicious scoundrel.\" \n\"The actress tried to DEPICT the emotions of the character she was playing.\" \n\"The writer DEPICTED the horrors of war.\" \nOther forms of the word: DEPICTION, n."
            },
            "JAUNDICED": {
              "word": "JAUNDICED",
              "phonetic": "(jon'-dist)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "yellowish; hostile, prejudiced, jealous \nJAUNDICE is a disease which turns the skin yellow. JAUNDICED skin or a JAUNDICED appearance, therefore, looks as if it has been affected by JAUNDICE: it is yellow or yellowish. \nJAUNDICE can affect the vision, and people with JAUNDICE sometimes see things as being yellow. JAUNDICED has therefore come to be used about people who see things as being worse than they are, because of envy, suspicion, prejudice, and so on. \n\"He looked with a somewhat JAUNDICED eye on their plan to hitchhike across the country\"--that is, he wasn't very much in favor of it, and thought it would turn out badly. \nOther forms of the word: JAUNDICE, n."
            },
            "PENSIVE": {
              "word": "PENSIVE",
              "phonetic": "(pen'-siv)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "thoughtful, deep in thought \nSomeone who is PENSIVE is deep in thought. Often PENSIVE suggests a dreamy kind of thoughtfulness, where a person isn't reasoning a problem through but is simply in a reflective, almost sad mood. \n\"She sat there for a long time with a PENSIVE, far-away look on her face.\" \n\"Jim became rather PENSIVE whenever he remembered those sad incidents in his life.\""
            },
            "SQUANDER": {
              "word": "SQUANDER",
              "phonetic": "(skwon'-dÔøΩr)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to waste, spend carelessly, throw away foolishly \nTo SQUANDER something is to waste it, to use it up extravagantly and carelessly. The word is used especially about time and money. People who are careful about saving money do not SQUANDER it. \n\"He SQUANDERED his pay on gambling.\" \n\"When the day of the test came, she was sorry that she had SQUANDERED all of her time watching television.\" \n\"She SQUANDERED her life on foolish pleasures.\""
            },
            "ULTERIOR": {
              "word": "ULTERIOR",
              "phonetic": "(uhl-tEr'-E-ÔøΩr)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "hidden, not obvious, unseen \nULTERIOR comes from a Latin word that means _lying beyond_, _lying further off_. In English the word usually has the sense \"being beyond what is seen or admitted\" and suggests that something is purposely being kept concealed. The word is generally used about purposes, motives, and the like. \n\"Not a shadow of his ULTERIOR purpose was visible in his actions.\" \n\"He pretended to be friendly toward the others, but I knew that he had an ULTERIOR motive for it.\" \n\"The child was so open and innocent that one could not suspect him of having ULTERIOR thoughts.\""
            },
            "AMASS": {
              "word": "AMASS",
              "phonetic": "(Q-mas')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to gather, accumulate, pile up \nTo AMASS is to pile up into a mass, to heap up or accumulate. The word is usually, although not always, used about something that is valuable. \n\"He AMASSED huge amounts of gold.\" \n\"I AMASSED a great deal of knowledge during high school.\" \n\"Jim AMASSED thousands of bottle caps over the years.\" \n\"Jane AMASSED a fortune by buying and selling stocks.\""
            },
            "KINDRED": {
              "word": "KINDRED",
              "phonetic": "(kin'-drid)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "related, similar \nYour KIN are your family, your relatives. \n\"Her KIN stood by her when everyone else had deserted her.\" \nKINDRED, as a noun, is another word for KIN. \n\"All his KINDRED came to visit him when he was ill.\" \nAs an adjective, KINDRED means \"having a common source,\" _related_. \n\"English and German are KINDRED languages.\" \nKINDRED also means \"having much in common,\" _similar_. \n\"They were KINDRED spirits; they had the same opinions about almost everything.\""
            },
            "ORDINANCE": {
              "word": "ORDINANCE",
              "phonetic": "(or'-dQ-nÔøΩns)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "an order, law, rule \nORDINANCE is related to the word order. An ORDINANCE is a law or rule, usually one issued by a city or town. \n\"The city council passed an ORDINANCE forbidding smoking in public places.\" \n\"There is a local ORDINANCE that makes littering punishable by a fifty dollar fine.\""
            },
            "KNOLL": {
              "word": "KNOLL",
              "phonetic": "(nOI)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a small hill, mound \nA KNOLL is a small hill, usually with a rounded shape. \n\"The land was flat except for a few gentle KNOLLS in the distance.\" \n\"It took us only a minute or two to climb to the top of the KNOLL.\""
            },
            "ORIFICE": {
              "word": "ORIFICE",
              "phonetic": "(or'-ÔøΩfis)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "an opening, mouth, aperture \nORIFICE comes from the Latin word for _mouth_, also the source of the word _oral_. ORIFICE is used for any outer opening or mouth of something. \n\"The ORIFICE of the tube had become blocked up with dirt.\" \n\"The creature had a small ORIFICE through which it took in food and air.\""
            },
            "QUASH": {
              "word": "QUASH",
              "phonetic": "(kwosh)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to put an end to, beat down, crush \nQUASH is related to the word _squash_, and both have about the same meaning: to _beat down_, _crush_. QUASH, however, is used more about rebellions, chances, hopes, rumors, and the like, than about physical objects. \n\"The army QUASHED the rebellion easily.\" \n\"The airplane strike QUASHED our hopes of getting home for Christmas.\""
            },
            "SLOVENLY": {
              "word": "SLOVENLY",
              "phonetic": "(sluhv'-ÔøΩn-lE)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "untidy, sloppy, careless \nA SLOVEN is a person who always dresses, acts, or works in a messy, slipshod manner. SLOVENLY is the adjective from SLOVEN. (It is an adjective even though it ends in _-ly_.) A person is SLOVENLY if he is sloppy or careless about his appearance or work. \n\"She is so SLOVENLY. She looks as though she sleeps in her clothes.\" \n\"Jim's SLOVENLY appearance makes a very bad impression on people.\" \nSLOVENLY is also used about people's activities and products. \n\"It was a SLOVENLY report, full of mistakes and erasures.\" \n\"The supervisor criticized the mechanic's SLOVENLY workmanship.\" \nOther forms of the word: SLOVEN, n."
            }
          },
          "id": 1,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "The BENEVOLENT woman.",
                  "answers": [
                    "lucky",
                    "wealthy",
                    "kindly",
                    "holy",
                    "cruel"
                  ],
                  "word": "BENEVOLENT",
                  "correct": "kindly"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The GUISE of friendship.",
                  "answers": [
                    "promise",
                    "appearance",
                    "reality",
                    "beauty",
                    "hope"
                  ],
                  "word": "GUISE",
                  "correct": "appearance"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To CONTRIVE a system.",
                  "answers": [
                    "learn",
                    "consider",
                    "improve",
                    "invent",
                    "oppose"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONTRIVE",
                  "correct": "invent"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "How did they DEPICT him?",
                  "answers": [
                    "like",
                    "see",
                    "lose",
                    "choose",
                    "describe"
                  ],
                  "word": "DEPICT",
                  "correct": "describe"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "JAUNDICED appearance.",
                  "answers": [
                    "healthy",
                    "saddened",
                    "yellowish",
                    "grayish",
                    "frightened"
                  ],
                  "word": "JAUNDICED",
                  "correct": "yellowish"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She looks PENSIVE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "nervous",
                    "thoughtful",
                    "happy",
                    "angry",
                    "wealthy"
                  ],
                  "word": "PENSIVE",
                  "correct": "thoughtful"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He SQUANDERS his money.",
                  "answers": [
                    "misplaces",
                    "saves",
                    "wastes",
                    "worries about",
                    "hides"
                  ],
                  "word": " SQUANDER",
                  "correct": "wastes"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ULTERIOR motives.",
                  "answers": [
                    "pressing",
                    "worse",
                    "obvious",
                    "hidden",
                    "dishonest"
                  ],
                  "word": "ULTERIOR",
                  "correct": "hidden"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "AMASS a treasure.",
                  "answers": [
                    "give away",
                    "find",
                    "lose",
                    "gather",
                    "pray for"
                  ],
                  "word": "AMASS",
                  "correct": "gather"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "KINDRED tribes.",
                  "answers": [
                    "related",
                    "happy",
                    "friendly",
                    "far-off",
                    "local"
                  ],
                  "word": "KINDRED",
                  "correct": "related"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "New ORDINANCES.",
                  "answers": [
                    "customs",
                    "morals",
                    "orders",
                    "sheriffs",
                    "privileges"
                  ],
                  "word": "ORDINANCE",
                  "correct": "orders"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Reached the KNOLL.",
                  "answers": [
                    "rock",
                    "small hill",
                    "cave",
                    "top",
                    "valley"
                  ],
                  "word": "KNOLL",
                  "correct": "small hill"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Examined the ORIFICE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "cave",
                    "tunnel",
                    "wall",
                    "tooth",
                    "opening"
                  ],
                  "word": "ORIFICE",
                  "correct": "opening"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "QUASH the rebellion.",
                  "answers": [
                    "fear",
                    "stir up",
                    "laugh at",
                    "oppose",
                    "crush"
                  ],
                  "word": "QUASH",
                  "correct": "crush"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SLOVENLY people.",
                  "answers": [
                    "hateful",
                    "poor",
                    "careful",
                    "untidy",
                    "wonderful"
                  ],
                  "word": "SLOVENLY",
                  "correct": "untidy"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a BENEVOLENT person be stingy?",
                  "word": "BENEVOLENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would an actor appear in different GUISES on stage?",
                  "word": "GUISE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Did Thomas Edison CONTRIVE things?",
                  "word": "CONTRIVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a person be DEPICTED in a short story?",
                  "word": "DEPICT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are cheerful people usually JAUNDICED?",
                  "word": "JAUNDICED",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would someone who is in a PENSIVE mood be very talkative?",
                  "word": "PENSIVE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do people become rich by SQUANDERING their money?",
                  "word": "SQUANDER",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could people with ULTERIOR motives be called sneaky?",
                  "word": "ULTERIOR",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can you AMASS facts?",
                  "word": "AMASS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are apes and gorillas KINDRED animals?",
                  "word": "KINDRED",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are you supposed to obey an ORDINANCE?",
                  "word": "ORDINANCE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it difficult to reach the top of a KNOLL?",
                  "word": "KNOLL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can an ORIFICE be very small?",
                  "word": "ORIFICE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "If you QUASH a rumor, would you confirm that it is true?",
                  "word": "QUASH",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a SLOVENLY person make a good waiter?",
                  "word": "SLOVENLY",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "With a BENEVOLENT sneer he laughed at her misfortune.",
                  "word": "BENEVOLENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "In the GUISE of a policeman the spy could go anywhere he wanted in the building.",
                  "word": "GUISE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She CONTRIVED to get her husband home in time for the surprise party.",
                  "word": "CONTRIVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She tried to DEPICT everyday life in ancient Russia for them.",
                  "word": "DEPICT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He had a JAUNDICED view of government; he thought every politician was a crook.",
                  "word": "JAUNDICED",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Whenever she was in a PENSIVE mood she would think of all the exciting things she was missing in life.",
                  "word": "PENSIVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Bill SQUANDERED his artistic talent on drawing cartoons for advertisements.",
                  "word": "SQUANDERED",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They examined the ULTERIOR of the house for any signs of water damage.",
                  "word": "ULTERIOR",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She AMASSED a large collection of fine paintings.",
                  "word": "AMASSED",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Everyone was so KINDRED to me that I forgot all about my problems.",
                  "word": "KINDRED",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The ORDINANCE in Bill's family was to have Thanksgiving dinner early in the afternoon.",
                  "word": "ORDINANCE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We picnicked at the foot of a small KNOLL.",
                  "word": "KNOLL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Mrs. Smith went to work at the ORIFICE every day.",
                  "word": "ORIFICE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The disabled airplane fell down and QUASHED the water.",
                  "word": "QUASHED",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We were shocked by his SLOVENLY appearance; he just didn't seem to care how he looked.",
                  "word": "SLOVENLY",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "BENEVOLENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "beautiful",
                    "charitable",
                    "generous"
                  ],
                  "word": "BENEVOLENT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "GUISE",
                  "answers": [
                    "resemblance",
                    "interference",
                    "appearance"
                  ],
                  "word": "GUISE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CONTRIVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "devise",
                    "defeat",
                    "design"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONTRIVE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DEPICT",
                  "answers": [
                    "represent",
                    "improve",
                    "paint"
                  ],
                  "word": "DEPICT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "JAUNDICED",
                  "answers": [
                    "suspicious",
                    "yellow",
                    "uncertain"
                  ],
                  "word": "JAUNDICED",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PENSIVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "active",
                    "reflective",
                    "meditative"
                  ],
                  "word": "PENSIVE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SQUANDER",
                  "answers": [
                    "spend",
                    "forget",
                    "waste"
                  ],
                  "word": "SQUANDER",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ULTERIOR",
                  "answers": [
                    "secret",
                    "unknown",
                    "dangerous"
                  ],
                  "word": "ULTERIOR",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "AMASS",
                  "answers": [
                    "choose",
                    "accumulate",
                    "collect"
                  ],
                  "word": "AMASS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "KINDRED",
                  "answers": [
                    "similar",
                    "related",
                    "identical"
                  ],
                  "word": "KINDRED",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ORDINANCE",
                  "answers": [
                    "law",
                    "suggestion",
                    "regulation"
                  ],
                  "word": "ORDINANCE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "KNOLL",
                  "answers": [
                    "mound",
                    "plain",
                    "hill"
                  ],
                  "word": "KNOLL",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ORIFICE",
                  "answers": [
                    "hole",
                    "corridor",
                    "mouth"
                  ],
                  "word": "ORIFICE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "QUASH",
                  "answers": [
                    "put down",
                    "wear out",
                    "destroy"
                  ],
                  "word": "QUASH",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SLOVENLY",
                  "answers": [
                    "dangerous",
                    "messy",
                    "slipshod"
                  ],
                  "word": "SLOVENLY",
                  "correct": "0"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "6.6",
          "definitions": {
            "FACADE": {
              "word": "FACADE",
              "phonetic": "(fÔøΩsahd')",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "the front (of a building); a false appearance \nNote the pronunciation. The _c_ is soft. \nThe FACADE of a building is its front, the part which faces the street and which most people see. \n\"The bomb damaged the FACADE of the hotel, but the people inside were unharmed.\" \nSometimes, to make a small building appear to be bigger than it actually is, the FACADE is extended above the building's top floor. Such a FACADE is called a _false front_. \n\"The FACADE of the building is two stories high, but the building has only one floor.\" \nFrom this meaning FACADE has come to be used for any outward appearance, especially one which is false or misleading. \n\"She looked calm, but this was just a FACADE; she was really very angry.\" \n\"Their apparent wealth was all a FACADE; in fact, they could barely afford the clothes they wore.\" \nUsage: FACADE is also sometimes spelled _façade_."
            },
            "ADULTERATE": {
              "word": "ADULTERATE",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩduhl'-t:>r-At)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to make impure, corrupt, pollute \nADULTERATE has nothing to do with the word _adult_. To ADULTERATE something is to make it less pure, usually by adding a substance that is of poorer quality. The word is used especially about foods and drugs. \n\"He claimed the hamburger had been ADULTERATED by the addition of harmful chemicals.\" \nThe word is also sometimes used in a general sense. \n\"Her happiness was ADULTERATED by the continuing suspicion that it was all about to end.\" \nThe word UNADULTERATED means _pure_ or _sheer_. \n\"Everything he says is UNADULTERATED nonsense\"--that is, it is complete and total nonsense. \nOther forms of the word: ADULTERATION, n. UNADULTERATED, adj."
            },
            "CLEAVE": {
              "word": "CLEAVE",
              "phonetic": "(klEv)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to split, tear, cut apart \nTo CLEAVE something is to split it apart, especially with a cutting blow--for example, from an ax. \n\"He could CLEAVE the log with one mighty swing of his ax.\" \n\"The force of the explosion CLEAVED the boulder in two.\" \nCLEAVE can also he used about the thing being cut. \n\"This kind of wood CLEAVES easily.\" \nIn a slightly different sense, the word can also mean \"to make way for, by (or as if by) cutting.\" \n\"They CLEAVED a path through the jungle.\" \nA CLEAVER is a heavy instrument used by butchers to cut up animals. \nOther forms of the word: CLEAVER, n. \nUsage: CLEAVE is a rather formal word, used more in print than in speech. The past tense of CLEAVE can be CLEAVED, CLOVE, or CLEFT. Interestingly, CLEAVE has a second meaning that is almost the opposite of the meaning given above; it means \"to cling to or be firmly attached to,\" as in \"The wet uniforms cleaved to their bodies.\""
            },
            "ENUMERATE": {
              "word": "ENUMERATE",
              "phonetic": "i-nU'-mÔøΩr-At)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to count, list, name one by one \nENUMERATE comes from the same Latin source as _number_, _numeral_, _numerous_, and other words having to do with numbers and counting. ENUMERATE can mean simply to _count_, but it usually has the sense of \"counting off\" or listing items one after another. \n\"He began to ENUMERATE the reasons why we shouldn't go.\" \n\"We ENUMERATED the qualities we thought the new employee should have.\" \nIn most cases it is better to use the simpler words _count_ and _list_, unless the sense is specifically to count off one after another. \nOther forms of the word: ENUMERATION, n."
            },
            "AFFIX": {
              "word": "AFFIX",
              "phonetic": "(:;,..fiks')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to attach, fasten, stick firmly in place \nTo AFFIX something is to attach it to something else. \n\"You must AFFIX a stamp to that letter or else the post office won't deliver it.\" \nThe AFFIXING doesn't have to be a physical act. \n\"The teacher AFFIXED a severe penalty to cheating on the test.\" \n\"He AFFIXED great importance to the professor's remarks.\" \nAFFIX is often used about adding your signature to something. \n\"He had to AFFIX his signature to the bottom of the document to make it legal.\" \nAFFIX comes from the same source as the word _fix_. AFFIX has nothing to do with _fix_ in the sense of _repair_. Fix, though, can mean \"to put firmly in place\" as in the phrase \"to _fix_ in your memory.\" The two words in this sense have close to the same meaning."
            },
            "PRECIPICE": {
              "word": "PRECIPICE",
              "phonetic": "(pres'-:;,..pis)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a steep cliff \nA PRECIPICE is a very steep cliff, one that has almost a vertical face to it. \n\"Everyone was afraid to go very near the edge of the PRECIPICE.\" \n\"The mountain climbers decided it would be almost impossible to reach the top of the PRECIPICE.\" \nSometimes PRECIPICE is used in a general sense for the brink of any kind of disaster. \n\"The nation now stands on the PRECIPICE of a severe economic depression.\" \nIn the Pretest, many people choose _valley_ as the meaning of PRECIPICE. A PRECIPICE is a cliff which might lead down into a _valley_, but it is not the _valley_ itself."
            },
            "AGAPE": {
              "word": "AGAPE",
              "phonetic": "(:;,..gAp')",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "wide open, gaping; in a state of wonder. \nAGAPE is related to the words _gap_ and _gape_. The word means _wide open_. It is usually used about a person's mouth, which might be open because of wonder, surprise, a yawn, or the like. \n\"His mouth was AGAPE when he saw who had walked in the door.\" \n\"The crowd was AGAPE at the astounding feats of the acrobats.\" \nMany people choose _horrified_ as the synonym for AGAPE. A person's mouth may be AGAPE because of horror, but the word means _wide open_, not _horrified_. \nUsage: AGAPE always comes after the noun it modifies."
            },
            "SUBMISSIVE": {
              "word": "SUBMISSIVE",
              "phonetic": "(suhb-mis'-iv)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "tame, yielding, compliant, docile \nSUBMISSIVE is an adjective from SUBMIT. See _-ive_ under Suffixes. One meaning of SUBMIT is \"to yield to someone else's authority, to surrender.\" \n\"When the police arrived, the burglar submitted without a struggle.\" \nSomeone who is SUBMISSIVE is inclined to SUBMIT, to yield to power or authority. \n\"They were very SUBMISSIVE children. They would obey anyone who gave them an order.\" \n\"Why are you so SUBMISSIVE? You shouldn't do everything he tells you to do.\" \nOther forms of the word: SUBMIT, v. SUBMISSION, n."
            },
            "ANTAGONISM": {
              "word": "ANTAGONISM",
              "phonetic": "(an-tag'-:;,..nizm)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "hostility, opposition, enmity \nANTAGONISM is active opposition, between people or groups, for example, who are unfriendly or in conflict. The word usually suggests a basic dislike which can easily be stirred up into actual fighting. \n\"The natives felt an ANTAGONISM toward the tourists who swarmed into their town every summer.\" \n\"Jim's mother tried to end the ANTAGONISM between his brother and him.\" \nMany people pick _suffering_ as the meaning of ANTAGONISM, probably because they see the word _agony_ in ANTAGONISM. Actually, both words come from a Greek word meaning _struggle_, but they have developed very different meanings. \nOther forms of the word: ANTAGONIST, n. ANTAGONISTIC, adj. ANTAGONIZE, v."
            },
            "APPENDAGE": {
              "word": "APPENDAGE",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩpen'-dij)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "an attachment, accessory, addition \nThe _pend_ part of APPENDAGE comes from the Latin word for _hang_, also the source of English words like _pendant_ and _pendulum_. An APPENDAGE is something that is attached or added on to something else so that it is part of it. See _ad-_ under Prefixes. In biology, arms, legs, tails, and fins are appendages. In general use, however, the word usually suggests that this added-on part is not very important or essential. \n\"The shed was merely a small APPENDAGE of the large house.\" \n\"The fancy knobs and dials on the machine were useless APPENDAGES; they were just there to make it look impressive.\" \nTo APPEND something is to add or attach it to something else. \n\"A bibliography was APPENDED to the book before they published the second edition.\""
            },
            "DOMICILE": {
              "word": "DOMICILE",
              "phonetic": "(dom'-ÔøΩs11",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a home, dwelling place, residence \nA DOMICILE is a home or dwelling place. The word is especially used to mean \"a person's legal residence\"--that is, where he can be considered to live for voting or tax purposes. \n\"The judge ruled that her legal DOMICILE was in New York State.\" \n\"He decided to establish his DOMICILE in Cleveland\"--in other words, he decided to live there. \nDOMICILE is also a verb. To DOMICILE is to reside or dwell. \n\"They DOMICILED in the south of the country during the winter months.\""
            },
            "GUFFAW": {
              "word": "GUFFAW",
              "phonetic": "(gÔøΩfo')",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a noisy burst of laughter \nA GUFFAW is a loud, coarse laugh. Originally the word was probably just an imitation of the sound of this kind of laugh. \n\"The comedian's act certainly didn't produce any GUFFAWS in the audience; all we could hear were a few scattered giggles.\" \nGUFFAW can also be used as a verb. \n\"The audience GUFFAWED when the villain slipped on a banana peel.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer on the Pretest is _bitter cry_, which is opposite in meaning to GUFFAW."
            },
            "STRATA": {
              "word": "STRATA",
              "phonetic": "(strA'-tÔøΩ",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "layers, levels \nSTRATA is the plural of STRATUM. A STRATUM is an even layer of something. STRATA are several of these layers, one on top of the other. The word is most often used about layers of rocks, but it is also used about other things like social classes. \n\"Geologists can study the history of the Earth by examining the STRATA of rock formations.\" \n\"Various STRATA of society were represented on the committee.\""
            },
            "BUFFOON": {
              "word": "BUFFOON",
              "phonetic": "(bÔøΩfUn')",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a clown, jester \nA BUFFOON is a _clown_, someone who says or does foolish things to entertain people. \n\"The BUFFOON stood on his head and barked like a dog to amuse the king.\" \nIn general, BUFFOON is an insulting term for any extremely stupid or foolish person. \n\"He called his opponent a BUFFOON and said he was too stupid to be president.\" \nBUFFOONERY is clown-like behavior. \n\"Stop all this BUFFOONERY and act your age.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer is _monkey_, probably because of confusion with _baboon_, which is a kind of _monkey_. \nOther forms of the word: BUFFOONERY, n."
            },
            "ADVOCATE": {
              "word": "ADVOCATE",
              "phonetic": "(ad'-vÔøΩ-kAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to recommend, support \nTo ADVOCATE something is to speak or write publicly in favor of it. \n\"She ADVOCATES a shorter school day and longer vacations for students.\" \n\"Everyone at the meeting seemed to ADVOCATE a different way of solving the problem.\" \n\"No one on the committee ADVOCATED doing away with taxes entirely.\" \nADVOCATE is also a noun. An ADVOCATE is someone who defends or pleads for a cause or a person. \n\"The plan's strongest ADVOCATES are the ones who will gain the most from it.\" \nOther forms of the word: ADVOCACY, n."
            }
          },
          "id": 2,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "The FACADE of the building.",
                  "answers": [
                    "basement",
                    "rear",
                    "front",
                    "structure",
                    "first floor"
                  ],
                  "word": "FACADE",
                  "correct": "front"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "It had been ADULTERATED.",
                  "answers": [
                    "substituted",
                    "made impure",
                    "made stronger",
                    "shaken up",
                    "aged"
                  ],
                  "word": "ADULTERATE",
                  "correct": "made impure"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CLEAVE it.",
                  "answers": [
                    "turn",
                    "smooth",
                    "bend",
                    "crack",
                    "split"
                  ],
                  "word": "CLEAVE",
                  "correct": "split"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He ENUMERATED the problems.",
                  "answers": [
                    "knew about",
                    "found",
                    "listed",
                    "added to",
                    "talked about"
                  ],
                  "word": "ENUMERATE",
                  "correct": "listed"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Finally AFFIXED.",
                  "answers": [
                    "fastened",
                    "repaired",
                    "removed",
                    "finished",
                    "improved"
                  ],
                  "word": "AFFIX",
                  "correct": "fastened"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "See the PRECIPICE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "valley",
                    "cliff",
                    "pathway",
                    "roof",
                    "stairway"
                  ],
                  "word": "PRECIPICE",
                  "correct": "cliff"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Stood AGAPE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "laughing",
                    "wide open",
                    "horrified",
                    "at ease",
                    "firm"
                  ],
                  "word": "AGAPE",
                  "correct": "wide open"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They were SUBMISSIVE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "determined",
                    "friendly",
                    "tame",
                    "silent",
                    "wild"
                  ],
                  "word": "SUBMISSIVE",
                  "correct": "tame"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Their ANTAGONISM.",
                  "answers": [
                    "fear",
                    "suffering",
                    "attraction",
                    "contest",
                    "hostility"
                  ],
                  "word": "ANTAGONISM",
                  "correct": "hostility"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Obvious APPENDAGE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "rubbish",
                    "conclusion",
                    "class",
                    "attachment",
                    "treatment"
                  ],
                  "word": "APPENDAGE",
                  "correct": "attachment"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Where is his DOMICILE?",
                  "answers": [
                    "servant",
                    "office",
                    "home",
                    "birthplace",
                    "weapon"
                  ],
                  "word": "DOMICILE",
                  "correct": "home"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Heard the GUFFAW.",
                  "answers": [
                    "noisy laugh",
                    "shout",
                    "short answer",
                    "bitter cry",
                    "sneeze"
                  ],
                  "word": "GUFFAW",
                  "correct": "noisy laugh"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Uncovered STRATA.",
                  "answers": [
                    "layers",
                    "walls",
                    "information",
                    "depths",
                    "scratches"
                  ],
                  "word": "STRATA",
                  "correct": "layers"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Watch the BUFFOON.",
                  "answers": [
                    "monkey",
                    "hurricane",
                    "juggler",
                    "clown",
                    "singer"
                  ],
                  "word": "BUFFOON",
                  "correct": "clown"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To ADVOCATE a plan.",
                  "answers": [
                    "discuss",
                    "recommend",
                    "abandon",
                    "accept",
                    "criticize"
                  ],
                  "word": "ADVOCATE",
                  "correct": "recommend"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Is the FACADE of a building on the outside?",
                  "word": "FAÇADE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is food better after it has been ADULTERATED?",
                  "word": "ADULTERATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can an ax CLEAVE a piece of wood?",
                  "word": "CLEAVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "If you ENUMERATE the difficulties of a plan, do you cause more of them?",
                  "word": "ENUMERATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could glue be used to AFFIX a poster to a wall?",
                  "word": "AFFIX",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it dangerous to be on the edge of a PRECIPICE?",
                  "word": "PRECIPICE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a person's mouth be AGAPE while he is yawning?",
                  "word": "AGAPE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a SUBMISSIVE person be easy to get along with?",
                  "word": "SUBMISSIVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do close friends feel a strong ANTAGONISM toward each other?",
                  "word": "ANTAGONISM",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are APPENDAGES usually very necessary?",
                  "word": "APPENDAGE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "If you permanently moved to another state, could you keep the same DOMICILE?",
                  "word": "DOMICILE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would people GUFFAW at a funeral?",
                  "word": "GUFFAW",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do STRATA lie beside one another?",
                  "word": "STRATA",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are BUFFOONS supposed to be funny?",
                  "word": "BUFFOON",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a salesman ADVOCATE buying his product?",
                  "word": "ADVOCATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "His FACADE of indifference disguised his concern.",
                  "word": "FACADE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "That television show is UNADULTERATED trash; it's the worst program I've ever seen.",
                  "word": "ADULTERATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She CLEAVED the windows with a bucket of water and a sponge.",
                  "word": "CLEAVE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She quickly ENUMERATED the advantages her idea had over all the rest.",
                  "word": "ENUMERATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "John would have to AFFIX the car whenever it broke down.",
                  "word": "AFFIX",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The plane was forced to land in a deep PRECIPICE.",
                  "word": "PRECIPICE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The boys stood AGAPE when they saw the ghost suddenly appear.",
                  "word": "AGAPE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Some teachers are too SUBMISSIVE; they won't let you get away with anything.",
                  "word": "SUBMISSIVE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He lay on the ground in ANTAGONISM after he had been wounded.",
                  "word": "ANTAGONISM",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Jim wanted to be an important part of the team, but the coach made him feel as if he were just an APPENDAGE.",
                  "word": "APPENDAGE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He worked in Los Angeles, but his DOMICILE was outside the city.",
                  "word": "DOMICILE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His joke brought a loud GUFFAW from everyone.",
                  "word": "GUFFAW",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The highest STRATUM of their society sets the fashion for the other classes.",
                  "word": "STRATA",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He called us a bunch of BUFFOONS for acting so silly during the class.",
                  "word": "BUFFOON",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The senator was a strong ADVOCATE of the Equal Rights Amendment.",
                  "word": "ADVOCATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "FACADE",
                  "answers": [
                    "show",
                    "appearance",
                    "shine"
                  ],
                  "word": "FACADE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ADULTERATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "worsen",
                    "corrupt",
                    "remove"
                  ],
                  "word": "ADULTERATE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CLEAVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "separate",
                    "rip",
                    "ruin"
                  ],
                  "word": "CLEAVE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ENUMERATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "count",
                    "list",
                    "increase"
                  ],
                  "word": "ENUMERATE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "AFFIX",
                  "answers": [
                    "pile",
                    "connect",
                    "stick"
                  ],
                  "word": "AFFIX",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PRECIPICE",
                  "answers": [
                    "side",
                    "cliff",
                    "brink"
                  ],
                  "word": "PRECIPICE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "AGAPE",
                  "answers": [
                    "ajar",
                    "open",
                    "huge"
                  ],
                  "word": "AGAPE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SUBMISSIVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "yielding",
                    "tame",
                    "thoughtful"
                  ],
                  "word": "SUBMISSIVE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ANTAGONISM",
                  "answers": [
                    "fear",
                    "opposition",
                    "conflict"
                  ],
                  "word": "ANTAGONISM",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "APPENDAGE",
                  "answers": [
                    "improvement",
                    "addition",
                    "attachment"
                  ],
                  "word": "APPENDAGE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DOMICILE",
                  "answers": [
                    "home",
                    "shop",
                    "house"
                  ],
                  "word": "DOMICILE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "GUFFAW",
                  "answers": [
                    "smile",
                    "chuckle",
                    "laugh"
                  ],
                  "word": "GUFFAW",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "STRATA",
                  "answers": [
                    "angles",
                    "rows",
                    "levels"
                  ],
                  "word": "STRATA",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BUFFOON",
                  "answers": [
                    "fool",
                    "thief",
                    "comedian"
                  ],
                  "word": "BUFFOON",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ADVOCATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "tolerate",
                    "defend",
                    "favor"
                  ],
                  "word": "ADVOCATE",
                  "correct": "0"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        }
      ],
      "reviewTest": {
        "wordList": [
          "AGAPE",
          "DOMICILE",
          "MELEE",
          "PLACATE",
          "STRATA",
          "ALOOF",
          "GUFFAW",
          "ORIFICE",
          "QUIRK",
          "SUBMISSIVE",
          "BENEVOLENT",
          "KINDRED",
          "PANG",
          "SQUANDER",
          "SWOON",
          "BLASPHEME",
          "MANIFOLD",
          "PENSIVE",
          "STEADFAST",
          "VEHEMENT",
          "CONTRIVE",
          "ADULTERATE",
          "ANTAGONISM",
          "ENUMERATE",
          "JAUNDICED",
          "PROCURE",
          "ADVOCATE",
          "APPENDAGE",
          "FACADE",
          "KNOLL",
          "QUASH",
          "AFFIX",
          "BUFFOON",
          "GUISE",
          "NONPAREIL",
          "SLOVENLY",
          "ALLOT",
          "CLEAVE",
          "HALLOWED",
          "ORDINANCE",
          "ULTERIOR",
          "AMASS",
          "DEPICT",
          "IMPLORE",
          "PRECIPICE"
        ],
        "questions": [
          {
            "part1": "Their theories of education are",
            "part2": "; they have much in common, although they're not exactly alike.",
            "answer": "kindred"
          },
          {
            "part1": "As they dug deeper they uncovered several",
            "part2": "of ruins, indicating that the city had been rebuilt many times.",
            "answer": "strata"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Although everyone was certain that he had been killed, she remained",
            "part2": "in her belief that someday he would return.",
            "answer": "steadfast"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Mr. Jones",
            "part2": "his life's savings on a scheme he thought would make him wealthy.",
            "answer": "squandered"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Mary almost",
            "part2": "when the handsome movie star kissed her.",
            "answer": "swooned"
          },
          {
            "part1": "With a(n)",
            "part2": "shake of her head, Jane denied that she had stolen the money.",
            "answer": "vehement"
          },
          {
            "part1": "At first the boy seemed rebellious, but he was really very",
            "part2": "and would do whatever he was told.",
            "answer": "submissive"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He cleverly",
            "part2": "to get paid for work he would have had to do for free anyway.",
            "answer": "contrived"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Jim tried to",
            "part2": "his father by washing the car, but his father stayed angry.",
            "answer": "placate"
          },
          {
            "part1": "In her despair she",
            "part2": "God and called Him evil.",
            "answer": "blasphemed"
          },
          {
            "part1": "His stories were so funny that all you could hear were loud",
            "part2": "in the room.",
            "answer": "guffaws"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He felt a(n)",
            "part2": "of envy when he saw his opponent receive the award.",
            "answer": "pang"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Ed has an annoying",
            "part2": "of pretending to be in deep thought whenever you ask him the simplest question.",
            "answer": "quirk"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Our mouths were",
            "part2": "when we heard that we had won the contest.",
            "answer": "agape"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He spent much of his time outside the country, but his legal",
            "part2": "was New York City.",
            "answer": "domicile"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Late at night he would become rather",
            "part2": "and start thinking about the meaning of life.",
            "answer": "pensive"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Even though everyone tried to get him to be friendly, he remained",
            "part2": "and said he was too busy for friendship.",
            "answer": "aloof"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The microbe took in air through a small",
            "part2": "in its side.",
            "answer": "orifice"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The town meeting became a confused",
            "part2": "as one person after another stood up and demanded to be heard.",
            "answer": "melee"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "man helped thousands of needy people.",
            "answer": "benevolent"
          },
          {
            "part1": "There was a list three pages long of the",
            "part2": "duties Sharon had in her important new job.",
            "answer": "manifold"
          },
          {
            "part1": "All of us hold sacred the",
            "part2": "memory of our dead mother.",
            "answer": "hallowed"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He told us that the car was so old it was impossible to",
            "part2": "the parts to repair it.",
            "answer": "procure"
          },
          {
            "part1": "With his sharp ax he managed to",
            "part2": "the log with one stroke.",
            "answer": "cleave"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The nature committee",
            "part2": "turning the area into a state park.",
            "answer": "advocated"
          },
          {
            "part1": "They acted like",
            "part2": ", singing silly songs and playing foolish pranks.",
            "answer": "buffoons"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The company",
            "part2": "the maple syrup by adding some cheaper liquids to it.",
            "answer": "adulterated"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The sick man appeared",
            "part2": ".The doctor suggested that fresh air and sunlight would improve his color.",
            "answer": "jaundiced"
          },
          {
            "part1": "They maintain a(n)",
            "part2": "of happiness, but really they are both very miserable.",
            "answer": "facade"
          },
          {
            "part1": "It is impossible at this time to",
            "part2": "all the reasons why we are doing this.",
            "answer": "enumerate"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He was so",
            "part2": "that he wouldn't wash the dishes or take out the rubbish. His entire house was a mess.",
            "answer": "slovenly"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The police were called in to",
            "part2": "the riot, and they put an end to it almost as soon as it started.",
            "answer": "quash"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We were each",
            "part2": "a portion of the garden in which to grow vegetables.",
            "answer": "allotted"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Jane got dizzy when she stood at the edge of the",
            "part2": "and looked down at the ground far below.",
            "answer": "precipice"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The movie",
            "part2": "him as a handsome, brave fellow, but he wasn't like that at all.",
            "answer": "depicted"
          },
          {
            "part1": "This is merely a(n)",
            "part2": "of the larger work, added on to it much later.",
            "answer": "appendage"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Can't we do something to reduce the",
            "part2": "between those two students? They always look as if they're ready to kill each other.",
            "answer": "antagonism"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The lawyer",
            "part2": "a considerable amount of evidence to use at the trial.",
            "answer": "amassed"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Wendy",
            "part2": "a star to the top of the Christmas tree.",
            "answer": "affixed"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He",
            "part2": "the robber not to take his watch, but the robber ignored his pleas.",
            "answer": "implored"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Her cooking is",
            "part2": "; I've never tasted food that good before.",
            "answer": "nonpareil"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Under the",
            "part2": "of a political survey the study actually probed people's religious beliefs.",
            "answer": "guise"
          },
          {
            "part1": "She must have had some",
            "part2": "purpose in visiting us. She wouldn't come all this way just to say hello.",
            "answer": "ulterior"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Jim lay at the top of a small grassy",
            "part2": "and stared at the sky.",
            "answer": "knoll"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The city issued a new",
            "part2": "that made it illegal to park on the street overnight.",
            "answer": "ordinance"
          }
        ],
        "type": "fitb"
      }
    },
    {
      "wordsets": [
        {
          "title": "6.7",
          "definitions": {
            "DESPOT": {
              "word": "DESPOT",
              "phonetic": "(des'-pÔøΩt",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a tyrant, absolute ruler \nDESPOT was originally an honorary title applied to the emperor of Byzantium. From this the word came to be used about any ruler with absolute and unlimited powers. Nowadays DESPOT usually suggests a ruler who uses these powers unjustly or cruelly. \n\"The DESPOT imprisoned everyone who criticized him.\" \n\"The owner of the company used to be fairly reasonable, but lately he has become a real DESPOT, demanding complete obedience in everything.\" \nThe actions or character of a DESPOT are called DESPOTIC. \n\"The king's DESPOTIC treatment of the peasants caused them to revolt.\" \nOther forms of the word: DESPOTIC, adj. DESPOTISM, n."
            },
            "GENTEEL": {
              "word": "GENTEEL",
              "phonetic": "(jen-tEI')",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "polite, well bred, refined \nGENTEEL is related to the word _gentle_, but the words have taken on very different meanings and should not be confused. GENTEEL means \"having the style or characteristics of the upper class,\" _refined_, _well bred_. \n\"The two very GENTEEL ladies were shocked by the filthiness of the house.\" \nGENTEEL is usually used with a slightly sarcastic sense, as if the politeness and good breeding were put on or out of place. The word is often found in the phrase \"GENTEEL poverty,\" which refers to people who try to maintain the style of the upper classes, even though they are too poor to do this very well."
            },
            "INSUBORDINATE": {
              "word": "INSUBORDINATE",
              "phonetic": "(in-sÔøΩbor'-dÔøΩnit)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "disobedient, rebellious \nSee _in-2_ and _sub-_ under Prefixes and _ate2_ under Suffixes. A person who is a SUBORDINATE is in a lower position than someone else, and he has to obey the people who are above him. \n\"He is a poor boss. He treats his SUBORDINATES as if they didn't have any feelings.\" \nSomeone who is INSUBORDINATE is unwilling to be a SUBORDINATE. He is disobedient and rebels against authority. \n\"Some of my employees were so INSUBORDINATE that I had to fire them.\" \n\"The private was accused of being INSUBORDINATE to an officer.\" \nOther forms of the word: INSUBORDINATION, n."
            },
            "GIRTH": {
              "word": "GIRTH",
              "phonetic": "(gerth)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "circumference, size \nGIRTH comes from an old word for _belt_. A GIRTH is the belt that goes around a horse to keep the saddle in place. GIRTH has come to mean the measurement around something, especially the measurement around a person's body. \n\"For a short person he has a very large GIRTH; it is difficult to find a pair of pants that fit him.\" \n\"They tried to estimate the GIRTH of the tree trunk before they actually measured it.\" \n\"His huge GIRTH made it difficult for him to get in and out of cars.\""
            },
            "INTERJECTION": {
              "word": "INTERJECTION",
              "phonetic": "(in-tÔøΩr-jek'-shÔøΩn)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "an exclamation \nSee _inter-_ under Prefixes. The _ject_ part of the word means _throw_. It is also found in words like _project_ and _reject_. To INTERJECT means to _throw_ in a comment or remark in the middle of what someone else is saying. \n\"'But that's not true!' he INTERJECTED in the middle of the professor's speech.\" \nAn INTERJECTION is a word or phrase suddenly shouted out in excitement. _Wow!_ _Stop!_ _Oh, no!_ _Go ahead!_ are all examples of INTERJECTIONS. \nOther forms of the word: INTERJECT, v."
            },
            "REBUKE": {
              "word": "REBUKE",
              "phonetic": "(ri-byUk')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to scold, criticize, censure \nTo REBUKE someone is to criticize him sharply, to speak severely to him. \n\"The teacher REBUKED him for speaking out of turn.\" \n\"She was REBUKED by her parents for staying out late.\" \nREBUKE is also a noun, meaning \"a strong expression of disapproval,\" a _reproof_. \n\"She received a strong REBUKE for not making her bed.\""
            },
            "LISTLESS": {
              "word": "LISTLESS",
              "phonetic": "(list'-lgs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "spiritless, indifferent \nSee _-less_ under Suffixes. The _list_ part of the word comes from an old word meaning _desire_. Someone who is LISTLESS lacks desire; he is too bored or tired to do anything. The word is used about people's moods, appearance, and actions. \n\"The girl has been in a LISTLESS mood all day. She won't do anything; she just lies on her bed and stares at the ceiling.\" \n\"He greeted them with a LISTLESS handshake which showed he wasn't very interested in meeting them.\" \n\"Pete made a LISTLESS attempt to do his homework, then gave up and went back to watching television.\""
            },
            "PARAPHERNALIA": {
              "word": "PARAPHERNALIA",
              "phonetic": "(par-ÔøΩfar-nAl-yg)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "equipment, apparatus, furnishings \nPARAPHERNALIA is the equipment used for a particular kind of job or a particular purpose. \n\"A baseball player's PARAPHERNALIA includes bat, ball, glove, and uniform.\" \n\"The fishermen stowed all their PARAPHERNALIA under the seats of the boat.\" \n\"When he first entered the laboratory, he didn't know what half of the PARAPHERNALIA was.\""
            },
            "REPERCUSSION": {
              "word": "REPERCUSSION",
              "phonetic": "(rE-pgr-kush'-gn",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "an effect, result, consequence \nSee _re-_ under Prefixes. The _percuss_ part of the word comes from a Latin word meaning to _strike_. _Percussion_ instruments are musical instruments, like drums and cymbals, which make sounds by being struck. A REPERCUSSION is a striking or beating back, such as when a body hits another body that resists it. The word is usually used in a general sense about the effects, often indirect or widespread, of a particular action. \n\"There will certainly be REPERCUSSIONS if we decide to fire him.\" \n\"No one knew what the REPERCUSSIONS of this decision would be.\" \n\"The REPERCUSSIONS of his speech were felt far and wide.\""
            },
            "VIABLE": {
              "word": "VIABLE",
              "phonetic": "(vl'-ÔøΩ-bgl)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "capable of living; workable \nSee _-able_ under Suffixes. The _vi_ part of VIABLE comes from the French word _vie_, which means _life_. Something which is VIABLE is able to live or exist, is capable of surviving. The word is used about unborn babies who have developed enough to be capable of living outside the womb. In a sense that has developed from this, VIABLE means \"capable of being done,\" _workable_. \n\"His plan was clever but not particularly VIABLE. It would cost a lot and require a great deal of work.\" \n\"After some initial problems, their agreement proved to be quite VIABLE.\" \n__Changeable is the most commonly chosen wrong answer in the Pretest, probably because VIABLE is confused with the word _variable_."
            },
            "BAUBLE": {
              "word": "BAUBLE",
              "phonetic": "(bo'-bgl)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a trinket, plaything, ornament \nA BAUBLE is a bright, pretty object that has little or no usefulness. It may or may not be expensive. \n\"He bought some little BAUBLE for the child to keep her occupied during the long trip.\" \n\"She bought several shiny BAUBLES just because she liked the look of them.\" \n\"He said the jewel was just a BAUBLE that he hoped she liked.\""
            },
            "ATTAlN": {
              "word": "ATTAlN",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩtAn')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to reach, achieve, gain \nTo ATTAIN something is to gain it or reach it. The word generally suggests that some effort was needed, or that what was gained was valuable. \n\"You must study if you wish to ATTAIN knowledge.\" \n\"She ATTAINED her present high position by hard work and talent.\" \n\"It will be impossible to ATTAIN our goal without more help.\" \n_Hold_ is the most common mistake as the meaning of ATTAIN. This is probably due to confusion between ATTAIN and _retain_. To _retain_ something is to hold on to it. \n\"Once he had ATTAINED power he did his best to _retain_ it.\" \nOther forms of the word: ATTAINMENT, n."
            },
            "BERATE": {
              "word": "BERATE",
              "phonetic": "(bi-rAt')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to scold, rebuke, criticize sharply \nTo BERATE someone is to scold him sharply and angrily, often for an extended period of time. \n\"The teacher BERATED Tim for constantly being late.\" \n\"There is no need to BERATE the child. She already said she was sorry for her mistake.\" \n\"My mother is constantly BERATING me because my room is so messy.\""
            },
            "CONSENSUS": {
              "word": "CONSENSUS",
              "phonetic": "(k:}n-sen'-s:}s)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a general agreement, collective opinion \nSee _con-_ under Prefixes. The _sens_ part of the word means to _feel_ or _think_. It comes from the same Latin word as _sense_ and _sentiment_. A CONSENSUS is a _feeling together_, a general opinion shared by a number of people. \n\"It was the CONSENSUS of the group that much more work would have to be done.\" \n\"The class was unable to reach a CONSENSUS about the best place to have the Christmas party.\" \n\"The CONSENSUS of the coaches was that he was the best player in the league.\""
            },
            "IMPASSIVE": {
              "word": "IMPASSIVE",
              "phonetic": "(im-pas'-:}v)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "emotionless, unmoved, indifferent \nSomeone who is IMPASSIVE shows no signs of feeling or interest. He has no emotions, at least none that anyone can see. \n\"She remained IMPASSIVE while they told her of her mother's accident.\" \n\"He stared IMPASSIVELY at them as they threatened to torture him.\" \n\"Ken came back to the room with an IMPASSIVE look on his face. No one could tell whether he had passed or failed the test.\""
            }
          },
          "id": 0,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "A real DESPOT.",
                  "answers": [
                    "dungeon",
                    "tyrant",
                    "saint",
                    "fat man",
                    "station"
                  ],
                  "word": "DESPOT",
                  "correct": "tyrant"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "GENTEEL behavior.",
                  "answers": [
                    "strict",
                    "amusing",
                    "calm",
                    "polite",
                    "rude"
                  ],
                  "word": "GENTEEL",
                  "correct": "polite"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Very INSUBORDINATE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "unfriendly",
                    "stingy",
                    "disobedient",
                    "well behaved",
                    "outstanding"
                  ],
                  "word": "INSUBORDINATE",
                  "correct": "disobedient"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Impressive GIRTH.",
                  "answers": [
                    "wit",
                    "depth",
                    "speed",
                    "value",
                    "size"
                  ],
                  "word": "GIRTH",
                  "correct": "size"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Sudden INTERJECTION.",
                  "answers": [
                    "conversation",
                    "excitement",
                    "idea",
                    "exclamation",
                    "removal"
                  ],
                  "word": "INTERJECTION",
                  "correct": "exclamation"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To REBUKE him.",
                  "answers": [
                    "cheat",
                    "hurt",
                    "praise",
                    "scold",
                    "ignore"
                  ],
                  "word": "REBUKE",
                  "correct": "scold"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LISTLESS person.",
                  "answers": [
                    "lost",
                    "ignorant",
                    "spiritless",
                    "penniless",
                    "fearless"
                  ],
                  "word": "LISTLESS",
                  "correct": "spiritless"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Much PARAPHERNALIA.",
                  "answers": [
                    "rejoicing",
                    "equipment",
                    "poverty",
                    "clothing",
                    "confusion"
                  ],
                  "word": "PARAPHERNALIA",
                  "correct": "equipment"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Certain REPERCUSSIONS.",
                  "answers": [
                    "effects",
                    "noises",
                    "injuries",
                    "differences",
                    "reasons"
                  ],
                  "word": "REPERCUSSION",
                  "correct": "effects"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VIABLE projects.",
                  "answers": [
                    "impossible",
                    "workable",
                    "wonderful",
                    "unusual",
                    "changeable"
                  ],
                  "word": "VIABLE",
                  "correct": "workable"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Full of BAUBLES.",
                  "answers": [
                    "beads",
                    "gifts",
                    "diamonds",
                    "rings",
                    "trinkets"
                  ],
                  "word": "BAUBLE",
                  "correct": "trinkets"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Difficult to ATTAIN.",
                  "answers": [
                    "hold",
                    "stop",
                    "see",
                    "know",
                    "reach"
                  ],
                  "word": "ATTAIN",
                  "correct": "reach"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He BERATED the employee.",
                  "answers": [
                    "scolded",
                    "discharged",
                    "praised",
                    "evaluated",
                    "struck"
                  ],
                  "word": "BERATE",
                  "correct": "scolded"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Ignored the CONSENSUS.",
                  "answers": [
                    "idea",
                    "debate",
                    "listing",
                    "agreement",
                    "election"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONSENSUS",
                  "correct": "agreement"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They remained IMPASSIVE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "uncertain",
                    "excited",
                    "unmoved",
                    "tired",
                    "active"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPASSIVE",
                  "correct": "unmoved"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Are most DESPOTS kind?",
                  "word": "DESPOT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a savage be GENTEEL?",
                  "word": "GENTEEL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do teachers prefer INSUBORDINATE students?",
                  "word": "INSUBORDINATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a person with a large GIRTH likely to weigh a lot?",
                  "word": "GIRTH",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is _Ouch!_ an INTERJECTION?",
                  "word": "INTERJECTION",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a teacher REBUKE a student for doing well on a test?",
                  "word": "REBUKE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would LISTLESS people be a lot of fun at a party?",
                  "word": "LISTLESS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do mechanics have PARAPHERNALIA?",
                  "word": "PARAPHERNALIA",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a law to ban cars have REPERCUSSIONS in this country?",
                  "word": "REPERCUSSION",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are VIABLE plans likely to fail?",
                  "word": "VIABLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is an automobile a BAUBLE?",
                  "word": "BAUBLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do people want to ATTAIN their desires?",
                  "word": "ATTAIN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a student be BERATED for getting an A in English?",
                  "word": "BERATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does a unanimous vote represent a CONSENSUS?",
                  "word": "CONSENSUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are football fans usually IMPASSIVE?",
                  "word": "IMPASSIVE",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "The country's DESPOTIC ruler had all his prisoners tortured.",
                  "word": "DESPOT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "It's difficult to act in a GENTEEL manner when you are covered with mud.",
                  "word": "GENTEEL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The boss claimed Art was being INSUBORDINATE, but Art said he had a right to express his opinions.",
                  "word": "INSUBORDINATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "By dieting she was able to decrease her GIRTH by six inches.",
                  "word": "GIRTH",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She completely INTERJECTED any ideas that didn't agree with her own.",
                  "word": "INTERJECTION",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The dog received a strong REBUKE whenever it barked in the house.",
                  "word": "REBUKE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Ed became LISTLESS and eager to get going whenever people were late.",
                  "word": "LISTLESS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He had most of the usual PARAPHERNALIA for cleaning the house, but he couldn't find the vacuum cleaner.",
                  "word": "PARAPHERNALIA",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They had a long REPERCUSSION about the best way to raise money.",
                  "word": "REPERCUSSION",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Despite predictions of disaster, the new nation proved to be quite VIABLE, and actually flourished.",
                  "word": "VIABLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He bought her a ring, bracelet, and some other BAUBLES for her birthday.",
                  "word": "BAUBLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He ATTAINED this house for five years before selling it.",
                  "word": "ATTAIN",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Frank's mother BERATED him for lying to her.",
                  "word": "BERATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Most people thought it was a great movie, but Jane's CONSENSUS was that it was terrible.",
                  "word": "CONSENSUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They tried to make him laugh, but he continued to gaze IMPASSIVELY at them.",
                  "word": "IMPASSIVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "DESPOT",
                  "answers": [
                    "citizen",
                    "tyrant",
                    "ruler"
                  ],
                  "word": "DESPOT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "GENTEEL",
                  "answers": [
                    "generous",
                    "noble",
                    "refined"
                  ],
                  "word": "GENTEEL",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INSUBORDINATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "rebellious",
                    "stupid",
                    "mutinous"
                  ],
                  "word": "INSUBORDINATE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "GIRTH",
                  "answers": [
                    "width",
                    "size",
                    "height"
                  ],
                  "word": "GIRTH",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INTERJECTION",
                  "answers": [
                    "exclamation",
                    "guess",
                    "shout"
                  ],
                  "word": "INTERJECTION",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REBUKE",
                  "answers": [
                    "punish",
                    "debate",
                    "warn"
                  ],
                  "word": "REBUKE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LISTLESS",
                  "answers": [
                    "dull",
                    "bored",
                    "shy"
                  ],
                  "word": "LISTLESS",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PARAPHERNALIA tools",
                  "answers": [
                    "tools",
                    "houses",
                    "instruments"
                  ],
                  "word": "PARAPHERNALIA",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REPERCUSSION",
                  "answers": [
                    "result",
                    "importance",
                    "consequence"
                  ],
                  "word": "REPERCUSSION",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VIABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "living",
                    "necessary",
                    "practical"
                  ],
                  "word": "VIABLE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BAUBLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "watch",
                    "trinket",
                    "toy"
                  ],
                  "word": "BAUBLE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ATTAIN",
                  "answers": [
                    "obtain",
                    "win",
                    "keep"
                  ],
                  "word": "ATTAIN",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BERATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "denounce",
                    "criticize",
                    "mock"
                  ],
                  "word": "BERATE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CONSENSUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "smell",
                    "opinion",
                    "agreement"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONSENSUS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IMPASSIVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "indifferent",
                    "emotionless",
                    "doubtful"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPASSIVE",
                  "correct": "2"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "6.8",
          "definitions": {
            "SAGE": {
              "word": "SAGE",
              "phonetic": "(sAj)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "wise, judicious \nSAGE means _wise_. The word is especially applied to a person who is wise through long experience. \n\"The old judge was noted for his SAGE opinions.\" \n\"The SAGE teacher gave him good advice about how to solve the problem.\" \nSAGE is also a noun, meaning \"a profoundly wise man.\" \n\"The ancient SAGES knew a great deal about human nature.\""
            },
            "INDULGE": {
              "word": "INDULGE",
              "phonetic": "(in-duhlj')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to humor, pamper, spoil, give way to, gratify \nTo INDULGE someone is to satisfy his wishes and demands, even if he has little right to make them. \n\"Grandmother INDULGES those children too much. She lets them do whatever they want.\" \nTo INDULGE yourself is to give in to your own desires or feelings. \n\"After the long journey she INDULGED herself by taking a hot bath and eating at the best restaurant in town.\" \nTo INDULGE _in_ something is to give in to your desire for it. \n\"They INDULGED in ice cream and cake after dinner.\" \n\"He INDULGES in the luxury of a cruise every year.\" \nOther forms of the word: INDULGENCE, n. INDULGENT, adj."
            },
            "RECTIFY": {
              "word": "RECTIFY",
              "phonetic": "(rek'-tÔøΩfl)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to correct, make right \nThe _rect_ part of both RECTIFY and _correct_ comes from a Latin word meaning _right_. Both words mean \"to make or put right.\" See _-fy_ under Suffixes. \n\"He tried to RECTIFY his mistake but only made it worse.\" \n\"She demanded that they RECTIFY their bad habits.\" \n\"If we cannot RECTIFY this problem soon we will have to end the entire project.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer in the Pretest is _change_. You can _change_ something and make it wrong; to RECTIFY is only to make something right."
            },
            "INSURRECTION": {
              "word": "INSURRECTION",
              "phonetic": "(in-sÔøΩrek'-shÔøΩn)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "an uprising, rebellion, revolt \nINSURRECTION comes from a Latin word which means to _rise up_ and which is also the source of the words _surge_ and _insurgent_. An INSURRECTION is a rising up of people in resistance to authority or the government. It is usually less well organized than a rebellion or a revolution. \n\"The leaders of the INSURRECTION claimed that half the population supported their cause.\" \n\"The army crushed the INSURRECTION with little difficulty.\""
            },
            "REPREHENSIBLE": {
              "word": "REPREHENSIBLE",
              "phonetic": "(re-pri-hen'-sÔøΩbÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "blameworthy, deserving censure \nSee _-able_ under Suffixes. REPREHEND is a rather uncommon word that means to _criticize_, to _reprove_. Someone or something that is REPREHENSIBLE deserves to be criticized. \n\"I think your actions were REPREHENSIBLE. You ought to be severely punished.\" \n\"His opinions are fine, but the way he forces everyone to agree with them is REPREHENSIBLE.\" \n\"Everyone thought the company's decision to make the work day longer was REPREHENSIBLE.\" \n_Puzzling_ is the most commonly chosen wrong answer on the Pretest, perhaps because REPREHENSIBLE looks like _incomprehensible_, which means _not understandable_."
            },
            "SOLACE": {
              "word": "SOLACE",
              "phonetic": "(sol'-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "comfort, consolation, relief \nSOLACE means _comfort_ or _relief_ from sorrow or pain. \n\"He looked for SOLACE from his troubles.\" \nSOLACE is also the thing that brings comfort. \n\"Her children were a SOLACE to her in her old age.\" \n\"The money her husband left her in his will was little SOLACE to her after his death.\" \n\"Nothing seemed to comfort him until he found some SOLACE in music.\""
            },
            "MEMOIRS": {
              "word": "MEMOIRS",
              "phonetic": "(mem'-wahrz)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a life story, autobiography, recollections \nNote the pronunciation. MEMOIRS is a French word, and keeps the French pronunciation. \nThe word MEMOIRS is related to the word _memory_. MEMOIRS are a person's life story, usually telling about events and people that he has personal knowledge of. \n\"The general wrote his MEMOIRS about his experiences during the war.\" \n\"Everyone wanted to know what the movie star would say about these people in his MEMOIRS.\" \nMEMOIRS is sometimes used in the singular. \n\"She wrote a MEMOIR of her early days in the fashion industry.\" \n_Short reminders_ is the most popular wrong answer on the Pretest, due to confusion with the word _memo_."
            },
            "RECOMPENSE": {
              "word": "RECOMPENSE",
              "phonetic": "(rek'-ÔøΩm-pens)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a reward, payment, compensation \nA RECOMPENSE is a return or payment made for work, loss, or injury. The word suggests making up for something, an attempt to do justice or to make amends. \n\"He thought the RECOMPENSE they offered was not adequate for the loss of his home.\" \n\"The company gave her a Christmas bonus as partial RECOMPENSE for all the extra work she had done that year.\" \n\"We must make some RECOMPENSE for causing him to miss his plane flight.\" \nRECOMPENSE is also a verb. \n\"The insurance company RECOMPENSED him for the theft of the camera.\""
            },
            "TlNGE": {
              "word": "TlNGE",
              "phonetic": "(tinj)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a trace, slight coloring, slight mixture \nTINGE may be used either as a noun or as a verb. A TINGE is a _trace_ or _slight mixture_ of something. The word is especially used about a slight trace of a color found in something, but it can also be used about traces of emotions in the face or voice. \n\"There is a TINGE of green in the sky.\" \n\"There was a TINGE of sadness in his expression as he walked out the door.\" \nWhen used as a verb, TINGE means to _color_ or _affect slightly_. \n\"The white tile floor was TINGED with yellow after only a few months.\" \n\"Her voice was TINGED with regret as she declined the invitation.\" \n\"The air was TINGED with the pleasant aroma of freshly baked bread.\""
            },
            "VANQUISH": {
              "word": "VANQUISH",
              "phonetic": "(vang'-kwish)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to defeat, overcome, conquer \nVANQUISH means to _defeat_ or _conquer_, but it is stronger than these words. VANQUISH usually suggests an important, complete defeat or conquest of an enemy. \n\"The victorious general had VANQUISHED the enemy.\" \nOne can VANQUISH other things besides enemies. \n\"The disease was totally VANQUISHED after they developed the new medicine.\" \n\"He was able to VANQUISH his fears about flying and board the plane.\""
            },
            "BREVITY": {
              "word": "BREVITY",
              "phonetic": "(brev'-ÔøΩ-tE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "shortness, briefness \nBREVITY is shortness of time. BREVITY is the noun usually used in association with the adjective _brief_. \n\"The program was very brief; we were surprised by its BREVITY.\" \n\"The poet mourned the BREVITY of human life.\" \n\"The BREVITY of this book was more than made up for by its wisdom and humor.\" \nMany people choose _value_ as the meaning of BREVITY, perhaps because BREVITY is usually considered to be a virtue."
            },
            "VENDETTA": {
              "word": "VENDETTA",
              "phonetic": "(ven-det'-:))",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a blood feud \nVENDETTA is the Italian word for _vengeance_. A VENDETTA is a feud between two families that starts when one family murders someone in the other family. Then the second family murders someone in the first family for revenge. And so it goes on and on, sometimes for generations. The most famous American VENDETTA was between the Hatfields and the McCoys. \n\"Romeo and Juliet were forbidden to marry because there was a VENDETTA between their families.\" \n\"After years of VENDETTA, the two families decided on a truce before they were all wiped out.\" \nSometimes the word is used in a general sense for any feud that goes on for a long time. \n\"He had a personal VENDETTA with the company that had sold him the broken typewriter.\""
            },
            "DELETE": {
              "word": "DELETE",
              "phonetic": "(di-lEt')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to erase, take out, cancel, eliminate \nTo DELETE something is to take it out, to erase or omit it. The word is usually used about written or printed matter. \n\"They decided to DELETE this section of the chapter before the book was printed.\" \n\"The teacher DELETED Bill's name from the list of those going to the museum.\" \n\"I was asked to DELETE that sentence from my speech.\" \nMany people confuse DELETE with _shorten_. To DELETE something is to strike it out entirely, not just to shorten it. \nOther forms of the word: DELETION, n."
            },
            "MIRTH": {
              "word": "MIRTH",
              "phonetic": "(merth)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "merriment, laughter, gladness \nMIRTH is gladness or happiness accompanied by laughter and fun. \n\"Everyone was full of MIRTH at the Christmas party.\" \n\"They could barely hide their MIRTH as he slipped on a banana peel.\" \nOther forms of the word: MIRTHFUL, adj. MIRTHLESS, adj."
            },
            "RABBLE": {
              "word": "RABBLE",
              "phonetic": "(rab'-:)I)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a mob, disorderly crowd \nA RABBLE is a crowd or mob of people who act stupidly or unthinkingly. The word is always used in an insulting sense. \n\"He ignored the RABBLE who tried to block his way.\" \n\"The RABBLE in the stadium shouted insults at the referee.\" \nA RABBLE-_rouser_ is a person who tries to stir up a mob, usually by making speeches. \n\"Several RABBLE-rousers urged the mob to take the law into its own hands.\""
            }
          },
          "id": 1,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "SAGE advice.",
                  "answers": [
                    "careful",
                    "wise",
                    "ancient",
                    "foolish",
                    "odd"
                  ],
                  "word": "SAGE",
                  "correct": "wise"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INDULGE the children.",
                  "answers": [
                    "accept",
                    "love",
                    "feed",
                    "pamper",
                    "punish"
                  ],
                  "word": "INDULGE",
                  "correct": "pamper"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To RECTIFY it.",
                  "answers": [
                    "change",
                    "enlarge",
                    "favor",
                    "correct",
                    "destroy"
                  ],
                  "word": "RECTIFY",
                  "correct": "correct"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Started the INSURRECTION.",
                  "answers": [
                    "fight",
                    "argument",
                    "uprising",
                    "trial",
                    "investigation"
                  ],
                  "word": "INSURRECTION",
                  "correct": "uprising"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REPREHENSIBLE behavior.",
                  "answers": [
                    "greedy",
                    "holy",
                    "puzzling",
                    "blameworthy",
                    "fearful"
                  ],
                  "word": "REPREHENSIBLE",
                  "correct": "blameworthy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "A little SOLACE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "joy",
                    "strength",
                    "comfort",
                    "hope",
                    "sorrow"
                  ],
                  "word": "SOLACE",
                  "correct": "comfort"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Read his MEMOIRS.",
                  "answers": [
                    "life story",
                    "orders",
                    "short reminders",
                    "long novel",
                    "responses"
                  ],
                  "word": "MEMOIRS",
                  "correct": "life story"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His RECOMPENSE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "mistake",
                    "duty",
                    "reputation",
                    "value",
                    "reward"
                  ],
                  "word": "RECOMPENSE",
                  "correct": "reward"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "A certain TINGE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "sadness",
                    "trace",
                    "part",
                    "smell",
                    "change"
                  ],
                  "word": "TINGE",
                  "correct": "trace"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To VANQUISH them.",
                  "answers": [
                    "rescue",
                    "lose",
                    "defeat",
                    "hate",
                    "torture"
                  ],
                  "word": "VANQUISH",
                  "correct": "defeat"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Its BREVITY.",
                  "answers": [
                    "length",
                    "decrease",
                    "value",
                    "weight",
                    "shortness"
                  ],
                  "word": "BREVITY",
                  "correct": "shortness"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Stopped the VENDETTA.",
                  "answers": [
                    "blood feud",
                    "sailing race",
                    "melody",
                    "police raid",
                    "truce"
                  ],
                  "word": "VENDETTA",
                  "correct": "blood feud"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DELETE the paragraph.",
                  "answers": [
                    "rearrange",
                    "shorten",
                    "finish",
                    "erase",
                    "include"
                  ],
                  "word": "DELETE",
                  "correct": "erase"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "A great deal of MIRTH.",
                  "answers": [
                    "energy",
                    "light",
                    "excitement",
                    "sadness",
                    "merriment"
                  ],
                  "word": "MIRTH",
                  "correct": "merriment"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Disliked the RABBLE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "workers",
                    "enemy",
                    "nobility",
                    "mob",
                    "young"
                  ],
                  "word": "RABBLE",
                  "correct": "mob"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Does a person have to be old to be SAGE?",
                  "word": "SAGE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do policemen usually INDULGE criminals?",
                  "word": "INDULGE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would most people like to RECTIFY their mistakes?",
                  "word": "RECTIFY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could people be hurt in an INSURRECTION?",
                  "word": "INSURRECTION",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it REPREHENSIBLE to be kind to animals?",
                  "word": "REPREHENSIBLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do some people seek SOLACE in eating?",
                  "word": "SOLACE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would MEMOIRS usually be true?",
                  "word": "MEMOIRS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would ten dollars be sufficient RECOMPENSE for someone whose car was stolen?",
                  "word": "RECOMPENSE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a face ever be TINGED with sadness?",
                  "word": "TINGE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Did Germany VANQUISH the United States in World War II?",
                  "word": "VANQUISH",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a thousand-page book be known for its BREVITY?",
                  "word": "BREVITY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are VENDETTAS generally pleasant?",
                  "word": "VENDETTA",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a single letter be DELETED?",
                  "word": "DELETE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does someone who is full of MIRTH need to be cheered up?",
                  "word": "MIRTH",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can RABBLE be dangerous?",
                  "word": "RABBLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Even though we disliked her, we knew she would give us SAGE advice.",
                  "word": "SAGE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The students INDULGED in all sorts of foolishness when the teacher was away.",
                  "word": "INDULGE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "My mother RECTIFIED me for coming home late.",
                  "word": "RECTIFY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We worked hard on the INSURRECTION of the newspaper; we wanted to make sure everything was perfect.",
                  "word": "INSURRECTION",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "You are old enough now to be REPREHENSIBLE for your own actions.",
                  "word": "REPREHENSIBLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "It took a great deal of SOLACE to understand what the professor meant.",
                  "word": "SOLACE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "In her MEMOIRS she wrote about all the famous people she had met.",
                  "word": "MEMOIRS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The salesman ran up considerable RECOMPENSES while he was on the road.",
                  "word": "RECOMPENSE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "There was a TINGE of anger in his voice when he told them to stop talking.",
                  "word": "TINGE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The senator VANQUISHED all his opponents in the election.",
                  "word": "VANQUISH",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "I was impressed by the BREVITY with which he could present a complicated argument.",
                  "word": "BREVITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They waged a political VENDETTA against the senators who had voted against the bill.",
                  "word": "VENDETTA",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He said that the third clause had to be DELETED before he would sign the contract.",
                  "word": "DELETE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The actress's silly faces caused some MIRTH in the audience.",
                  "word": "MIRTH",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The angry old man said that those teenagers were ignorant RABBLE and should all be locked up.",
                  "word": "RABBLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "SAGE",
                  "answers": [
                    "famous",
                    "intelligent",
                    "sensible"
                  ],
                  "word": "SAGE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INDULGE",
                  "answers": [
                    "humor",
                    "expect",
                    "spoil"
                  ],
                  "word": "INDULGE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RECTIFY",
                  "answers": [
                    "improve",
                    "repair",
                    "exchange"
                  ],
                  "word": "RECTIFY",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INSURRECTION",
                  "answers": [
                    "revolt",
                    "rebel",
                    "reject"
                  ],
                  "word": "INSURRECTION",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REPREHENSIBLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "blameworthy",
                    "laughable",
                    "condemnable"
                  ],
                  "word": "REPREHENSIBLE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SOLACE",
                  "answers": [
                    "help",
                    "relief",
                    "power"
                  ],
                  "word": "SOLACE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MEMOIRS",
                  "answers": [
                    "invention",
                    "remembrance",
                    "description"
                  ],
                  "word": "MEMOIRS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RECOMPENSE",
                  "answers": [
                    "accept",
                    "repay",
                    "compensate"
                  ],
                  "word": "RECOMPENSE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TINGE",
                  "answers": [
                    "shade",
                    "dirt",
                    "color"
                  ],
                  "word": "TINGE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VANQUISH",
                  "answers": [
                    "overcome",
                    "forget",
                    "conquer"
                  ],
                  "word": "VANQUISH",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BREVITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "quickness",
                    "fun",
                    "briefness"
                  ],
                  "word": "BREVITY",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VENDETTA",
                  "answers": [
                    "despair",
                    "grudge",
                    "revenge"
                  ],
                  "word": "VENDETTA",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DELETE",
                  "answers": [
                    "finish",
                    "remove",
                    "omit"
                  ],
                  "word": "DELETE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MIRTH",
                  "answers": [
                    "amusement",
                    "gratefulness",
                    "happiness"
                  ],
                  "word": "MIRTH",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RABBLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "crowd",
                    "audience",
                    "mob"
                  ],
                  "word": "RABBLE",
                  "correct": "1"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "6.9",
          "definitions": {
            "SMUG": {
              "word": "SMUG",
              "phonetic": "(smuhg)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "self-satisfied, pleased with oneself, complacent \nA SMUG person is quite pleased with himself. SMUG people firmly believe they are right or superior, and take delight in being better than others. SMUGNESS is not a very admirable quality. \n\"Alice felt quite SMUG after she had beaten her brother at tennis.\" \n\"SMUG in his belief that he knew the subject, he didn't bother studying for the test.\" \n\"She gave her friends a SMUG smile as she walked up to the stage to receive her award.\" \nOther forms of the word: SMUGNESS, n."
            },
            "VINDICTIVE": {
              "word": "VINDICTIVE",
              "phonetic": "(vin-dik'-tiv)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "vengeful, unforgiving \nVINDICTIVE means \"showing a desire for revenge.\" A VINDICTIVE person by nature wants to get even with anyone who wrongs him. \n\"She's a VINDICTIVE person. If she thinks you've said something bad about her, she'll spend weeks trying to get back at you.\" \n\"My father was stern, but he wasn't VINDICTIVE.\" \n\"He made some VINDICTIVE remarks about his old enemy.\" \n\"We don't want to be VINDICTIVE; we just want to get back the money he took from us.\""
            },
            "BEDEVIL": {
              "word": "BEDEVIL",
              "phonetic": "(bi-dev'-ÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to torment, harass, annoy, plague \n_Be-_ is a prefix which forms verbs out of nouns. To BEDEVIL someone is to treat him _devilishly_, usually by constantly annoying or worrying him. \n\"The mosquitoes BEDEVILED us when we camped by the lake.\" \n\"This project has been BEDEVILED by problems since the beginning.\" \n\"She was BEDEVILED by minor illnesses all year.\" \nIn the Pretest, the most commonly chosen incorrect answer is _astound_, perhaps due to a confusion of BEDEVIL with _bedazzle_, which means to _impress forcefully_."
            },
            "NEGLIGIBLE": {
              "word": "NEGLIGIBLE",
              "phonetic": "(neg'-li-jÔøΩbÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "unimportant, small, not worthy of attention \nSee _-able_ under Suffixes. Anything that is NEGLIGIBLE is able to be neglected without worrying about it, usually because it is so unimportant or tiny. \n\"The medicine had a NEGLIGIBLE effect. She was no better after taking it than before.\" \n\"His attempts to help us were NEGLIGIBLE. I don't think he tried very hard.\" \n\"You get a NEGLIGIBLE saving by buying the large economy size. It's just not worth it.\""
            },
            "EDIFYING": {
              "word": "EDIFYING",
              "phonetic": "(ed'-ÔøΩfl-ing)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "uplifting, enlightening, instructive \nEDIFYING and its related verb EDIFY are from the same Latin root as _edifice_, which means \"a large and impressive building.\" To EDIFY originally meant simply to _build_. Now it is only used in the sense of \"to build up one's mind or morals.\" \nAn \"EDIFYING experience\" is one which improves you spiritually or intellectually. It is not necessarily an enjoyable experience, although it may be. \n\"The teacher said it would be an EDIFYING experience for us to go to the museum.\" \n\"The minister delivered a very EDIFYING sermon.\" \nOther forms of the word: EDIFY, v. EDIFICATION, n."
            },
            "MALEFACTOR": {
              "word": "MALEFACTOR",
              "phonetic": "(mal'-ÔøΩfak-tÔøΩ)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a criminal, evildoer \nMALEFACTOR comes from Latin words meaning \"to do evil.\" A MALEFACTOR is a criminal, or anyone who does evil to another. \n\"Some unknown MALEFACTOR broke several windows in the school last night.\" \n\"The MALEFACTORS must not be allowed to get away with their crime.\" \nThe opposite of MALEFACTOR is _benefactor_, someone who does good to other people."
            },
            "MUSE": {
              "word": "MUSE",
              "phonetic": "(myUz)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to think, meditate, ponder, reflect \nTo MUSE _on_ or _over_ something is to think silently about it. The word usually suggests a dreamy or wondering attitude rather than serious thought. \n\"He MUSED on the shortness of human life.\" \n\"She MUSED over the good times they used to have.\" \n\"Sally MUSED about the beauty of nature.\""
            },
            "REPROACH": {
              "word": "REPROACH",
              "phonetic": "(ri-prOch')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to blame, criticize, rebuke \nTo REPROACH someone is to find fault with him, especially in a tone that suggests sorrow or the need for sorrow. The idea is often that of shaming a person into being better. \n\"Jim's mother REPROACHED him for forgetting her birthday.\" \n\"The teacher REPROACHED the students for not studying harder.\" \nREPROACH is also a noun, meaning _blame_ or _censure_. A person whose reputation is \"above REPROACH\" has never done anything he might be blamed for. \n\"His criminal activities brought REPROACH on his entire family.\" \nOther forms of the word: REPROACHFUL, adj."
            },
            "ENVOY": {
              "word": "ENVOY",
              "phonetic": "(on'-voy",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a messenger, agent, deputy, representative \nENVOY is from a French word meaning to _send_. An ENVOY is a person sent somewhere as a representative of a government, business, group of people, etc. \n\"We sent him as our ENVOY to meet with our opponents.\" \n\"The ENVOY came to beg us to forgive his king.\" \nIn diplomacy, ENVOY is a specific rank of diplomat, second in importance after an ambassador. \nNote the different pronunciations. Sometimes words from foreign languages keep their foreign pronunciation for a long time in English. ENVOY seems to be in the process of changing from the French pronunciation _on'-voy_ to the English _en'-voy_."
            },
            "FISSURE": {
              "word": "FISSURE",
              "phonetic": "(fish'-ÔøΩr)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a narrow crack or opening \nA FISSURE is a long, narrow crack, usually rather deep, and usually made by splitting or breaking. \n\"The earthquake caused many FISSURES to appear on the sides of the mountain.\" \nIn a broader sense, a FISSURE is a division or disagreement which threatens to break up a group of people. \n\"A FISSURE developed in the party between those who supported the war and those who opposed it.\" \n\"His stand on unemployment opened up many FISSURES in his previously solid support.\""
            },
            "COALESCE": {
              "word": "COALESCE",
              "phonetic": "(kO-ÔøΩ-les')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to unite, join together \nTo COALESCE is to come or grow together into one body or group. COALESCE often suggests a slow or natural process of growing together. \n\"Over time the land between them was built up and the two islands finally COALESCED.\" \n\"Several small parties managed to COALESCE into one important political organization.\""
            },
            "DELUGE": {
              "word": "DELUGE",
              "phonetic": "(del'-yUj)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a flood, downpour \nA DELUGE is a great flood, usually caused by a tremendous downpour of rain. A DELUGE can also be anything that overwhelms like a flood. \n\"When the movie star was sick, the hospital received a DELUGE of mail.\" \n\"There was a DELUGE of criticism when the popular teacher was fired.\" \nDELUGE is also a verb meaning to _flood_. \n\"When the dam broke, towns along the river were DELUGED.\" \n\"They DELUGED the company with requests for more information.\" \n\"He was DELUGED with job offers after he graduated from school.\" \n_Battle_ is the most commonly chosen wrong answer, possibly because DELUGE sometimes has a sense of violence and destructiveness."
            },
            "FARCICAL": {
              "word": "FARCICAL",
              "phonetic": "(fahr'-sg-kgl",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "absurd, laughable, ridiculous \nA FARCE is a comedy, usually one filled with silly characters and unbelievable situations. \n\"We expected a serious drama, but it turned out to be a light-hearted FARCE.\" \nA FARCE is also any situation or event that is like such a comedy. \n\"Everything seemed to go wrong; the entire picnic was a complete FARCE.\" \nFARCICAL is the adjective from FARCE. See _-ic_ under Suffixes. Something that is FARCICAL is like a FARCE, so silly and extreme that it is funny. \n\"His attempts to explain why he was late were almost FARCICAL.\" \n\"It was a FARCICAL game. The players seemed to make up the rules as they went along.\" \nOther forms of the word: FARCE, n."
            },
            "SURMISE": {
              "word": "SURMISE",
              "phonetic": "(sgr-mlz')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to guess, suspect, suppose, think \nTo SURMISE means \"to believe without strong evidence,\" to _guess_ or _suppose_. \n\"He SURMISED that there would be a surprise party for him.\" \n\"The detective SURMISED that the burglars had entered the house through an open window.\" \nSURMISE is also a noun, which means a _guess_. \n\"Her SURMISE proved to be correct.\""
            },
            "ASSENT": {
              "word": "ASSENT",
              "phonetic": "(g-sent')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to agree, consent, concur \nTo ASSENT to something is to agree to it. ASSENT often does not suggest strong support but a weaker kind of \"going along.\" \n\"My father ASSENTED when I asked him if I could go to the movies.\" \n\"I cannot ASSENT to the idea that all men are basically evil.\" \n\"Everyone ASSENTED to the proposal that we have a party.\" \nASSENT is also a noun, meaning _agreement_. \n\"The teacher gave her ASSENT to our suggestion that we have a class picnic.\" \nUsage: ASSENT is often followed by _to_."
            }
          },
          "id": 2,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "SMUG people.",
                  "answers": [
                    "insulting",
                    "self-satisfied",
                    "frightened",
                    "clever",
                    "funny"
                  ],
                  "word": "SMUG",
                  "correct": "self-satisfied"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Known to be VINDICTIVE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "lying",
                    "unkind",
                    "vengeful",
                    "loving",
                    "blameless"
                  ],
                  "word": "VINDICTIVE",
                  "correct": "vengeful"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Continues to BEDEVIL me.",
                  "answers": [
                    "astound",
                    "thrill",
                    "torment",
                    "defeat",
                    "fear"
                  ],
                  "word": "BEDEVIL",
                  "correct": "torment"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "NEGLIGIBLE amounts.",
                  "answers": [
                    "unknown",
                    "unimportant",
                    "usual",
                    "considerable",
                    "agreed"
                  ],
                  "word": "NEGLIGIBLE",
                  "correct": "unimportant"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "A very EDIFYING experience.",
                  "answers": [
                    "shameful",
                    "boring",
                    "solemn",
                    "frightening",
                    "uplifting"
                  ],
                  "word": "EDIFYING",
                  "correct": "uplifting"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Approached the MALEFACTOR.",
                  "answers": [
                    "priest",
                    "policeman",
                    "businessman",
                    "criminal",
                    "soldier"
                  ],
                  "word": "MALEFACTOR",
                  "correct": "criminal"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To MUSE on it.",
                  "answers": [
                    "meditate",
                    "sleep",
                    "smile",
                    "speak",
                    "decide"
                  ],
                  "word": "MUSE",
                  "correct": "meditate"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To REPROACH them.",
                  "answers": [
                    "forget",
                    "ruin",
                    "applaud",
                    "meet",
                    "blame"
                  ],
                  "word": "REPROACH",
                  "correct": "blame"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He sent the ENVOY.",
                  "answers": [
                    "warning",
                    "messenger",
                    "spy",
                    "guard",
                    "ship"
                  ],
                  "word": "ENVOY",
                  "correct": "messenger"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Found the FISSURE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "stream",
                    "narrow crack",
                    "joining place",
                    "deep hole",
                    "boulder"
                  ],
                  "word": "FISSURE",
                  "correct": "narrow crack"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They will COALESCE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "change",
                    "boil",
                    "unite",
                    "separate",
                    "harden"
                  ],
                  "word": "COALESCE",
                  "correct": "unite"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "After the DELUGE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "winter",
                    "battle",
                    "explosion",
                    "flood",
                    "trick"
                  ],
                  "word": "DELUGE",
                  "correct": "flood"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FARCICAL actions.",
                  "answers": [
                    "violent",
                    "serious",
                    "unexplained",
                    "thoughtless",
                    "absurd"
                  ],
                  "word": "FARCICAL",
                  "correct": "absurd"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "I SURMISE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "know",
                    "hope",
                    "guess",
                    "feel",
                    "remember"
                  ],
                  "word": "SURMISE",
                  "correct": "guess"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They all ASSENTED.",
                  "answers": [
                    "sat down",
                    "finished",
                    "prepared",
                    "agreed",
                    "refused"
                  ],
                  "word": "ASSENT",
                  "correct": "agreed"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Are SMUG people usually very likable?",
                  "word": "SMUG",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a VINDICTIVE person hold a grudge?",
                  "word": "VINDICTIVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it pleasant to be BEDEVILED?",
                  "word": "BEDEVILED",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a jackhammer cause a NEGLIGIBLE amount of noise?",
                  "word": "NEGLIGIBLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is an EDIFYING experience always an enjoyable one?",
                  "word": "EDIFYING",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a MALEFACTOR be famous?",
                  "word": "MALEFACTOR",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can you MUSE over something unimportant?",
                  "word": "MUSE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do people often feel sorry after they have been REPROACHED?",
                  "word": "REPROACH",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is an ENVOY likely to travel much?",
                  "word": "ENVOY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a FISSURE solid?",
                  "word": "FISSURE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can heat make objects COALESCE?",
                  "word": "COALESCE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would three letters be a DELUGE of mail?",
                  "word": "DELUGE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would people be sad at a FARCICAL event?",
                  "word": "FARCICAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can you SURMISE when you aren't certain?",
                  "word": "SURMISE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a person ASSENT to something he doesn't particularly like?",
                  "word": "ASSENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "With a SMUG air of superiority he showed them how to put the puzzle together.",
                  "word": "SMUG",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Our VINDICTIVE neighbors built a large fence just to block our view.",
                  "word": "VINDICTIVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Doubts about his decision continued to BEDEVIL him long after it had been made.",
                  "word": "BEDEVIL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Although they worked hard at cleaning the house, the results were NEGLIGIBLE; it was just about as dirty as before.",
                  "word": "NEGLIGIBLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She only bought top-quality food to EDIFY her family.",
                  "word": "EDIFYING",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He had a secret MALEFACTOR who sent him the money to finish college.",
                  "word": "MALEFACTOR",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The comedian MUSED us with his jokes.",
                  "word": "MUSE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The car REPROACHED us at seventy miles an hour.",
                  "word": "REPROACH",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The president sent his personal ENVOY to talk with the king.",
                  "word": "ENVOY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The debate over whether to hire him caused a FISSURE in the organization.",
                  "word": "FISSURE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The six streams meet and COALESCE into a river.",
                  "word": "COALESCE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They DELUGED him with prizes after he won the contest.",
                  "word": "DELUGE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His explanation of how electricity works was so obviously wrong it was almost FARCICAL.",
                  "word": "FARCICAL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "From the way Bill was acting, Mary SURMISED that he was unhappy in his new job.",
                  "word": "SURMISE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She ASSENTED the fact that he made more money than she did for doing the same job.",
                  "word": "ASSENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "SMUG",
                  "answers": [
                    "confident",
                    "vain",
                    "eager"
                  ],
                  "word": "SMUG",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VINDICTIVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "hopeless",
                    "merciless",
                    "spiteful"
                  ],
                  "word": "VINDICTIVE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BEDEVIL",
                  "answers": [
                    "trouble",
                    "annoy",
                    "defeat"
                  ],
                  "word": "BEDEVIL",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "NEGLIGIBLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "uncertain",
                    "insignificant",
                    "tiny"
                  ],
                  "word": "NEGLIGIBLE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EDIFYING",
                  "answers": [
                    "educational",
                    "enjoyable",
                    "uplifting"
                  ],
                  "word": "EDIFYING",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MALEFACTOR",
                  "answers": [
                    "madman",
                    "thief",
                    "murderer"
                  ],
                  "word": "MALEFACTOR",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MUSE",
                  "answers": [
                    "wonder",
                    "consider",
                    "discuss"
                  ],
                  "word": "MUSE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REPROACH",
                  "answers": [
                    "scold",
                    "criticize",
                    "despise"
                  ],
                  "word": "REPROACH",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ENVOY",
                  "answers": [
                    "leader",
                    "diplomat",
                    "representative"
                  ],
                  "word": "ENVOY",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FISSURE",
                  "answers": [
                    "split",
                    "opening",
                    "increase"
                  ],
                  "word": "FISSURE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "COALESCE",
                  "answers": [
                    "join",
                    "add",
                    "blend"
                  ],
                  "word": "COALESCE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DELUGE",
                  "answers": [
                    "overwhelm",
                    "drown",
                    "hurt"
                  ],
                  "word": "DELUGE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FARCICAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "ridiculous",
                    "dangerous",
                    "humorous"
                  ],
                  "word": "FARCICAL",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SURMISE",
                  "answers": [
                    "guess",
                    "imagine",
                    "study"
                  ],
                  "word": "SURMISE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ASSENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "agree",
                    "waver",
                    "comply"
                  ],
                  "word": "ASSENT",
                  "correct": "1"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        }
      ],
      "reviewTest": {
        "wordList": [
          "BAUBLE",
          "DELUGE",
          "INSURRECTION",
          "MUSE",
          "SAGE",
          "BERATE",
          "GIRTH",
          "MALEFACTOR",
          "PARAPHERNALIA",
          "VANQUISH",
          "BREVITY",
          "IMPASSIVE",
          "MEMOIRS",
          "RECTIFY",
          "VENDETTA",
          "DELETE",
          "INSUBORDINATE",
          "MIRTH",
          "REPROACH",
          "VIABLE",
          "ASSENT",
          "DESPOT",
          "GENTEEL",
          "RABBLE",
          "SOLACE",
          "ATTAIN",
          "EDIFYING",
          "INDULGE",
          "REBUKE",
          "SMUG",
          "BEDEVIL",
          "ENVOY",
          "INTERJECTION",
          "RECOMPENSE",
          "SURMISE",
          "COALESCE",
          "FARCICAL",
          "LISTLESS",
          "REPERCUSSION",
          "TINGE",
          "CONSENSUS",
          "FISSURE",
          "NEGLIGIBLE",
          "REPREHENSIBLE",
          "VINDICTIVE"
        ],
        "questions": [
          {
            "part1": "He always had a(n)",
            "part2": "expression on his face. You could never tell what he was thinking.",
            "answer": "impassive"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The clerk looked very sad and",
            "part2": "the little boy for trying to steal the candy.",
            "answer": "reproached"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Because of the huge size of our army we were able to",
            "part2": "the enemy in the battle.",
            "answer": "vanquish"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The police claimed that he was the",
            "part2": "responsible for burning down the building.",
            "answer": "malefactor"
          },
          {
            "part1": "She liked to take a few moments at night, sit by herself, and",
            "part2": "over the events of the day.",
            "answer": "muse"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The child was very",
            "part2": "; she absolutely refused to do what she was told.",
            "answer": "insubordinate"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The company admitted its mistake and promised to",
            "part2": "it immediately.",
            "answer": "rectify"
          },
          {
            "part1": "His",
            "part2": "are full of humorous stories about the events of his life.",
            "answer": "memoirs"
          },
          {
            "part1": "They were always laughing and joking and full of",
            "part2": ". It seemed that nothing could make them unhappy.",
            "answer": "mirth"
          },
          {
            "part1": "His constant eating increased his",
            "part2": "until he couldn't fit into any of his suits.",
            "answer": "girth"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We were amazed by the",
            "part2": "of his speech; it only lasted thirty seconds.",
            "answer": "brevity"
          },
          {
            "part1": "It is an exciting idea, but it's just not",
            "part2": "; we would never have enough time to put it into effect.",
            "answer": "viable"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The two families have had a(n)",
            "part2": "with each other for generations. By now everyone has forgotten how it started.",
            "answer": "vendetta"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The policeman angrily",
            "part2": "the child for running out into the traffic.",
            "answer": "berated"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The king had to put down several minor",
            "part2": "by groups who opposed him.",
            "answer": "insurrections"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The editor said the book was too long, so he shortened some chapters and",
            "part2": "others.",
            "answer": "deleted"
          },
          {
            "part1": "They carefully cleaned all the",
            "part2": "that would be needed for the job.",
            "answer": "paraphernalia"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The tremendous rainstorms caused a(n)",
            "part2": "which destroyed many houses.",
            "answer": "deluge"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The child quickly grew tired of the bright, pretty",
            "part2": "and wanted something more interesting to play with.",
            "answer": "bauble"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He is a(n)",
            "part2": "and sensible man who is known for his wise handling of difficult problems.",
            "answer": "sage"
          },
          {
            "part1": "There was a slight reddish",
            "part2": "to her dress.",
            "answer": "tinge"
          },
          {
            "part1": "A series of injuries",
            "part2": "the athlete during his playing career.",
            "answer": "bedeviled"
          },
          {
            "part1": "No amount of money could be adequate",
            "part2": "for the harm they had done him.",
            "answer": "recompense"
          },
          {
            "part1": "It is impossible to",
            "part2": "perfection in our work, but we should come as close as we can.",
            "answer": "attain"
          },
          {
            "part1": "I don't think what she did was so",
            "part2": "; I wouldn't criticize anyone for just trying to tell the truth.",
            "answer": "reprehensible"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The principal gave a very",
            "part2": "speech on the importance of studying. We all learned a lot.",
            "answer": "edifying"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The police were instructed to keep the",
            "part2": "off the streets so that the visiting king would see only clean, respectful tradespeople.",
            "answer": "rabble"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Jim's mother",
            "part2": "him strongly for not obeying her.",
            "answer": "rebuked"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Al feels very",
            "part2": "sometimes. He just wants to sleep and eat and watch television.",
            "answer": "listless"
          },
          {
            "part1": "I'm not sure exactly when he'll be back, but I",
            "part2": "that he'll be here in time for supper.",
            "answer": "surmise"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "of the committee was that it needed more time before it could reach a final decision.",
            "answer": "consensus"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Some of the poison leaked out, but the amount was",
            "part2": "; it wasn't enough to harm anyone.",
            "answer": "negligible"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We sent our",
            "part2": "to the new country to tell them of our peaceful intentions.",
            "answer": "envoy"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The clown's",
            "part2": "attempt to ride a bicycle backward had everyone laughing.",
            "answer": "farcical"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Both of us",
            "part2": "to the arrangement by which we split the reward equally.",
            "answer": "assented"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The war between the two little countries had serious",
            "part2": "throughout the world.",
            "answer": "repercussions"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The climber fell into the deep",
            "part2": "in the side of the mountain.",
            "answer": "fissure"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Art wasn't",
            "part2": "when people wronged him; he didn't believe in seeking revenge.",
            "answer": "vindictive"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The parents",
            "part2": "their children by letting them stay up an extra hour.",
            "answer": "indulged"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He lived in",
            "part2": "poverty. He wore the most expensive suits, but they were threadbare and ragged.",
            "answer": "genteel"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He was quite",
            "part2": "about his victory, and said the losers would never be as good as he was.",
            "answer": "smug"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Several small groups of people",
            "part2": "into one large crowd.",
            "answer": "coalesced"
          },
          {
            "part1": "As he grew older the king became more and more of a(n)",
            "part2": ", making all laws by himself and jailing anyone who opposed him.",
            "answer": "despot"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Many kind friends came to offer",
            "part2": "to her in her time of trouble.",
            "answer": "solace"
          },
          {
            "part1": "She shouted out \"Wonderful!\", \"Marvelous!\", and other",
            "part2": "during the exciting concert.",
            "answer": "interjections"
          }
        ],
        "type": "fitb"
      }
    },
    {
      "wordsets": [
        {
          "title": "6.10",
          "definitions": {
            "EMPHATIC": {
              "word": "EMPHATIC",
              "phonetic": "(em-fat'-ik)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "forceful, insistent, strongly expressive, striking \nEMPHASIS is the stress or force used to show that something is important. \n\"The coach laid great EMPHASIS on speed.\" \nEMPHATIC is the adjective from EMPHASIS. See _-ic_ under Suffixes. EMPHATIC means _forceful_, _insistent_. \n\"The mayor issued an EMPHATIC denial to the rumor that he was seriously ill.\" \n\"Jim's tone was EMPHATIC when he said he would never let Bill drive his car again.\" \n\"The teacher said EMPHATICALLY that there would be absolutely no talking during the test.\" \nOther forms of the word: EMPHASIS, n. EMPHASIZE, v."
            },
            "INCEPTION": {
              "word": "INCEPTION",
              "phonetic": "(in-sep'-shÔøΩn)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "beginning, start, commencement \nINCEPTION is a rather formal word for the _beginning_ or _start_ of something. The word is used especially about projects, organizations, practices, and the like. \n\"Since the INCEPTION of the fund-raising drive we have received over ten thousand dollars.\" \n\"I was present at the club's INCEPTION two years ago.\" \n\"The plot of the novel changed greatly between the book's INCEPTION and its completion.\""
            },
            "GINGERLY": {
              "word": "GINGERLY",
              "phonetic": "(jin'-jÔøΩr-lE)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "careful, cautious, wary \nGINGERLY means _careful_ or _cautious_. To do something in a GINGERLY manner is to do it with care, in order to avoid hurting yourself, making a noise, or breaking something. \n\"They moved in a GINGERLY way across the beach, looking out for pieces of broken glass.\" \nGINGERLY is also an adverb. \n\"He GINGERLY picked up the priceless vase and carried it across the room.\" \n\"We walked GINGERLY through the minefield, afraid that any second we would be blown up.\""
            },
            "IMPLEMENT": {
              "word": "IMPLEMENT",
              "phonetic": "(im'-plÔøΩmÔøΩnt)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a tool, instrument \nAn IMPLEMENT is a _tool_, an object used in carrying out some kind of work. \n\"She had a hoe, a rake, and other gardening IMPLEMENTS.\" \n\"As part of the peace treaty they agreed to give up all their IMPLEMENTS of war.\" \n\"Television can be used as an IMPLEMENT of education.\" \nIMPLEMENT is also a verb, meaning to _carry out_ or _put into effect_. \n\"The workers were told to IMPLEMENT the president's new policy immediately.\" \n\"It's easy to make a decision; it's more difficult to IMPLEMENT it.\" \nIn the Pretest, the most popular wrong answer is _decoration_. This may be due to a confusion between IMPLEMENT and _ornament_, which is a _decoration_. \nOther forms of the word: IMPLEMENTATION, n."
            },
            "PALPITATE": {
              "word": "PALPITATE",
              "phonetic": "(pal'-pÔøΩtAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to throb, beat rapidly, pulsate, quiver \nTo PALPITATE is to beat rapidly and strongly, like the heart during exercise or strong emotion. \n\"Her heart started to PALPITATE whenever she thought of the man she loved.\" \n\"Running up the flight of stairs caused the man's heart to PALPITATE.\" \nOther forms of the word: PALPITATION, n."
            },
            "INTREPID": {
              "word": "INTREPID",
              "phonetic": "(in-trep'-id)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "fearless, daring, brave \nSee _in-2_ under Prefixes. The _trepid_ part of the word comes from a Latin word meaning _fear_, also the source of the English word _trepidation_. Someone who is INTREPID is _fearless_; he is daring and resolute when it comes to meeting danger. \n\"The INTREPID explorers set off into the jungle, knowing they might never come out alive.\" \nOther forms of the word: INTREPIDITY, n."
            },
            "MATRON": {
              "word": "MATRON",
              "phonetic": "mA'-tr:>n)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a dignified married woman \nA MATRON is a married woman, especially a mature or dignified one with a high social position. \n\"They were dignified old MATRONS who spent most of their time on the committees for various charities.\" \nMATRON is also used for the woman who is in charge of the housekeeping at a hospital, prison, or similar institution. \nOther forms of the word: MATRONLY, adj."
            },
            "PALATABLE": {
              "word": "PALATABLE",
              "phonetic": "pal'-:>t-:>-b:>I)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "tasty, agreeable to the taste \nSee _-able_ under Suffixes. The _palate_ is the roof of the mouth; it was once popularly thought to be where the sense of taste was located. Thus, something which is PALATABLE is agreeable to the _palate_ or the taste. The word is usually used about foods that are little more than acceptable to the palate, and not about foods which taste wonderful. \n\"The dinner he cooked was at least PALATABLE, which is more than I expected.\" \n\"This vegetable can be PALATABLE if it is cooked the right way.\" \nSometimes PALATABLE is used in a general sense to mean _agreeable_, _acceptable_. \n\"You may not find my criticisms very PALATABLE, but I'm still going to make them.\""
            },
            "RETICENT": {
              "word": "RETICENT",
              "phonetic": "(ret'-:>-sÔøΩnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "silent, reserved, quiet \nSomeone who is RETICENT is not inclined to say much, either out of caution or shyness. A RETICENT person keeps most things to himself, and only gives out information grudgingly. \n\"She was RETICENT about what had happened that day. It was obvious she was hiding something.\" \n\"He is usually RETICENT about all his accomplishments, but this time he told everyone.\" \n\"Don't be RETICENT. Let us know how you feel.\" \nOther forms of the word: RETICENCE, n."
            },
            "SORDID": {
              "word": "SORDID",
              "phonetic": "sor'-did)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "filthy, dirty \nSomeone or something that is SORDID is filthy and disgusting. The word's basic meaning is _dirty_, but it always suggests uncleanness that is caused by evil or corruption. \n\"It was difficult for children to grow up in these SORDID surroundings.\" \n\"He had some SORDID habits which caused all decent people to avoid him.\" \n\"The evil criminals carried out their SORDID plot to kidnap the child.\""
            },
            "DISCREET": {
              "word": "DISCREET",
              "phonetic": "(dis-krEt')",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "tactful, cautious, careful \nA person who is DISCREET shows good judgment in what he says or does. He is very careful not to do anything which might harm his own interests or those of his friends. A DISCREET person can be trusted with a secret, or with a task that requires tact and diplomacy. \n\"The DISCREET diplomat refused to criticize the leaders of the foreign country.\" \n\"She thought it would be DISCREET to leave before the party got too wild.\" \nA \"DISCREET silence\" occurs when someone has decided that it's better not to say anything in a particular situation. \nOther forms of the word: DISCRETION, n. DISCRETIONARY, adj."
            },
            "AGGRIEVED": {
              "word": "AGGRIEVED",
              "phonetic": "(:>-grEvd')",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "wronged, offended, troubled \nAGGRIEVED is related to the words _grief_ and _grieve_. To be AGGRIEVED is to be wronged or treated unjustly, so that you have cause for complaint. \n\"He felt AGGRIEVED when the teacher punished him and not the rest of the students.\" \n\"Bill had a permanently AGGRIEVED attitude; he thought that people were always treating him badly.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer is _neglected_. Someone who is _neglected_ may have a right to feel AGGRIEVED, but the two words do not have the same meaning. \nOther forms of the word: AGGRIEVE, v."
            },
            "EQUITY": {
              "word": "EQUITY",
              "phonetic": "(ek'-wÔøΩtE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "fairness, impartiality, justice \nEQUITY is related to the word _equal_. EQUITY is the quality of being fair, just, and impartial. \n\"The EQUITY of his solution seemed to please everyone.\" \n\"He thought that as a matter of EQUITY he should get a share.\" \nIn English and American law, EQUITY is a particular system of rules and doctrines which is designed to correct or override other laws in cases where they appear to work unfairly. The adjective formed from EQUITY is EQUITABLE, which means _reasonable_, _just_. \n\"It was hardly an EQUITABLE arrangement, since she paid for the car and he was the only one who could use it.\" \nOther forms of the word: EQUITABLE, adj."
            },
            "LEGACY": {
              "word": "LEGACY",
              "phonetic": "(leg'-ÔøΩsE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "an inheritance, bequest \nA LEGACY is something, like land or money, left by will as a gift to someone else. \n\"Her uncle left her a small LEGACY which helped pay for her college education.\" \nIn a general sense, a LEGACY is anything received from the past or from our ancestors. \n\"Their chief LEGACY to their children was a keen desire to help the unfortunate.\" \n\"Those beautiful paintings are our LEGACY from the great artists of the past.\""
            },
            "PLEBEIAN": {
              "word": "PLEBEIAN",
              "phonetic": "(pl::-bE'-:;,n)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "commonplace, undistinguished \nIn ancient Rome there were two classes of people, the _plebs_, or common people, and the _patricians_, or nobles. The adjective PLEBEIAN means \"of or relating to the plebs or common people.\" The word is used about people, things ,or activities that are considered crude or commonplace. \n\"The nobleman didn't want his daughter to marry into such a PLEBEIAN family.\" \n\"He considered himself too cultured to take part in so PLEBEIAN a sport as bowling.\" \nPLEBEIAN is also a noun. \n\"I may only be a simple PLEBEIAN, but I have rights too.\""
            }
          },
          "id": 0,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "His EMPHATIC reply.",
                  "answers": [
                    "mild",
                    "forceful",
                    "quick",
                    "insulting",
                    "puzzling"
                  ],
                  "word": "EMPHATIC",
                  "correct": "forceful"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Its INCEPTION.",
                  "answers": [
                    "improvement",
                    "end",
                    "beginning",
                    "approval",
                    "value"
                  ],
                  "word": "INCEPTION",
                  "correct": "beginning"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "GINGERLY movements.",
                  "answers": [
                    "silent",
                    "clumsy",
                    "careful",
                    "slow",
                    "quick"
                  ],
                  "word": "GINGERLY",
                  "correct": "careful"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Bronze IMPLEMENT.",
                  "answers": [
                    "cup",
                    "decoration",
                    "weapon",
                    "statue",
                    "tool"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPLEMENT",
                  "correct": "tool"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To PALPITATE continuously.",
                  "answers": [
                    "bother",
                    "work",
                    "worry",
                    "throb",
                    "float"
                  ],
                  "word": "PALPITATE",
                  "correct": "throb"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INTREPID men.",
                  "answers": [
                    "brilliant",
                    "fearless",
                    "cowardly",
                    "cold",
                    "watchful"
                  ],
                  "word": "INTREPID",
                  "correct": "fearless"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Visited the MATRON.",
                  "answers": [
                    "married woman",
                    "young girl",
                    "bride",
                    "rich man",
                    "teacher"
                  ],
                  "word": "MATRON",
                  "correct": "married woman"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PALATABLE food.",
                  "answers": [
                    "unsurpassed",
                    "sweet",
                    "tasty",
                    "disagreeable",
                    "colorless"
                  ],
                  "word": "PALATABLE",
                  "correct": "tasty"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Unusually RETICENT.",
                  "answers": [
                    "frightened",
                    "sad",
                    "quiet",
                    "lonely",
                    "noisy"
                  ],
                  "word": "RETICENT",
                  "correct": "quiet"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SORDID surroundings.",
                  "answers": [
                    "dangerous",
                    "filthy",
                    "magnificent",
                    "ruined",
                    "various"
                  ],
                  "word": "SORDID",
                  "correct": "filthy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DISCREET refusal.",
                  "answers": [
                    "secret",
                    "tactful",
                    "proud",
                    "total",
                    "thoughtless"
                  ],
                  "word": "DISCREET",
                  "correct": "tactful"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She felt AGGRIEVED.",
                  "answers": [
                    "relaxed",
                    "neglected",
                    "satisfied",
                    "tired",
                    "wronged"
                  ],
                  "word": "AGGRIEVED",
                  "correct": "wronged"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The EQUITY of the decision.",
                  "answers": [
                    "purpose",
                    "acceptance",
                    "fairness",
                    "importance",
                    "result"
                  ],
                  "word": "EQUITY",
                  "correct": "fairness"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "A small LEGACY.",
                  "answers": [
                    "association",
                    "request",
                    "inheritance",
                    "profit",
                    "mistake"
                  ],
                  "word": "LEGACY",
                  "correct": "inheritance"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Considered them PLEBEIAN.",
                  "answers": [
                    "clumsy",
                    "majestic",
                    "holy",
                    "commonplace",
                    "foreign"
                  ],
                  "word": "PLEBEIAN",
                  "correct": "commonplace"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "If a teacher puts EMPHASIS on neatness, does she care about it?",
                  "word": "EMPHATIC",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Has a project gotten very far at the time of its INCEPTION?",
                  "word": "INCEPTION",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "If someone had to carry a bomb, would he carry it GINGERLY?",
                  "word": "GINGERLY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a pen be considered an IMPLEMENT?",
                  "word": "IMPLEMENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a heart always PALPITATING?",
                  "word": "PALPITATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are mountain climbers usually INTREPID?",
                  "word": "INTREPID",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a baby be a MATRON?",
                  "word": "MATRON",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is dirt PALATABLE?",
                  "word": "PALATABLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would most salesmen be RETICENT?",
                  "word": "RETICENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a person be SORDID?",
                  "word": "SORDID",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Should a secret agent be DISCREET?",
                  "word": "DISCREET",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a person who feels AGGRIEVED likely to be angry at someone?",
                  "word": "AGGRIEVED",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Should people be angry about an EQUITABLE decision?",
                  "word": "EQUITABLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a diamond ring be a LEGACY?",
                  "word": "LEGACY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a duchess be a PLEBEIAN?",
                  "word": "PLEBEIAN",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "He struck the table EMPHATICALLY to show that he meant what he said.",
                  "word": "EMPHATIC",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The school held an INCEPTION so that everyone could meet the new principal.",
                  "word": "INCEPTION",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They GINGERLY picked up the child and placed her in the ambulance.",
                  "word": "GINGERLY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They IMPLEMENTED the actor on his fine performance.",
                  "word": "IMPLEMENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He PALPITATED the switch to make sure it worked.",
                  "word": "PALPITATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He was so INTREPID that his hand started to shake as he opened the door.",
                  "word": "INTREPID",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His grandmother was a distinguished MATRON.",
                  "word": "MATRON",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "I expected a wonderful meal; instead I got some stale bread that was barely PALATABLE.",
                  "word": "PALATABLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The RETICENT boy wouldn't tell his parents why he was afraid to go to school.",
                  "word": "RETICENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Everyone admired the SORDID way he treated his children.",
                  "word": "SORDID",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "When asked if she would run for reelection, the senator kept a DISCREET silence.",
                  "word": "DISCREET",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Her AGGRIEVED expression showed that she was feeling sorry for herself again.",
                  "word": "AGGRIEVED",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We were amazed by the EQUITY of the arrangement, under which she got less pay for the same amount of work.",
                  "word": "EQUITY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "A continuing hostility between the two countries was the unfortunate LEGACY of the ancient war.",
                  "word": "LEGACY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She felt that watching television was a PLEBEIAN activity, and refused to do it.",
                  "word": "PLEBEIAN",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "EMPHATIC",
                  "answers": [
                    "cruel",
                    "strong",
                    "insistent"
                  ],
                  "word": "EMPHATIC",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INCEPTION",
                  "answers": [
                    "origin",
                    "victory",
                    "start"
                  ],
                  "word": "INCEPTION",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "GINGERLY",
                  "answers": [
                    "cautiously",
                    "worriedly",
                    "accurately"
                  ],
                  "word": "GINGERLY",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IMPLEMENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "road",
                    "device",
                    "machine"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPLEMENT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PALPITATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "vibrate",
                    "tremble",
                    "ache"
                  ],
                  "word": "PALPITATE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INTREPID",
                  "answers": [
                    "bold",
                    "rude",
                    "daring"
                  ],
                  "word": "INTREPID",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MATRON",
                  "answers": [
                    "elderly",
                    "ill",
                    "dignified"
                  ],
                  "word": "MATRON",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PALATABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "possible",
                    "edible",
                    "acceptable"
                  ],
                  "word": "PALATABLE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RETICENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "shy",
                    "secretive",
                    "sad"
                  ],
                  "word": "RETICENT",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SORDID",
                  "answers": [
                    "expensive",
                    "mean",
                    "vile"
                  ],
                  "word": "SORDID",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DISCREET",
                  "answers": [
                    "happy",
                    "quiet",
                    "careful"
                  ],
                  "word": "DISCREET",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "AGGRIEVED",
                  "answers": [
                    "upset",
                    "offended",
                    "nervous"
                  ],
                  "word": "AGGRIEVED",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EQUITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "justness",
                    "fairness",
                    "brilliance"
                  ],
                  "word": "EQUITY",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LEGACY",
                  "answers": [
                    "earnings",
                    "inheritance",
                    "gift"
                  ],
                  "word": "LEGACY",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PLEBEIAN",
                  "answers": [
                    "easy",
                    "average",
                    "common"
                  ],
                  "word": "PLEBEIAN",
                  "correct": "0"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "6.11",
          "definitions": {
            "RECAPITULATE": {
              "word": "RECAPITULATE",
              "phonetic": "(rE-kg-pich'-ÔøΩIAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to sum up, summarize, restate briefly \nTo RECAPITULATE means to _sum up_ an argument, a discussion, or the like, by going over the main points again. \n\"At the end of the debate both sides briefly RECAPITULATED their positions.\" \n\"She RECAPITULATED the reasons why she should be elected president.\" \n\"I would like to RECAPITULATE what other writers have said about this novel.\" \nIn the Pretest, many people choose _continue_ as the meaning of RECAPITULATE, but RECAPITULATE means to _summarize_, usually with a view towards ending a speech or an argument. \nOther forms of the word: RECAPITULATION, n."
            },
            "EXODUS": {
              "word": "EXODUS",
              "phonetic": "(ek'-sg-dÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a mass departure, emigration \nThe EXODUS was the departure of the Israelites from Egypt, described in the second book of the Bible. An EXODUS has come to mean any departure or going away of a large group of people, with or without the difficulties that the Israelites had in leaving Egypt. See _ex-_ under Prefixes. \n\"The promise of better jobs in the growing cities caused a large EXODUS of workers from rural areas.\" \nThe most popular wrong answer is _trip_, which is close to the meaning of EXODUS but not quite the same. One person could go by himself on a _trip_ to the store, but this would not be an EXODUS."
            },
            "IMBIBE": {
              "word": "IMBIBE",
              "phonetic": "(im-blb')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to drink, drink in, absorb \nIMBIBE comes from Latin words meaning \"to drink in.\" See _in-1_ under Prefixes. The word means actual drinking and \"drinking in\" or absorbing ideas, knowledge, and the like. \n\"He tried to IMBIBE all the knowledge the teacher could give him.\" \nWhen IMBIBE means actual drinking, it sometimes has a rather humorous tone. \n\"The drunk said he only IMBIBED on national holidays.\""
            },
            "HEW": {
              "word": "HEW",
              "phonetic": "(hyU)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to cut, chop, carve \nTo HEW something is to cut it. The word usually suggests a rough job of cutting, done with an ax, a sword, or the like. \n\"He HEWED the trunk of the tree with one mighty blow of his ax.\" \n\"This statue was HEWN out of solid rock.\" \n\"They had to HEW a path for themselves through the thick jungle.\" \n\"She HEWED the branches from the tree.\" \nUsage: The past participle of HEW is HEWN."
            },
            "ILLUSTRIOUS": {
              "word": "ILLUSTRIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(Huhs'-trE-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "famous, eminent, distinguished, celebrated \nILLUSTRIOUS comes from a Latin word meaning to _brighten_, also the source of the word _luster_. People who are ILLUSTRIOUS are famous. They are brilliantly distinguished because of what they have done or because of their good qualities. \n\"Our ILLUSTRIOUS ancestors made this nation as great as it is today.\" \n\"This novel will make the ILLUSTRIOUS writer even more famous.\" \n\"When the ILLUSTRIOUS judge retired, everyone honored him for his wisdom and mercy.\" \n_Hardworking_ is the most commonly chosen incorrect answer, probably because of confusion between ILLUSTRIOUS and _industrious_."
            },
            "WANTON": {
              "word": "WANTON",
              "phonetic": "(won'-tÔøΩn)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "immoral, irresponsible, reckless, undisciplined \nThe basic meaning of WANTON is \"lacking discipline.\" The word is used in several ways using this idea. WANTON can mean \"done unjustifiably,\" _malicious_. \n\"The youths were charged with the WANTON attack on the old man.\" \nIt can mean _extravagant_, _unchecked_. \n\"Your WANTON spending is going to make us all poor.\" \nOr it can mean _immoral_, _unchaste_. \n\"These WANTON people are a disgrace to the neighborhood.\" \n_Rare_ is the most commonly chosen wrong answer, perhaps because of the _want_ part of the word."
            },
            "IMPART": {
              "word": "IMPART",
              "phonetic": "(im-pahrt')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to make known, communicate, transmit, pass on \nTo IMPART means to _communicate_, to _pass on_. The word is used in two different senses. The first is to _give_ or _pass on_ a quality or condition to something. \n\"The new carpet IMPARTED a certain elegance to the dining room.\" \n\"The general's signature at the bottom IMPARTED a great deal of authority to the orders.\" \nThe second sense is simply to _tell_ or _make known_ something. \n\"I want to IMPART some secret information to you.\" \n\"The professor IMPARTED his knowledge to the students.\""
            },
            "WILE": {
              "word": "WILE",
              "phonetic": "(wll)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a trick, ploy, ruse \nA WILE is a trick used to entrap someone or to lure him on. \n\"The babysitter had to use all her WILES to get the children to go to bed.\" \n\"He was not taken in by her WILES, and refused to go along with the scheme.\" \n\"We used all our WILES, but we still couldn't get the teacher to postpone the test.\" \nWILY is the adjective from WILE. See _-y_ under Suffixes. WILY means _tricky_, _crafty_, _sly_. \n\"The WILY old thief knew all the ways to steal people's money.\" \nUsage: WILE is usually used in the plural, WILES."
            },
            "ESPOUSE": {
              "word": "ESPOUSE",
              "phonetic": "(es-powz'",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to support, adopt, make one's own, come to believe in \nA _spouse_ is a marriage partner, a husband or wife. To ESPOUSE meant originally \"to take as a spouse,\" to _wed_. The word is still sometimes used in this way, but it usually now has the sense \"to attach yourself to a cause or a belief' as if you were married to it. \n\"They eagerly ESPOUSED the doctrine of equal pay for equal work.\" \n\"Everyone ESPOUSED the miners' cause.\" \n\"He ESPOUSED a strange theory that turned out to be correct.\" \nESPOUSE is a stronger word than _believe_ or _support_; it suggests more eagerness and completeness in your feelings. \n\"Once he had ESPOUSED this new idea, no one could talk him out of it.\""
            },
            "WROUGHT": {
              "word": "WROUGHT",
              "phonetic": "(rot)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "shaped, fashioned, formed \nWROUGHT is an old form of the past tense of _work_. WROUGHT as an adjective basically means _worked_. The word is usually applied to objects that have been carefully or elaborately fashioned, especially by hand. \n\"He bought his wife a pair of beautifully WROUGHT earrings for her birthday.\" \n\"The lovely hand-WROUGHT lampshade was quite expensive.\" \nWhen used of metals, WROUGHT means \"beaten or hammered into shape with tools.\" \n\"The candlesticks were WROUGHT of the finest silver.\" \nIn a different sense WROUGHT is used in the phrase \"WROUGHT up,\" which means _worked up_, _excited_. \n\"My mother gets all WROUGHT up when I don't come home on time.\""
            },
            "LAUDABLE": {
              "word": "LAUDABLE",
              "phonetic": "(lod'-ÔøΩbÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "praiseworthy, deserving praise, commendable \nSee _-able_ under Suffixes. LAUD is a rare word meaning to _praise highly_. Something or someone that is LAUDABLE is able to be praised, is worthy of being praised. \n\"Your desire to increase your vocabulary is LAUDABLE.\" \n\"We thought his opinions were LAUDABLE, but we didn't like the way he insisted that everyone agree with him.\" \n_Understandable_ is the most commonly chosen wrong answer, perhaps because LAUDABLE sounds like _audible_, which means \"able to be heard.\""
            },
            "CULPABLE": {
              "word": "CULPABLE",
              "phonetic": "(kuhl'-pÔøΩÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "blameworthy \nSee _-able_ under Suffixes. The _culp_ part of the word comes from a Latin word meaning _blame_, also the source of the word _culprit_. Someone or something that is CULPABLE is worthy of being blamed for something, deserves condemnation or punishment. \n\"The judge said her parents were as CULPABLE for her crimes as she was.\" \n\"You cannot consider him CULPABLE, since he was forced to do what he did.\" \n\"His ignorance of the dangerous situation was CULPABLE, because it was his job to know about such things.\" \nThe most commonly chosen incorrect answer is _effective_, probably because of a confusion between CULPABLE and _capable_. \nOther forms of the word: CULPABILITY, n."
            },
            "PICAYUNE": {
              "word": "PICAYUNE",
              "phonetic": "(pik'-E-yUn",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "trivial, trifling, small, unworthy of notice \nA PICAYUNE was a small coin used in the Spanish colo- nies in America. When the Americans took over the word, it came to be used as an adjective which means _small_, _insignificant_, _practically worthless_. \n\"She owes a PICAYUNE amount--not more than a dollar.\" \n\"Several of the patients had PICAYUNE complaints about their treatment, but everyone was pleased in general.\" \n\"He thought her criticisms were PICAYUNE; they were just about minor points that didn't make any difference.\""
            },
            "SCATHING": {
              "word": "SCATHING",
              "phonetic": "(skATH'-ing)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "damaging, harmful, very severe \nSCATHING is an old English word which meant _harmful_, _damaging_, or _injurious_. SCATHING is now used chiefly about damaging or harmful words. \n\"The reviewer gave a SCATHING criticism of the new play, saying that the author couldn't write and that the actors couldn't perform.\" \n\"The boss's SCATHING reply to Ken's suggestion hurt him deeply.\" \nThe related word UNSCATHED means _unharmed_, _undamaged_. \n\"It was a miracle she walked away from the accident UNSCATHED.\" \nOther forms of the word: UNSCATHED, adj."
            },
            "SUPERFICIAL": {
              "word": "SUPERFICIAL",
              "phonetic": "(sU-pÔøΩr-fish'-ÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "shallow, trivial, insignificant \nSUPERFICIAL comes from the Latin word for _surface_. Something which is SUPERFICIAL is on the surface only; it doesn't go very deep. A SUPERFICIAL wound is a minor wound which just involves the surface of the skin. When applied to people and their actions, SUPERFICIAL means \"concerned only with what is on the surface, with what is apparent and obvious.\" \n\"It was a SUPERFICIAL report. It just gave the facts, not the reasons behind them.\" \n\"The doctor gave him a quick, SUPERFICIAL examination and said he was all right.\" \nOther forms of the word: SUPERFICIALITY, n."
            }
          },
          "id": 1,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "RECAPITULATE the argument.",
                  "answers": [
                    "continue",
                    "answer",
                    "sum up",
                    "end",
                    "lose"
                  ],
                  "word": "RECAPITULATE",
                  "correct": "sum up"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The EXODUS began.",
                  "answers": [
                    "prayer",
                    "mass departure",
                    "trip",
                    "long visit",
                    "miracle"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXODUS",
                  "correct": "mass departure"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The guests IMBIBED.",
                  "answers": [
                    "ate",
                    "were late",
                    "wrote",
                    "stayed sober",
                    "drank"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMBIBE",
                  "correct": "drank"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To HEW it.",
                  "answers": [
                    "replace",
                    "cut",
                    "burn",
                    "fix",
                    "kill"
                  ],
                  "word": "HEW",
                  "correct": "cut"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ILLUSTRIOUS men.",
                  "answers": [
                    "famous",
                    "happy",
                    "beloved",
                    "unknown",
                    "hardworking"
                  ],
                  "word": "ILLUSTRIOUS",
                  "correct": "famous"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "WANTON people.",
                  "answers": [
                    "needy",
                    "immoral",
                    "rare",
                    "popular",
                    "holy"
                  ],
                  "word": "WANTON",
                  "correct": "immoral"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To IMPART knowledge.",
                  "answers": [
                    "lose",
                    "hide",
                    "divide up",
                    "gain",
                    "make known"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPART",
                  "correct": "make known"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Full of WILES.",
                  "answers": [
                    "smiles",
                    "danger",
                    "fear",
                    "tears",
                    "tricks"
                  ],
                  "word": "WILE",
                  "correct": "tricks"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He ESPOUSES their plan.",
                  "answers": [
                    "admires",
                    "requests",
                    "opposes",
                    "supports",
                    "demands"
                  ],
                  "word": "ESPOUSE",
                  "correct": "supports"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Carefully WROUGHT.",
                  "answers": [
                    "shaped",
                    "colored",
                    "placed",
                    "chosen",
                    "purchased"
                  ],
                  "word": "WROUGHT",
                  "correct": "shaped"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LAUDABLE actions.",
                  "answers": [
                    "impossible",
                    "praiseworthy",
                    "silly",
                    "understandable",
                    "clever"
                  ],
                  "word": "LAUDABLE",
                  "correct": "praiseworthy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He was CULPABLE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "miserable",
                    "wonderful",
                    "evil",
                    "effective",
                    "blameworthy"
                  ],
                  "word": "CULPABLE",
                  "correct": "blameworthy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Several PICAYUNE points.",
                  "answers": [
                    "typical",
                    "boring",
                    "trivial",
                    "crucial",
                    "different"
                  ],
                  "word": "PICAYUNE",
                  "correct": "trivial"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SCATHING reports.",
                  "answers": [
                    "revealing",
                    "exciting",
                    "disturbing",
                    "damaging",
                    "disagreeing"
                  ],
                  "word": "SCATHING",
                  "correct": "damaging"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SUPERFICIAL treatment.",
                  "answers": [
                    "formal",
                    "unnecessary",
                    "shallow",
                    "careful",
                    "mistaken"
                  ],
                  "word": "SUPERFICIAL",
                  "correct": "shallow"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Can you RECAPITULATE what someone else has said?",
                  "word": "RECAPITULATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it an EXODUS when a person leaves his house in the morning?",
                  "word": "EXODUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can you IMBIBE milk?",
                  "word": "IMBIBE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can you HEW a table?",
                  "word": "HEW",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is Adolf Hitler ILLUSTRIOUS?",
                  "word": "ILLUSTRIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are WANTON people always poor?",
                  "word": "WANTON",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do dictionaries IMPART information?",
                  "word": "IMPART",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would it be easy to cheat a WILY person?",
                  "word": "WILE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do people who are against change ESPOUSE it?",
                  "word": "ESPOUSE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a highly WROUGHT piece of furniture usually be plain?",
                  "word": "WROUGHT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it LAUDABLE to save a person from drowning?",
                  "word": "LAUDABLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a person be CULPABLE if he struck a car while driving on the wrong side of the road?",
                  "word": "CULPABLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is PICAYUNE criticism helpful to a person?",
                  "word": "PICAYUNE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do mothers sing SCATHING lullabies to their babies?",
                  "word": "SCATHING",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a SUPERFICIAL injury usually be very serious?",
                  "word": "SUPERFICIAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Hal RECAPITULATED his main arguments against the proposal.",
                  "word": "RECAPITULATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The governor tried to stop the EXODUS of businesses from his state by lowering taxes.",
                  "word": "EXODUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He IMBIBED her not to give in.",
                  "word": "IMBIBE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "An immense hole was HEWN in the side of the mountain.",
                  "word": "HEW",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The ILLUSTRIOUS composer wrote some of the greatest symphonies of our time.",
                  "word": "ILLUSTRIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The judge criticized their WANTON disregard for the ordinary standards of decency.",
                  "word": "WANTON",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His presence IMPARTED a sense of importance to the meeting.",
                  "word": "IMPART",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He knew about all his opponent's WILES and didn't let himself be trapped.",
                  "word": "WILE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "All the students ESPOUSED the idea of a shorter school day.",
                  "word": "ESPOUSE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The robbers took all his money and then WROUGHT him up.",
                  "word": "WROUGHT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His first attempt at playing the trumpet was LAUDABLE. No one could stay in the same room when he was practicing.",
                  "word": "LAUDABLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "John is our most CULPABLE salesman; no one is as good as he is.",
                  "word": "CULPABLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "You had better not make a mistake. This is the most PICAYUNE decision you will ever have to make.",
                  "word": "PICAYUNE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Many were injured in the explosion, but Barry was UNSCATHED.",
                  "word": "SCHATHING",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "That movie was SUPERFICIAL. I think it's the best I've ever seen.",
                  "word": "SUPERFICIAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "RECAPITULATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "explain",
                    "repeat",
                    "summarize"
                  ],
                  "word": "RECAPITULATE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EXODUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "emigration",
                    "departure",
                    "visit"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXODUS",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IMBIBE",
                  "answers": [
                    "absorb",
                    "drink",
                    "eat"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMBIBE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HEW",
                  "answers": [
                    "spill",
                    "split",
                    "saw"
                  ],
                  "word": "HEW",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ILLUSTRIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "different",
                    "great",
                    "distinguished"
                  ],
                  "word": "ILLUSTRIOUS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "WANTON",
                  "answers": [
                    "extravagant",
                    "powerful",
                    "spiteful"
                  ],
                  "word": "WANTON",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IMPART",
                  "answers": [
                    "know",
                    "tell",
                    "transmit"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPART",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "WILE",
                  "answers": [
                    "cheat",
                    "winner",
                    "fake"
                  ],
                  "word": "WILE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ESPOUSE",
                  "answers": [
                    "applaud",
                    "believe",
                    "erect"
                  ],
                  "word": "ESPOUSE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "WROUGHT",
                  "answers": [
                    "fixed",
                    "made",
                    "formed"
                  ],
                  "word": "WROUGHT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LAUDABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "good",
                    "rare",
                    "worthwhile"
                  ],
                  "word": "LAUDABLE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CULPABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "guilty",
                    "unreasonable",
                    "responsible"
                  ],
                  "word": "CULPABLE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PICAYUNE",
                  "answers": [
                    "petty",
                    "lost",
                    "worthless"
                  ],
                  "word": "PICAYUNE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SCATHING",
                  "answers": [
                    "bitter",
                    "ridiculous",
                    "insulting"
                  ],
                  "word": "SCATHING",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SUPERFICIAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "outward",
                    "insignificant",
                    "extraordinary"
                  ],
                  "word": "SUPERFICIAL",
                  "correct": "2"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "6.12",
          "definitions": {
            "AFFINITY": {
              "word": "AFFINITY",
              "phonetic": "(:)-fin'-:)-tE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "an attraction, natural liking, close connection \nAn AFFINITY _for_ something is a strong liking for or attraction to it. \n\"She found she had an AFFINITY for speaking in public.\" \n\"They felt a strange AFFINITY for the deserted old house.\" \nAn AFFINITY _with_ or _between_ things or people is a close resemblance or connection between them. \n\"There is a strong AFFINITY between the two writers.\" \n\"The English language has many AFFINITIES with German.\" \nAFFINITY has some very specific uses involving this basic idea of _attraction_ or _connection_. AFFINITY is relationship by marriage (as opposed to a relationship by blood). In chemistry, AFFINITY is the force by which atoms are held together in chemical compounds."
            },
            "VISTA": {
              "word": "VISTA",
              "phonetic": "(vis'-tJ)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a view, prospect \nA VISTA is a _view_, especially one seen through or along a narrow passage or avenue. \n\"We saw the beautiful VISTA of the distant mountains through the long rows of trees.\" \n\"A VISTA of the huge mansion appeared to them at the end of the driveway.\" \nA VISTA can also be a mental view extending over long periods of time or many matters. \n\"Einstein's theories opened many new VISTAS for research in physics.\""
            },
            "ASPIRE": {
              "word": "ASPIRE",
              "phonetic": "(J-splr')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to long, yearn, be ambitious \nTo ASPIRE _to_ or _after_ something is to be filled with ambition to reach it or accomplish it. You usually ASPIRE to something grand or important. \n\"Jane ASPIRED to the presidency.\" \n\"She ASPIRED to be the best singer of her time.\" \n\"Tom only ASPIRED after knowledge; nothing else mattered to him.\" \nASPIRATION is the noun from ASPIRE and means _ambition_, _goal_. \n\"His one ASPIRATION is to be a professional baseball player.\" \nOther forms of the word: ASPIRATION, n."
            },
            "ASSIMILATE": {
              "word": "ASSIMILATE",
              "phonetic": "(J-sim'-:)-IAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to absorb, take in \nTo ASSIMILATE something is to take it in so that it becomes a part of you. The word can be used about food. \n\"The body can ASSIMILATE some foods more easily than others.\" \nOr it can be used in a wider sense of ideas or knowledge. \n\"Johnny found it difficult to ASSIMILATE all the material the teacher presented to the class.\" \nThe word is also used about races and cultural groups. \n\"It took many years before the immigrants were completely ASSIMILATED into American society.\" \nOther forms of the word: ASSIMILATION, n."
            },
            "IMPETUS": {
              "word": "IMPETUS",
              "phonetic": "(im'-pJ-tJs)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a moving force, impulse, stimulus \nIMPETUS is the force behind something, the energy with which it is moving. \n\"He gave the tricycle a push, and this IMPETUS carried it all the way down the street.\" \n\"The train didn't have enough IMPETUS to get to the top of the hill.\" \nIMPETUS is also used in a more general sense to mean any _driving force_ or _stimulus_. \n\"The idea of getting rich quick was a strong IMPETUS behind the gold rush.\" \n\"His enthusiasm was the real IMPETUS behind the project.\""
            },
            "ARDENT": {
              "word": "ARDENT",
              "phonetic": "(ahr'-dJnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "burning, warm, passionate, enthusiastic \nARDENT comes from a Latin word meaning to _burn_. ARDENT is now not often used about actual fire or heat, but means _on fire_ with desire, enthusiasm, or some other strong emotion. \n\"He was an ARDENT supporter of free speech.\" \n\"She felt an ARDENT desire to see her native land once more.\" \n\"He spoke ARDENTLY of his love for his wife.\" \nThe noun related to ARDENT is ARDOR, which means \"warmth of emotion,\" _passion_, _zeal_. \n\"His ARDOR for chess cooled when he started playing opponents who could beat him.\" \nOther forms of the word: ARDOR, n."
            },
            "CONFOUND": {
              "word": "CONFOUND",
              "phonetic": "(kÔøΩn-townd'",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to confuse, mix up, puzzle, perplex \nCONFOUND comes from Latin words which mean to _pour together_. See _con-_ under Prefixes. To CONFOUND things is to mix them up so that one thing is confused with another. \n\"The author's error is to CONFOUND the desire to do good with the good deed itself.\" \nTo CONFOUND a person is to confuse him. CONFOUND in this sense is a rather strong word, and suggests such total puzzlement that it is difficult for a person to act. \n\"The sudden disappearance of the jewels CONFOUNDED everyone.\" \n\"They were CONFOUNDED by his stubborn refusal to go along.\" \nIn the Pretest, many people choose _anger_ as the meaning of CONFOUND, probably because CONFOUND is used in a mild oath, \"CONFOUND it.\" In this sense, CONFOUND means _damn_. It is an expression of anger, but it doesn't mean to make someone angry."
            },
            "REVEL": {
              "word": "REVEL",
              "phonetic": "(rev'-ÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to make merry \nTo REVEL is to make merry, to be festive. \n\"They REVELED for days when they heard the war was over.\" \nTo REVEL _in_ something is take great delight in it. \n\"He seemed to REVEL in making people feel uncomfortable.\" \n\"They REVELED in their freedom when school was over.\" \nREVEL is also a noun meaning _merrymaking_, _noisy festivities_. \n\"It was quite a REVEL. The fun lasted until dawn.\" \n\"There were REVELS every night on the millionaire's yacht.\" \nOther forms of the word: REVELRY, n."
            },
            "BESTIAL": {
              "word": "BESTIAL",
              "phonetic": "(bes'-chÔøΩI",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "beast-like, brutal, savage \nBESTIAL is an adjective from _beast_. See _-al_ under Suffixes. The word means \"of or like a beast\" and usually emphasizes the cruelty and savagery of a wild animal. \n\"The BESTIAL soldiers killed the women and children in cold blood.\" \n\"They should go to prison for life for their BESTIAL crimes.\" \n\"His BESTIAL behavior when he has been drinking shocks everyone.\" \nThe noun from BESTIAL is BESTIALITY, which is the quality of being a beast. \n\"The BESTIALITY of these vicious criminals outraged the public.\" \nOther forms of the word: BESTIALITY, n."
            },
            "ORDEAL": {
              "word": "ORDEAL",
              "phonetic": "(or-dEI')",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a severe trial \nIn ancient times, one way of deciding whether a person was guilty or innocent of a crime was to make the person undergo a severe or painful test like walking through fire. If the person survived this test, he was thought to be innocent of the crime. This test was known as an ORDEAL. \nNowadays, ORDEAL is used for any severe test or trying experience. \n\"Being lost in the desert without water was quite an ORDEAL.\" \n\"For her, every math test was an ORDEAL.\" \n\"It was a terrible ORDEAL for him to speak before a crowd.\""
            },
            "AFFABLE": {
              "word": "AFFABLE",
              "phonetic": "(af'-ÔøΩbÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "pleasant, friendly, gracious \nSee _-able_ under Suffixes. AFFABLE comes from Latin words meaning \"able to speak to.\" An AFFABLE person is easy to talk to; he is friendly and polite to everyone. \n\"The manager was unusually AFFABLE this morning; she laughed and joked with everyone on the staff.\" \n\"Our boss is very AFFABLE; he even stops and says hello to the part-time clerks.\" \n_Competent_ is the most commonly chosen wrong answer. Perhaps the people who choose this are confused by the _-able_ part of AFFABLE and think the word means _capable_. \nOther forms of the word: AFFABILITY, n."
            },
            "BLASÉ": {
              "word": "BLASÉ",
              "phonetic": "(blah-zA')",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "indifferent, world-weary \nBLASÉ is a French word, and keeps its French pronunciation. \nA BLASÉ person has experienced so many pleasures (or pretends that he has) that he has become bored with them. The things that excite or interest the average person leave him indifferent and unimpressed. \n\"She was quite BLASÉ about winning the prize. You'd think it happened to her every day.\" \n\"With a BLASÉ shrug of his shoulders he said it didn't matter to him whether he went on the trip or not.\" \n\"He tried to act BLASÉ about being elected class president, but he couldn't hide his excitement.\" \n_Old-fashioned_ is the most commonly chosen incorrect answer, due to confusion with _passé_, which looks and sounds much like BLASÉ."
            },
            "DEFILE": {
              "word": "DEFILE",
              "phonetic": "(di-fll'",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to make dirty, corrupt, pollute \nTo DEFILE something is to make it dirty or impure. DEFILE is a very strong word and suggests doing foul things to something that should be kept pure or sacred. \n\"A madman DEFILED the statue by pouring garbage all over it.\" \n\"He said his home was being DEFILED by the presence of such a vicious person, and he demanded that the man leave immediately.\""
            },
            "BANAL": {
              "word": "BANAL",
              "phonetic": "(bA'-nÔøΩI",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "commonplace, trite, worn-out \nSomething that is BANAL lacks all freshness or originality. It is commonplace and uninteresting. \n\"The speaker's BANAL remarks put everyone to sleep.\" \n\"The plot of the novel was quite BANAL; I've read the same sort of thing a hundred times before.\" \n\"All her ideas are BANAL; she hasn't had an original thought in her life.\" \nMany people choose _annoying_ as the meaning of BANAL. This may be due to confusion of BANAL with _bane_. A _bane_ is something that causes trouble or ruin. It is not related to the word BANAL. \nOther forms of the word: BANALITY, n."
            },
            "EXONERATE": {
              "word": "EXONERATE",
              "phonetic": "(eg-zon'-ÔøΩrAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to free from blame, clear, relieve \nEXONERATE comes from a Latin word meaning \"to relieve of a burden.\" Occasionally EXONERATE is used to mean \"to relieve of a task or duty.\" \n\"No one can EXONERATE you from your duty to your parents.\" \nThe word is usually used, though, in the sense \"to free from the burden of blame.\" \n\"The witness's testimony completely EXONERATED you.\" \n\"They admitted the evidence seemed to EXONERATE him from any blame for the fire.\" \nEXONERATE gives the idea not only that the person is not guilty, but that he has been cleared so completely that all the burden of being suspected and accused falls away from him."
            }
          },
          "id": 2,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Remarkable AFFINITY.",
                  "answers": [
                    "concern",
                    "distrust",
                    "attraction",
                    "history",
                    "distance"
                  ],
                  "word": "AFFINITY",
                  "correct": "attraction"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Amazing VISTA.",
                  "answers": [
                    "area",
                    "future",
                    "view",
                    "times",
                    "idea"
                  ],
                  "word": "VISTA",
                  "correct": "view"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ASPIRE to be the leader.",
                  "answers": [
                    "demand",
                    "ask",
                    "long",
                    "claim",
                    "refuse"
                  ],
                  "word": "ASPIRE",
                  "correct": "long"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Completely ASSIMILATED.",
                  "answers": [
                    "rejected",
                    "hidden",
                    "absorbed",
                    "recognized",
                    "revealed"
                  ],
                  "word": "ASSIMILATE",
                  "correct": "absorbed"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The IMPETUS behind it.",
                  "answers": [
                    "rushing around",
                    "happiness",
                    "thought",
                    "moving force",
                    "indifference"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPETUS",
                  "correct": "moving force"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ARDENT desire.",
                  "answers": [
                    "new",
                    "real",
                    "constant",
                    "burning",
                    "mild"
                  ],
                  "word": "ARDENT",
                  "correct": "burning"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He will CONFOUND anyone.",
                  "answers": [
                    "anger",
                    "please",
                    "discover",
                    "impress",
                    "confuse"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONFOUND",
                  "correct": "confuse"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REVEL until dawn.",
                  "answers": [
                    "sleep",
                    "make merry",
                    "fight",
                    "sing",
                    "work hard"
                  ],
                  "word": "REVEL",
                  "correct": "make merry"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BESTIAL behavior.",
                  "answers": [
                    "criminal",
                    "excellent",
                    "animal-like",
                    "logical",
                    "unusual"
                  ],
                  "word": "BESTIAL",
                  "correct": "animal-like"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Forget about the ORDEAL.",
                  "answers": [
                    "triumph",
                    "contract",
                    "accident",
                    "severe trial",
                    "strange sight"
                  ],
                  "word": "ORDEAL",
                  "correct": "severe trial"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "AFFABLE men.",
                  "answers": [
                    "stupid",
                    "vicious",
                    "competent",
                    "pleasant",
                    "holy"
                  ],
                  "word": "AFFABLE",
                  "correct": "pleasant"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BLASÉ expression.",
                  "answers": [
                    "indifferent",
                    "lively",
                    "sulky",
                    "innocent",
                    "old-fashioned"
                  ],
                  "word": "BLASÉ",
                  "correct": "indifferent"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To DEFILE it.",
                  "answers": [
                    "hate",
                    "clean",
                    "steal",
                    "dirty",
                    "break"
                  ],
                  "word": "DEFILE",
                  "correct": "dirty"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BANAL ideas.",
                  "answers": [
                    "mistaken",
                    "unique",
                    "annoying",
                    "fashionable",
                    "commonplace"
                  ],
                  "word": "BANAL",
                  "correct": "commonplace"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He was EXONERATED.",
                  "answers": [
                    "accused",
                    "cleared",
                    "found guilty",
                    "released",
                    "arrested"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXONERATE",
                  "correct": "cleared"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Do sailors usually have an AFFINITY for the sea?",
                  "word": "AFFINITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a VISTA be very close to a person?",
                  "word": "VISTA",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do some people ASPIRE after fame?",
                  "word": "ASPIRE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can your body ASSIMILATE rocks?",
                  "word": "ASSIMILATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a push give something IMPETUS?",
                  "word": "IMPETUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would an ARDENT swimmer enjoy going to the beach?",
                  "word": "ARDENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do people usually enjoy being CONFOUNDED?",
                  "word": "CONFOUND",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a team REVEL after it had won a championship?",
                  "word": "REVEL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are BESTIAL people usually likable?",
                  "word": "BESTIAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is eating dessert an ORDEAL for most people?",
                  "word": "ORDEAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would an AFFABLE person frighten most people?",
                  "word": "AFFABLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a BLASÉ person get excited very easily?",
                  "word": "BLASÉ",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a person dislike seeing his church DEFILED?",
                  "word": "DEFILE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a BANAL play be fascinating to watch?",
                  "word": "BANAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "If someone was suspected of murder, would he like to be EXONERATED?",
                  "word": "EXONERATED",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "The stars seemed to go on and on into AFFINITY.",
                  "word": "AFFINITY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "These inventions opened up for us wonderful VISTAS of mankind's future.",
                  "word": "VISTA",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He ASPIRED to be a writer, but he ended up working in a factory instead.",
                  "word": "ASPIRE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They were able to ASSIMILATE the new students into the class without any problem.",
                  "word": "ASSIMILATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The project lost all its IMPETUS when Susan quit.",
                  "word": "IMPETUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He shrugged ARDENTLY and said he didn't care much one way or the other.",
                  "word": "ARDENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The two men CONFOUNDED the business together and have been partners ever since.",
                  "word": "CONFOUND",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "It seemed as if everyone were joining in the noisy REVELS celebrating the end of the war.",
                  "word": "REVEL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "You must all be on your BESTIAL behavior when we meet the principal.",
                  "word": "BESTIAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The man claimed that walking home through the blizzard wasn't an ORDEAL, it was just a minor inconvenience.",
                  "word": "ORDEAL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Jim was not very AFFABLE at the party; he sat in a corner and refused to speak to anyone.",
                  "word": "AFFABLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "This waltz is so BLASÉ. You should be learning all the modern dances.",
                  "word": "BLASÉ",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He DEFILED us to come out and fight him.",
                  "word": "DEFILE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The BANAL poison killed them both.",
                  "word": "BANAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The judge EXONERATED the man and set him free.",
                  "word": "EXONERATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "AFFINITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "liking",
                    "increase",
                    "resemblance"
                  ],
                  "word": "AFFINITY",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VISTA",
                  "answers": [
                    "distance",
                    "smallness",
                    "view"
                  ],
                  "word": "VISTA",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ASPIRE",
                  "answers": [
                    "remember",
                    "desire",
                    "hope"
                  ],
                  "word": "ASPIRE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ASSIMILATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "blend",
                    "adopt",
                    "increase"
                  ],
                  "word": "ASSIMILATE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IMPETUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "power",
                    "height",
                    "force"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPETUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ARDENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "tight",
                    "fiery",
                    "strong"
                  ],
                  "word": "ARDENT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CONFOUND",
                  "answers": [
                    "excite",
                    "bewilder",
                    "puzzle"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONFOUND",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REVEL",
                  "answers": [
                    "delight",
                    "expect",
                    "enjoy"
                  ],
                  "word": "REVEL",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BESTIAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "crude",
                    "sad",
                    "vicious"
                  ],
                  "word": "BESTIAL",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ORDEAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "difficulty",
                    "pain",
                    "surprise"
                  ],
                  "word": "ORDEAL",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "AFFABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "friendly",
                    "beautiful",
                    "approachable"
                  ],
                  "word": "AFFABLE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BLASÉ",
                  "answers": [
                    "nonchalant",
                    "bored",
                    "ill"
                  ],
                  "word": "BLASÉ",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DEFILE",
                  "answers": [
                    "endanger",
                    "corrupt",
                    "dirty"
                  ],
                  "word": "DEFILE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BANAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "stale",
                    "strange",
                    "dull"
                  ],
                  "word": "BANAL",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EXONERATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "free",
                    "reward",
                    "relieve"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXONERATE",
                  "correct": "1"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        }
      ],
      "reviewTest": {
        "wordList": [
          "AFFABLE",
          "BANAL",
          "EXODUS",
          "ORDEAL",
          "RECAPITULATE",
          "AFFINITY",
          "BESTIAL",
          "IMBIBE",
          "PALPITATE",
          "SORDID",
          "AGGRIEVED",
          "CONFOUND",
          "IMPETUS",
          "PICAYUNE",
          "VISTA",
          "ARDENT",
          "EMPHATIC",
          "MATRON",
          "PLEBEIAN",
          "WILE",
          "ASPIRE",
          "ASSIMILATE",
          "EQUITY",
          "ILLUSTRIOUS",
          "LAUDABLE",
          "SCATHING",
          "BLASÉ",
          "ESPOUSE",
          "IMPART",
          "LEGACY",
          "SUPERFICIAL",
          "CULPABLE",
          "EXONERATE",
          "IMPLEMENT",
          "PALATABLE",
          "WANTON",
          "DEFILE",
          "GINGERLY",
          "INCEPTION",
          "RETICENT",
          "WROUGHT",
          "DISCREET",
          "HEW",
          "INTREPID",
          "REVEL"
        ],
        "questions": [
          {
            "part1": "With a(n)",
            "part2": "shake of his head he said he would never agree.",
            "answer": "emphatic"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The three",
            "part2": "were dignified ladies who ruled high society for many years.",
            "answer": "matrons"
          },
          {
            "part1": "It was a(n)",
            "part2": "speech, full of trite phrases and secondhand ideas.",
            "answer": "banal"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Your",
            "part2": "behavior will not be tolerated; we don't live in the jungle, you know.",
            "answer": "bestial"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Through the long gallery he saw a pleasant",
            "part2": "of a garden with a fountain in the middle.",
            "answer": "vista"
          },
          {
            "part1": "His",
            "part2": "behavior convinced everyone that he was immoral.",
            "answer": "sordid"
          },
          {
            "part1": "She had a couple of",
            "part2": "complaints about the meal. She said the onions were cut the wrong way and the napkin was on the wrong side of the plate.",
            "answer": "picayune"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He",
            "part2": "a great deal of liquor at the party.",
            "answer": "imbibed"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Whenever he ran too fast his heart would start to",
            "part2": ".",
            "answer": "palpitate"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The prisoner used all his",
            "part2": "in trying to escape.",
            "answer": "wiles"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The nobleman didn't want his son engaging in a(n)",
            "part2": "activity like going to the circus. He thought such things were just for common people.",
            "answer": "plebeian"
          },
          {
            "part1": "His",
            "part2": "desire for peace made him work night and day to end the war.",
            "answer": "ardent"
          },
          {
            "part1": "There was little",
            "part2": "between the two people; they had almost nothing in common.",
            "answer": "affinity"
          },
          {
            "part1": "I don't have time to repeat the whole thing so I'll just",
            "part2": "the main points.",
            "answer": "recapitulate"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Jim was so shy that it was quite a(n)",
            "part2": "for him to ask a girl for a date.",
            "answer": "ordeal"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Bob felt",
            "part2": "when everyone else got to go to the picnic except him.",
            "answer": "aggrieved"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Susan",
            "part2": "to be a reporter, so she majored in journalism in college.",
            "answer": "aspired"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The governor tried to stop the",
            "part2": "of businesses from his state by lowering taxes.",
            "answer": "exodus"
          },
          {
            "part1": "All the teachers thought Hal was stupid, but he",
            "part2": "everyone by placing first on the exam.",
            "answer": "confounded"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Uncle Bill is very",
            "part2": ";he always has a kind word for you and will listen to all your problems.",
            "answer": "affable"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Our work was starting to slow down, but then it received a new",
            "part2": "when several people said they wanted to help.",
            "answer": "impetus"
          },
          {
            "part1": "It is impossible to",
            "part2": "all the information contained in this book. There's just too much of it.",
            "answer": "assimilate"
          },
          {
            "part1": "During the quarrel, she made several",
            "part2": "remarks about his driving ability.",
            "answer": "scathing"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Rising from humble beginnings be became one of our most",
            "part2": "leaders.",
            "answer": "illustrious"
          },
          {
            "part1": "You must be more",
            "part2": ";you shouldn't tell everyone all our secrets.",
            "answer": "discreet"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He bought us a pair of fine hand-",
            "part2": "bookends for Christmas.",
            "answer": "wrought"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "soldiers fought their way through enemy territory to rescue the town.",
            "answer": "intrepid"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Everyone praised the",
            "part2": "of his decision, in which each person got what he deserved.",
            "answer": "equity"
          },
          {
            "part1": "When they hear his brilliant speech, I am sure they will",
            "part2": "his position on taxes.",
            "answer": "espouse"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He",
            "part2": "in being the center of attention. Nothing gives him more enjoyment.",
            "answer": "revels"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The wise man",
            "part2": "to them the wisdom of the ages.",
            "answer": "imparted"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Everyone was shocked by the",
            "part2": "destruction of school property; the person who did it obviously wanted to do as much damage as possible.",
            "answer": "wanton"
          },
          {
            "part1": "She walked in a(n)",
            "part2": "fashion through the room, afraid she would step on one of Billy's toys.",
            "answer": "gingerly"
          },
          {
            "part1": "They found several stone",
            "part2": "which the ancient tribe must have used in farming.",
            "answer": "implements"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He swung his ax and",
            "part2": "the large post in two.",
            "answer": "hewed"
          },
          {
            "part1": "I am confident this new evidence will completely",
            "part2": "the defendant.",
            "answer": "exonerate"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Her knowledge of the subject was only",
            "part2": ". She knew a lot of facts, but her understanding of them wasn't very deep.",
            "answer": "superficial"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The meat wasn't very good, but at least it was",
            "part2": "; I couldn't even eat the rest of the meal.",
            "answer": "palatable"
          },
          {
            "part1": "His attempts to bring peace to the world are",
            "part2": ", even if he doesn't succeed.",
            "answer": "laudable"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Mary was very",
            "part2": "about getting the scholarship. I guess she knew she deserved it.",
            "answer": "blasé"
          },
          {
            "part1": "His rich grandfather left him a substantial",
            "part2": ", so he never has to work again.",
            "answer": "legacy"
          },
          {
            "part1": "She",
            "part2": "the beautiful church by scrawling filthy words on its wall.",
            "answer": "defiled"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Since the",
            "part2": "of the new system there have been far fewer problems.",
            "answer": "inception"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The landlord was",
            "part2": "in this accident, because he hadn't fixed the stairway after he had been ordered to.",
            "answer": "culpable"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "girl couldn't bring herself to tell the boy how much she liked him.",
            "answer": "reticent"
          }
        ],
        "type": "fitb"
      }
    }
  ]
}